Let's move on to our next major data type, which is sorted sets.
Understanding sorted sets can be a little bit challenging because they're like a mix between two other
data types.
So we've already taken a look at hashes and sets.
So what exactly is a sorted set?
Well, I've got an example of one right here, as usual in red, as we're going to have a key that is
going to point to our data structure.
This right here is these sorted sets.
Just like a hash.
We've got a collection of what looks like key value pairs, but we don't refer to these as keys and
values.
Instead, we refer to everything on the left hand side as members and everything on the right hand side
as scores.
All the members are guaranteed to be unique.
Just like with a usual set.
Every single member has a score and the score is always, absolutely, always going to be a number.
So we will never have a score that is a string or anything like that.
The scores can be negative or positive.
They can be integers, they can be floats.
Basically any number we want to insert in here.
All the different members are going to be ordered according to their score.
We're going to go from least up to greatest.
Right here, we've got the lowest score of negative four that corresponds to peanut butter.
That's going to show up first inside of our sorted set.
And then at the bottom, we have the greatest score of 5.32 corresponding to strawberry.
I just want repeat one more time.
The members are unique, but these scores do not have to be unique.
We could have negative four show up twice.
Now in general, sort of assets are one of the most flexible and useful data types we have available
to us.
So we're going to get a lot of experience with them inside of our e-commerce application.
We're going to see just how many problems we can solve with them.
They really, truly are very useful.
Unfortunately, along with this flexibility and great functionality around them comes a wide variety
of different commands because there's so much stuff you can do at the sorted set.
There's a lot of different commands you understand around them as well as usual rock and got through
every last command here for two reasons.
First reason is that again, I'm going to assume that you can kind of get through some documentation
on some different commands that are kind of basic.
We're not very commonly used.
The other thing to be aware of, the other reason we're not going to go through every single command
is that there are many commands that are actually deprecated.
So in other words, these are commands that we don't make use of anymore in later versions of Redis.
And some examples of those would be the the rev range, the rev range by LAX.
So some of these up here around Z Rev and there are some others as well.
However, we are going to, of course, go through a bulk of these different commands.
We'll take a little bit of time.
So let's take a pause right here.
We're going to come back in just a moment.
We're going to create our new notebook.
Over on our book, I've called Mine Sorted Sets over here.
And as usual, we'll go through a couple of different commands.