The first couple of commands we're going to look at are just about adding a new members to a sorted
set, removing members and retrieving them as well.
All right.
So first, very basic commands, Z Add and Z score.
Ziad is used to add in a member score paired to a sorted set.
So if we do something like Z, Add Products 45 monitor, we would end up with accessing the sorted set
stored at the key of products.
We would add in a member of Monitor and then a score of 45.
Now one thing to be really aware of here is that the order of these two arguments right here, little
bit opposite from what you might expect it to be, you might expect it to first be the member and then
the score.
Note That's not the case.
It is the opposite.
First we put in the score, so that's always going to be a number number and then the member right after.
That can command is z-score.
And this gives us the score of a member that is already stored inside of our sorted sets.
So if we had something like Monitor 45 right here and then we ran at the score products monitor, we
would get back that number of 45.
All right, let's try out these two commands very quickly.
So back over inside of our book.
I'm going to do a A-Z.
Ad products.
45 monitor.
If I run that, I get back a one just to say, yeah, okay.
We added this value in.
And then immediately after that, if I do a Z score.
Of products.
With Monitor, I'll get back my value of 45.
Now keep in mind that as we stored numbers inside of lettuce, all the implication here is that these
are kind of being treated like strings.
So when we get our score back, it is going to come back to us as a string.
So for whatever different client library we are using, we might have to take that string and parse
it into a number.
Last command I want to show you very quickly is Z, Remove or Z.
R.E.M. And as your guest, this just allows us to remove a member from a sorted set that if we did Xyrem
products monitor, we would go and find that monitor member right there and just delete it.
Maybe we could try that out very quickly as well.
I'll do a REM products monitor, and then immediately after removing it, I'll do another Z-SCORE.
Products monitor.
So add.
Get the score.
Remove.
Get the score again.
If I run this.
And then click on the dot, dot, dot right there.
I can see the output from all four commands.
We can see.
Okay.
Nothing has been added up here.
We got a zero because we had already added in products.
We didn't get back the score.
We then remove that that member and then we do another Z score and we get back null to indicate that
we don't have that member inside there anymore.
Lastly I want to mention is around the Ziyad command, very similar to the set commands that we looked
at previously.
There are a variety of different arguments that we can append on to the Ziad command.
So if you look at the official documentation, you'll see, here's the ad.
We've got some familiar, vaguely looking arguments in here, such as Annex and Xbox, which allows
us to say, Hey, only attempt to add in this new score number pair if this value is not already set
or does not already exist.
There are a couple other arguments as well.
I mean, let's you take a look at the documentation around these.
We're not going to actually use them at all inside of our application.
So not super critical for us to spend a lot of time on them right now.
Okay.
So three basic commands, but of course, still many others to go over.
So let's start to take a look at some of the more complex commands in the next video.