The next two commands are going to look out can tell us the number of elements inside of a sorted set.
These two commands are going to seem very similar, but it turns out that there are a very small number
of variations between them.
We've got Z Card and Z Count.
Z card is short for Z cardinality, and that's going to tell us the total number of members inside of
a sorted set.
Let's try that out very quickly.
Okay.
So back over here.
I'm going to add in a new code cell.
And then going to delete the products sorted set that we created in these cell above the one up there
and then going to add in a couple of different elements.
Let's do the ADD products, 45 CPU.
Products.
Ten.
Keyboard.
And Products 55 power.
Now, to understand how many elements are inside this sorted sets, we would do simply Z count our Z
card products.
There we go.
Now if I run that, I'll be told, okay, we've got three members.
Simple enough.
Now sometimes we want to figure out how many elements are inside of a range of values or a range of
scores.
For that, we would use Z account.
So Z account is very similar to Z card.
It just allows us to apply a little bit of filtering criteria.
So we can do a Z count products and then a range of scores to look for.
So if I use 0 to 50, that means tell me how many members have a score between zero and 55 applied z
count to a sorted set that looks like this right here.
I would get back a number of one because I've only got one member with a score between zero and 50 and
that is monitor right there.
Let's try out ze count as well very quickly.
Okay.
Back over here.
I'm going to add in a new code cell.
I'm going to copy all that stuff right there and put it down here.
I'll then do a count.
And I want to find how many members have a score between zero and 50.
In this case, I should get back the number to the one for CPU and one for keyboard.
And sure enough, there we go.
If I expand the range to say 60, I'll get back all three.
And then very critically, if I put in 55 by default, this is a up to and including value.
So 0 to 55 means fine all the members up to and including 55.
So I will still get back three.
Now, it might seem like the count pretty much stops there, but it turns out there are a couple of
variations around it.
So let's look at those variations very quickly, because they will be eventually rather useful.
The first variation.
Is if we want to be somewhat more constricting inside of our range that we are looking for.
So by default, doing a Z count of products from 0 to 50 kind of implies a greater than or equal to
and a less than or equal to, as we just saw one moment ago.
So if I do 0 to 55, that means up to and including 55.
There might be some scenarios where I want to find all the products with a score up to you, but not
including 55.
And if that is the case, then I just put in a little open parentheses right before the number.
Notice that there is no closing parentheses on the other side.
It is just an opening parentheses.
I can apply that open parentheses to either of these values so I can apply it to just 50 or just zero
or brought them together.
So if we put in the open parentheses, kind of turns the expression into something like this.
Find all the products greater than zero and less than 50.
The back over here.
If I put in an open parentheses right there before the 55, now it's going to go to two because I'm
looking for all the products with a score greater than zero, greater or equal to zero, and specifically
less than 55.
All right.
One other very small variation that will be rather useful in many scenarios.
Though ze count still the same thing products.
Well then sometimes you want to get just an open range.
You'll find all these different products.
Count up the number of all them.
For that, we can use negative infinity and positive infinity.
You do not have to use the two infinities together so we could say just you a zero to positive infinity.
Or we could do 99 to or I should say -50 up to 99.
So this really just allows us to define an open ended range.
I could say find all the products with a score of 15.
Up to positive infinity.
Now give me two.
So that would be CPU and power.
And just as well I can do say up to 40.
And anything beneath that.
Now give me one for keyboard.
Okay.
So Z card gives us just plain the number of members inside of a z sets.
The account is when we want to get the number of members within a range of values and z count once again
has the little bit of special syntax where we can add in that open parentheses to one or both scores.