The next two commands are exact opposites of each other.
We've got Z, Pop Min and Z Pop Max.
What these commands are essentially saying, take the top number of elements and remove them from the
sorted set and give them back to us.
So zip up min.
We called it with products of two.
That means find the two lowest member score pairs.
Sorry.
Monitor and keyboard.
Delete them and return them to us.
Or Zee Pop, Max.
Same thing.
But we're taking a look at the highest score pairs Y, Z, pop, max products.
You would give us keyboard and power and remove them from these sorted sets.
The number argument here of two is optional, so we could remove that entirely.
And by default that means just remove the lowest one or the highest one.
And it does help you to of course we could put in any valid number.
So ten, 20, whatever else you want.
Okay.
These are pretty straightforward commands, but we might need them inside of our application.
Let's do once again a very quick test.
Back over here.
I'm going to add in a new cell.
I'm going to do a copy of just everything from Del up to the Z add.
Well then do a z pop min on products with two.
And so we'll get back the two lowest values, which are keyboard and CPU.
And then in a very similar vein, as you could guess, I'm going to copy that one.
And this one will do a Z pop max.
That will give us our and CPU.
All right.
Not that crazy.
Think it's pretty clear what's going on here.
Just one or two or three more commands and we'll move on to some actual implementation in our application
with sorted sets.