The next command we're going to take a look at is used to adjust a score of an existing member inside
of a sorted set.
So zinc-air by then products 15 and keyboard means go and find a member of keyboard and add 15 to its
score.
In this case, we'd find keyboard right here.
It has an existing score of 40, so would add 15 to that and it goes up with 55 after making that adjustment
registers, then going to resource these sorted set based upon the updated scores.
Now, because keyboard has a score greater than power, keyboard would go down underneath power like
so.
If we ever want to subtract from the score, we would call the anchor buy with a negative value instead.
So if I did a -25 on keyboard.
We then once again go and find you were right here.
We had subtract 25 in this case or at a -25, we would end up with 30.
And then once again, rightists would automatically resort all these numbers because power now has a
greater score.
Keyboard would be sorted or appear earlier in the list.
Okay.
So was the anchor by not too crazy.
Nonetheless, quick example the back of inside of our book I'll add new code cell.
I'm going to copy the Dell products with all the Z ads right here one more time.
Well, then do a.
Z anchor by products.
Let's try adjusting.
How about CPU?
I'm going to add on 15 to CPU.
Now, if we run this as is will be told the updated value of CPU, which in this case is 60, that is
the 45 plus the 15.
Just to verify that is the case, I'll then do a Z score products CPU and again still be told, yep,
definitely 60.
All right, so zinc-air buy just used very simply to adjust a member score.
This is the primary way in which we are ever going to update values inside of a sorted set between the
anchor by the RAM or Z Remove and Z add.
That's how we add update and remove members from a sorted set.