The last command that we're going to look out for right now around sorted sets is the range.
The range allows us to get a range of different members based upon their rank or index or position within
a sorted set or alternatively by their score.
So it's a little bit similar to Z Count, which we looked at a little bit ago, but this is really dealing
with giving us back the members as opposed to the number of elements inside of a sorted sets as usual.
Quick example on how was Z range products?
And then we're going to put in two numbers right here by default.
These numbers are going to be referring to indexes inside this sorted set.
And this index value starts at zero.
So if I did a Z range products one two, that's going to skip over index zero right here and give me
index one.
Up to and including index two.
That would give me back keyboard and power.
By default, I'm only going to get back the members of keyboard in power if I want to also get these
scores as well.
We have to add in the whip scores.
Keyword.
So in total the range products one two with scores means skipped the first element.
Give me from 1 to 2 and include the scores as well.
And that's what we would get back.
Naturally, an example, this would probably go a long way.
All right, back over here.
One more code cell again.
I'm going to copy down the Dell and the Z adds.
Well then do A-Z range.
Products.
One, two with scores.
There we go.
In this case, keyboard is at index zero.
So I'm going to skip over that.
I'm going to get from index one to index two, inclusive.
And I also want to get back to the scores as well.
We'll get CPU and it score power and it score.
If we leave off the width scores, we'll get just CPU and power.
There are a couple of variations on Z range you need to be aware of.
The first big variation.
Is the ABI score accurate.
We put in by score then these two numbers right here, their behavior is going to change quite significantly
if we add in bias score and we are no longer referring to indexes with the first two numbers.
Instead, we are trying to find members based upon their score, the minimum and maximum score.
If we did say Z Range Products zero two, how about 45 or how about 48?
Just be super clear.
So from 0 to 48, by score, that means starting at zero index or simply starting at score zero.
Find all the different numbers all the way up to and including 48.
That would give me a monitor and keyboard.
And then because I have with scores, once again, I'm going to get these scores of those as well.
That would be my return sets.
All right.
Quick example of that.
So once again, another copy paste down.
This time, I'm going to do a.
Zero.
Up to 50.
Let's do buy score with scores.
So in total, give me all the elements or all the members inside the sorted set with scores equal to
or greater than zero less than or equal to 50.
And also include the scores.
There we go.
We get back.
Keyboard zero.
CPU 45.
Now, when we put in these score ranges right here of zero and 50, they can use that same parentheses
syntax we saw a little bit ago.
If I did say 55 right there instead of 50.
I'm now going to get power as well because the 55 is interpreted as up to and including 55.
But if I add in that open parentheses now, it means less than 55 just up to you, but not including
55.
So now I'm going to see everything up to you, but not including 55.
In addition, we can also use that plus infinity or negative infinity syntax as well.
So I could say negative infinity up to you, but not including 55.
Or we could do this plane.
Everything so negative to positive infinity and that'll give us everything.
Last variations to Z range two.
We're going to look at our rev and limit.
Our revenue limit can be added on to all these other variations we've already looked at.
We could do a Z range with Y score and with scores and rev and limit was covering them separately just
so they're well, a little bit more clear.
All right.
So first, rev Rev is going to what the order of elements inside of our sorted set if for doing any
comparisons if we did a Z range products one to that still means go and find the elements at index one
and two.
So that would be keyword power.
But before doing that, it's going to reverse the order of members.
So we can imagine that we might have elements that look like monitor two, keyboard 45 and our 50.
We're going to first flip the order.
Like so.
And then witness flipped order.
Go and find the element at index one.
Up to and including the element at index two.
Now in this case, it would be keyboard and monitor.
And because we did not specify the width scores argument, we would get just the members.
Let's try out just the rev argument very quickly.
We'll come back and discuss the limit in just a moment.
Okay.
So back over here.
One more time.
Let's copy that down.
I just want to make sure we are always working with clean data here.
Of India's range products.
1 to 2.
Just to make sure we're on the same page, we'll run that as is.
So first inside of our sorted set is keyboard, then CPU, then power.
So once you means skip over keyboard and give us CPU and power.
But if I now reverse, that doesn't mean reverse the result set instead.
It means reverse the sorted set and then look up index one and two.
Now if we run that, we get CPU and keyboard.
Very last variation on z range that is limits.
Make use of limit to set up pagination on our results.
That limit can only be used when we are comparing elements based upon their score.
The We're only ever going to see a limit when we are using a by score as well.
In this example, I'm trying to find all the elements that they score from zero up to and including
55.
So for us right now in this diagram, that'll be all three elements getting back, all three elements.
I'm going to use limits to cut down the number of results I get back.
When we add the limit argument, we then provide two numbers afterwards.
So in this case, my first number is one.
The second is to the one means skip the first element and the result set of my results set is three.
All three elements right here.
I'm going to skip over the very first one and then the two means give me the next two of the result
sets.
That would be both keyboard and power.
If I had a limit of one one.
That means once again, skip over the first element and then give me only the next one, which would
be just keyboard by itself.
All right.
Quick example.
I'm going to do another copy here.
Very last copy, I promise.
For this one.
I'll do a Z range on products 0 to 60.
By score.
And then I'm going to limit one to.
That means skip over keyboard and give me back just CPU and power.
We can also do a limit of one one.
That means skip over keyboard and give me only the next burst elements that CPU.
And of course we can also do say a01.
So skip over nothing.
Give me the first element.
That's keyboard do zero two.
That's the first two.
Verse three, you get the idea.
All right.
So that is it.
That is a couple of different variations on Z range.
There are a few other variations that exist as well.
Most notably the by Lex keyword as well.
We're not going to cover blacks because I don't think you're going to be using it terribly often, at
least in the application you and I are working on.
We're going to keep things just a little bit lighter around sorted sets.
All right.
Now, because they can be a little bit confusing when you first look at them.
And we've already spent enough time looking at commands.
So I think it's time for us to start to focus on use cases of sorted sets.