Learning all these different commands is kind of worthless if we're not actually using them beyond just
running them one or two times.
So as we go throughout this course and learn about these different commands and these different concepts,
we're going to begin working on an actual, real, honest e-commerce application.
I've already put together the front end for this application, so it's essentially a collection of different
web pages, a lot of interactivity and stuff like that.
You and I are going to go through the back end of this application that I put together for us and write
out a series of queries with Redis that we're going to be working directly with Redis.
That's it.
You don't have to worry about just about any other web development stuff or APIs, stuff like that whatsoever.
All the code we're going to be writing is 100% focused on Redis.
Now the entire application is written using TypeScript.
If you do not know TypeScript wholly fine.
If you don't want to know TypeScript, what do they find?
For reasons that you're going to see very quickly.
As long as you learn how to work with Redis with one programming language, that knowledge is going
to transfer very well to other programming languages.
So if you don't like TypeScript, wholly fine.
Honestly?
Honestly, not usually.
I completely understand when people don't want to learn about a new language because maybe at their
job they work with another one.
But in this case, really, you can learn about Redis with TypeScript, and you're going to be fine.
If you transition to using Go or Java or something like that.
So with all that in mind in this video, we're going to go through a little bit of setup on this application.
Should be quick.
There are a couple of steps, but each step is pretty fast and simplistic.
But to run the application, we need to have nodes running on your computer.
You can download Node.js at the link I show right here.
So if you go to that link, you'll see a page like this.
Download the Windows Installer Mac OS installer.
They've also got Linux binaries down here as well.
Once you've got node up and running, you're ready to move on to the next step.
In the lecture right before this one, there should have been a text lecture and you should have downloaded
the ARB dot zip file.
That's the name of our application.
RB Short for Red SBA.
It's kind of like eBay.
And I say e-commerce application.
It's actually kind of like a bid for a product and win an auction application.
It's called eBay.
Make sure you download that zip file.
It has the raw source code inside of it.
Once you download that zip file, which I have already done.
Just go ahead and extract it anywhere in your computer where you want to store this code.
So here's the RB folder and inside there, here's all the starter code.
Next up inside of your terminal.
We're going to navigate to that folder that was just created and we're going to run the command and
install inside of that directory.
This is going to install all the dependencies for the project.
So over at my terminal.
There's the ARB folder that was just created when I unzipped it.
I'm going to change into there.
And I'm going to run the NPM install command.
And after a moment or two, we should see the installation complete.
You might get some notices about severely vulnerabilities and stuff like that.
These are largely exaggerated.
I would really not sweat these things, not give me a problem if you see anything pop up.
You can see, even for me, I've got five moderate warnings.
If you really care, you can look into the details of these vulnerabilities.
But I would really recommend you do not run the audit fix command.
If you run a command.
I guarantee you the application will break.
All right.
Next up, we're going to open up our code editor and we're going to tell this application how it can
connect to our Redis instance, the one that we had created a little bit ago, hosted on RedState.com.
But to do so, we're going to open up that code editor inside of our project directory and we're going
to find a file inside called the DOT EMV file.
Let me walk you through that process.
Here's my code editor.
I've already opened it inside the RB project directory.
Here's the EMV file.
It's inside of the root project directory.
You'll see a little bit of kind of stub declarations right here.
So we have to set the host of our readers instance the ports in the password.
This is all the same information that we entered into our book iCloud just a little bit ago.
But to get these connection settings.
We can go back to you.
What red cloud icon.
Remember this dashboard right here?
So it's at Red Ask.com.
You'll sign in, find the subscription you had created, and then find the database you had created
inside there.
On this database page, we're going to find that public end point.
And remember, we're going to copy everything up to you, but not including the colon.
I'm going to copy all that.
Go back over and I'm going to paste it in for the ports.
It's not the port, but the host.
There's the host.
I just pasted it in.
I do not have a colon at the end of this line.
I don't have any numbers.
Next up, I'll go and get the ports.
So that's just the number at the very end.
And pasted in.
Here.
Go.
Then finally, the password.
Down here at the bottom.
Copy that password.
We'll take it back over and paste it into the password field.
And that should be it.
I'm going to save this.
I'm going to go back over to my terminal and we're going to start up our application by running NPM
run dev.
This is the command you're going to use whenever you want to start up the app.
You only have to run it one time to start the app up and then you only have to run it again in the future.
If you say restart your computer, you close your terminal or any of another other things to shut down
the application.
So just remember that command npm run dev.
So at our terminal, inside of our project directory, we will do NPM run dev.
We'll see a little bit of a boot up message.
And then if you see any error messages in here around connecting to Redis, that means there is some
issue with the connection settings you provided.
You'll notice I don't get any errors or anything like that around connecting to Redis, and you should
not either at this point in time.
The visit or application, we're going to open up our browser and navigate to localhost.
Colon 3000.
I'll do that myself right away.
And here we go.
Okay.
So this is our our bay application.
At this point in time, you're going to notice there are some different sections inside of here, and
it looks like we should see some content in each of these gray boxes, but we currently see nothing.
And if I do a search right here, I always get just a loading thing and it never goes away.
And I've got a sign up and sign in page.
It don't really appear to be working at all.
So this is all because there is a tremendous amount of functionality that is not currently implemented
inside this application.
As I mentioned, you and I have to go through we have to implement a bunch of stuff.
On the retail side, we have to put in a bunch of queries, bunch of commands, stuff like that to make
this application work.
Over time, you're going to see different parts of this application start working to be a lot of fun.
Okay.
So now that everything is set up, we're going to come back the next video.
We're going to start working on our first piece of implementation on this app.
And of course, it's going to be focused on strings because that's what we just learned about.