I'd like to give you a very quick tour over this sample project.
So I'm back inside my editor, still inside the RB project directory.
I want to point out two folders in particular where we are going to spend a lot of time.
Let's open the SIRC folder, find services, and then inside there we're going to find queries right
here.
And Red is right underneath it.
We're going to spend a lot of time in both queries and reds where it contains many different files.
So maybe 15 total or so.
Just about every file has a couple of empty functions to find inside of it.
These are where we are going to write in some number of commands, reach out to Redis and store information
or retrieve information.
So again, right now, the application doesn't really have any data storage or any data fetching implemented.
And that is our goal.
That's what we need to implement to make this app work.
And in general, we don't have to worry just about at all about the front end of the app or actual any
actual HTML or stuff like that that runs in the browser.
Again, if you're not familiar with TypeScript or Web development, totally fine.
All right.
Next thing.
Inside that red folder, you'll notice that there is a client's file.
Just want to point out this file very quickly, because this file is where we make a connection to our
running registered database.
This connection is being made using a JavaScript library called Node Redis.
Right here is where we are making use of some of those.
Credentials that you entered into the end of your file.
So read as host, port and password, and then at the bottom is where we actually connect to that database.
I want to give you a couple of notes around reddest client libraries like the one that we're using right
here to access.
Read us from code.
As it turns out that these things are kind of interesting, maybe not the way you would expect.
All right.
So here's our observer on the left hand side.
We are making use of a language specific writers client library called specifically Node Red is the
term here.
Language specific just means that depending upon what programming language you are using, you're going
to use a slightly different library.
They might recall in the last video I mentioned that we are using TypeScript and that might be a little
bit of a downer as you might want to understand how to use Redis with say specifically Java or something
like that.
But again, don't sweat that too much.
I'm going to tell you why it's not a big deal that we're using TypeScript here over the next minute
or two.
So these different libraries that we make use of or with JavaScript or Java or Python or whatever else
are going to give us a set of functions we can call, which ultimately are going to run the same commands
that we've been learning about so far in other commands we're going to learn about in the future.
So quick example.
Okay.
So we have learned about get set and set with some arguments regardless of what client's library you
are using.
So one for Java, one for JavaScript, one for go.
Just about all these different raw commands we've been learning about are going to map up two functions
that look nearly identical regardless of what language you are using.
So this is how a gift would be executed with no jazz.
Note read his library.
It is client docket color.
The same kind of raw command could be executed in, say, Java or go with almost identical syntax,
almost identical function name, identical everything.
Again, even though we're using JavaScript TypeScript here, really not a big deal.
You're going to walk away with the knowledge of how to use this stuff with your particular language
as well.
Something like a set command will still be a client that sets the key value and then some options provided
in an additional object.
I want to give you a couple of other notes around these client libraries very quickly.
Here's one thing to really keep in mind.
If you've ever used a sequel type database before and you've interacted with it using a sequel forum,
you might be familiar with some kind of issue like this where you might be using an arm that allows
you to write out queries using a very abbreviated syntax, something that allows you to express what
kind of information you are looking up without having to worry about the underlying SQL that is generated
right here.
I've got an example of using an arm with a popular JavaScript library, and then on the left hand side,
I've got almost just about the equivalent SQL query being executed.
You'll notice that in between these two, using the one on the right hand side, probably a little bit
easier to figure out.
In this case, you can probably read this code and kind of have a reasonable idea of what's going on.
It's trying to find a user just one where their username is that string right there.
And we also want to fetch that user's profile as well.
You can probably put together a query using an Orem like this without really understanding what the
database is doing, how it's structured.
You could probably do without even understanding SQL at all because you didn't have to go through writing
out the actual SQL query.
Redis is very different in nature.
With Redis, we get access to these different functions that directly mirror the underlying, raw,
basic commands.
No read is quite library out there.
Or I should say very few are going to give you these really fancy APIs that help you query your data
without understanding the raw commands.
You have to understand the plain commands to use all of these different client libraries.
And that's why I told you a little bit ago using the official library document, assuming the official
command documentation is always very, very good practice because at the end of the day, that's what
your client library is doing, is just taking your raw commands or your function calls and turning them
into plain raw commands with very little translate translation in there, unlike what some of those
SQL or IMS do for you.
The other thing to take note of is that some of these libraries are going to have a truly zero documentation
on individual commands.
Okay.
So with all this in mind, I wanna show you one or two popular client libraries.
Very quickly, take a look at the documentation and just help you understand what you're kind of getting
into.
Once you start using these client libraries, you do not have to open up the websites.
I'm about to show you this.
Just a very quick demonstration.
All right.
So first, I'm at No Treatise on GitHub.
This is the library that we are using inside of our project.
I'm going to go to their official homepage.
Here's their official page right here.
And on the left hand side, I'm going to go to the section that says, Read his commands.
Now, I don't know about you, but if I saw a section that says Red is commands, I would expect to
have documentation on all the different commands that are available using this library.
But you're going to notice very quickly that there is no such documentation in this entire library that
is extremely popular.
There is not a single comprehensive, publicly web available source saying, Hey, here's a list of
all the different commands and how to use them.
Instead, the authors pretty much point you off to the official documentation and say, Oh, well,
if you want to figure out what commands are available through this library, just go look at the official
documentation and we pretty much implement all of these.
And so that is the reality.
A lot of these client libraries, they're not going to tell you how these commands actually work in
their own documentation.
Instead, they're just going to say, go up to the red stalks.
And we pretty much have functions that mirror each of these different commands listed in the documentation.
And in theory, they all just about work the same.
I want to give you one other very quick example.
This is a library called Jedis.
It is a Java client library.
So if you are in Java, you will probably use Jedis or something very similar.
I'm going to go through some documentation on a very particular function.
But here's some documentation on the assets method that exists inside this Jedi's library.
So this is the same set as the set that we have been doing, like the set right here to set some kind
of key value pair, optionally with some arguments.
So in this case, Jedis at least does say, hey, there's a set function out there, and here are the
type of arguments that you can expect to receive.
Or at least Jedis gives you a little bit of a hint of what's going on.
Unlike the Node Reddit library that we are using.
But even then, it still falls short on the official documentation.
Notice that as the return type signature, they say that a string will be returned, but they never
actually say in a very easily linked fashion inside of your exactly what that string is going to be.
For that, you have to go back over to the official documentation for the set commands, which we have
looked at before.
And then once here you can go down and take a look at the documentation around return value to understand
what actually is going to be returned to you and what the meaning of that string is going to be.
Even in a well-documented library like Jedis, it's still not giving you really the full story that
the official documentation does.
Okay.
So a lot of ranting here on my part.
All I'm really trying to get across is that these client libraries are really just mirroring the exact
underlying commands that Redis implements.
So understanding the commands themselves is way more important than understanding how any individual
client library works.
And the second big point here is that we really want to use the official documentation as our source
of understanding how these commands work, because the individual libraries don't really document these
commands very well or at all in some cases.
And that's pretty much it.
Okay, so now that we've got a kick off year for this project, let's start working on one of those
empty functions.
We're going to put together the implementation in just a moment.