Let's take a look at the first piece of implementation we're going to put together around our ARB application.
Okay.
So let me describe a little flow or something that's happening inside this application right now.
This has nothing to do with the e-commerce side of the app, so nothing around products or anything
like that.
It's actually a much more basic interaction.
Right now we have users who are making requests to our application.
Our application is written using a library called Svelte Hit.
This is a JavaScript library that uses a technique called server side rendering.
That means that our server generates some HTML and then sends that HTML directly back to the user's
browser.
So internally, whenever a request is issued, svelte kit figures out what page the user is trying to
view.
Are they trying to view the homepage?
The sign in screen?
Sign up, create product.
What page are they looking for?
Once that's determined, Kit is then going to run a bunch of JavaScript code to generate some HTML.
And it turns out that that particular step is relatively slow.
It takes a pretty good amount of time to actually generate that HTML, but once it is generated, then
send a response back to the user and the user immediately sees some HTML appear on the screen of their
browser.
So as our first task, the first improvement that we're going to put into this application, we're going
to try to speed up this process using rabbits.
I want to make sure that we are not constantly generating a bunch of HTML from scratch if it's not actually
required.
So let's use some of our Reddit's knowledge that we've gained to date how we might improve the performance
of this step.
Okay.
So here's we're going to do we're going to implement a very simple caching layer.
Now, whenever a user makes a request or application, we're going to figure out what page the user
is trying to view.
But then rather than immediately attempting to render that page or generate some HTML for it, we're
going to instead see if we have already created some HTML for this page and stored it inside of Redis
as a simple key value pair.
If we have already generated this page, we're going to immediately send a response back to the user.
Otherwise, if we have not generated this page before, we will generate it and then we will store that
HTML that was created inside of Redis so we can use it again in the future without having to run that
expensive rendering operation.
And then after that, we will still send a response back to the user.
So after a user comes to you a page inside your application for the very first time.
In other words, really no user has ever visited this page before.
We're going to fall into the know path, so we're going to render the page and store it inside of redness.
So we might have a key value pair inside of your old something like, say, page or render page something
to indicate that this is a cached email document and the value will be the HTML though some kind of
HTML doc with all the appropriate tags and whatnot.
And again, this is going to improve our performance because we don't have to constantly regenerate
these very common small documents over and over and over again.
That's it.
That's the general goal.
We're going to speed up the performance of our application by using a very simple caching implemented
in Redis.
Now, even though we could implement this very easily using a simple set and get command, it turns
out that there are a few other considerations we might want to have.
So let's walk through a couple of considerations in just a moment.