We are trying to implement some very simple page caching.
Like I said, this is probably going to be implemented with a very simple git and set operation, which
we've already taken a look at.
We could just dive in headfirst and put this stuff together.
But of course, there are a couple of high level notes I want to give you first.
All right.
This is the most important thing.
And out of the entire course, this is probably what I'm going to really hope that you walk away understanding
this.
Probably the most important part of read is Barnhardt and the world of SQL databases.
If we were using MySchool or PostgreSQL, we usually use a design methodology where we just take all
of our data and we throw it into tables, and once it is stored in tables we can then query that data
very flexibly.
We could figure out what data we need.
We can query it with any kind of query we can possibly think up using sequel, and our database is going
to take these different queries, run random, hopefully in the most efficient way possible.
In the world of reticence, we follow an absolutely reverse flow.
We do the absolute reverse.
But if you have any background in school design, we kind of want to take that idea or that entire methodology
and throw it out the window.
Instead, in the world of lettuce, we first figure out what queries we need to answer.
That's the thing we start with.
We say, What do we need to actually learn or look up inside of our data?
And then only once we understand that, we start to think about the design of our database.
So it's completely the opposite of the world of school that minds.
In this particular case, we are trying to implement some caching, and that means that we need to say,
okay, what are we trying to look at?
We are trying to store a rendered page and then at some point in time, the future end is the only possible
use case.
That is the only way in which we're going to search for this information.
There's never going to be a scenario where we say, try to find all of our cached pages and run some
query to find what the most common phrase is in those pages.
That is not a designed requirement, so we don't need to structure our data inside of red to allow us
to iterate over all the cache pages or anything like that.
We're using a very simple yet and set operation is appropriate in this case.
Now, for this implementation or for this feature, this is a pretty easy thing to think up.
Like we barely even have to think about what queries we're trying to answer.
But you're going to see that as we start to get into more complicated data.
Going through this second methodology or this kind of Reddit style can sometimes be a little bit more
challenging.
Okay.
Next up, let's go through our design considerations.
We're going to do this just a couple of times.
I'm not going to make you do it for every feature that we walk through.
I just want you to think about this stuff a handful of times, just to kind of get in the mindset of
how we really start designing stuff around.
Redis The first thing we need to figure out is what kind of data are we story?
Well, again, very simple, just plain string.
That's it.
And each string represents one render page second off.
Should we be concerned about the size of data?
In other words, we're trying to cache some pages.
What pages exactly are recounting?
Is it one per user?
Is it every page in cyber application?
Is there ever going to be a scenario where we are trying to store too much data?
Remember registers all its data in memory and so there is kind of a practical upper bound in how much
information we can hold on to.
As I mentioned previously, there are some strategies where we don't have to worry quite so much about
the size of our database, but at least right now, we should make sure that we're not trying to store
a tremendous amount of information as we are caching these pages.
So for that, we're going to do a very quick calculation.
Okay.
So Andrew, our application and I know I haven't shown you like all the features of this application
yet, but again, it's kind of like an eBay style e-commerce application.
So I bet you can guess what kind of pages we're going to have inside of out.
We'll have a landing page, a dashboard where a user can see what items they are currently selling.
The ability to create an auction.
You can look up an auction.
You can search and you can look up a user's profile.
In addition, we have a contact about us.
Sign in and sign up pages.
Again, I know we haven't looked at the app itself in great detail, but you can probably imagine what
these pages are all going to do.
Though some of these pages are going to be a very custom in nature.
In other words, every user is probably going to see some different content on the screen for each of
these different pages, or in some cases, every single time a user refreshes the page, they might
expect to see different data.
So in the case of, say, auction show or dashboard, these are going to involve some data that's probably
going to change quite a bit over time.
If a user is selling many products, they might expect to see their dashboard with very up to date data
around the status of every single auction.
And if a user is looking at a single auction that is very hotly contested, like a lot of people are
trying to buy a given product, we want to make sure every user is always seeing the most up to date
data.
Everything on the left hand side might not be a very good candidate for caching because these are pages
that we probably want to re render very often.
Or alternatively, we need to render a different page for every different user because there's going
to be different information on the screen, as is the case, especially with the dashboard.
Every users can have their own separate dashboard.
On the other hand, there are some pages where every user is definitely going to see the same content,
and the content on that page is not going to change very often.
That is the case with, say, a contact page or about us or a sign in or sign up page.
What gets rendered on those pages just doesn't change very often.
Now with all this in mind, if we just write off and say, hey, we're not going to cash any of this
stuff, let's actually do some real math and say, okay, even though there are these requirements,
maybe it does make sense to cache that content anyways.
So I sat down and I took a look at what an average page inside of our application for what size it is.
The homepage of our app, as it stands right now, is about 57.1 kilobytes large.
So with that as an average as the size for these different pages, we can start to average out what
the size requirements are of our entire caching feature.
So on the left hand side, we have six pages.
Every one of these pages is 57.1 kilobytes large, and there are 1024 kilobytes per megabyte.
So that comes out to be about one third of a megabyte for every user.
That's what it would take to cache all these different pages for every single user.
If we have a million users, or even 10 million or even 100 million users, this would really start
to stack up very quickly.
So maybe caching these more custom pages isn't quite as good idea.
But on the other hand, for our static pages over here.
We can have the same version of the contact about us.
Sign in and sign up pages for every single user.
They're all looking at the exact same page.
We've got four pages, 57.1 kilobytes each.
That means that to cast these pages for all users across our entire application, we're talking about
only .22 megabytes.
Well, that sounds pretty good to me.
Sounds like we can definitely cache these pages, not cache these, and get some pretty good performance
benefits.
Okay.
So back over here.
Should be concerned about the size of the data.
Yes.
And we're going to only cache certain pages.
Means we can have to put in some logic to decide whether or not we want to cache given page.
Next up, do we need to inspire this data?
Remember, a key aspect of the set operation is the ability to automatically expire data.
And the reason I told you that that existed at all is for accounting reasons, because we want to want
to eventually automatically expire data.
We want to expire the cash in our case for these different pages.
Probably so.
At some point in time, eventually we might decide to update the about us page or the contact page.
Sign in and sign up.
Probably not going to change very often, but they might.
So yes, we probably want to.
Expire after some number of minutes, hours, days.
And honestly, it's totally up to you what that expired time would be, what we probably want to have
one for testing purposes in our application, I'm going to use a very short expiration just to make
sure that the feature works as expected.
But if I ever deployed this app, I might use a much longer expiration.
Next up, the key naming policy.
In other words, what key names are we going to use inside of red?
We're going to come back to that one in just a moment because that's little bit more in-depth conversation.
And then finally, any business business logic concerns in this case?
No, I don't think so.
Not really.
Kind of is around this which pages we cash, but we kind of cover that with the question up here.
So I'm going to say no, no business logic concerns.
Okay.
So that's our design methodology.
Again, I'm not going to make you go through all these steps every time we build in a future.
It's really just this time and maybe another one or two, just so we kind of get through the process
of what we want to think about as we are storing data in Redis.
So we do still have to discuss this key naming policy, but we're going to do it in just a little bit.
As I know, these lectures start to go out a little bit long.