Last thing we're going to go through very quickly is keys.
And the best way to name them inside Red is.
I know I've done a lot of lecturing in the past couple of videos, so we didn't get through this key
naming stuff as quickly as I can.
Okay.
So key naming.
Couple of quick tips here.
First thing, and this is probably going be obvious, keys need to be unique.
So inside of our application, back in this diagram that we looked at just a little bit ago, I said
that we could cache a page at a key of simply page.
This would not work very well because remember, we just discussed how we're going to cache or different
distinct pages.
If we were caching them all underneath a key of page, well, we would just be constantly overwriting
this key with these different page HTML structures.
Not what we want, but we really need four different keys, one for each distinct page that we expect
to see inside of our app.
So one for the contact page.
Sign in, sign up and so on.
Rather than just using these very simple terms, though, we're going to come up with a better naming
structure, because if we just saw a key named sign in or sign up, well, we might not really understand
the goal of that key or what its purpose really serves inside of our app.
So that leads us to point number two.
Other engineers need to understand what a key is for if they ever see it inside of your app, or if
they're looking directly at the data inside of your database.
So again, having a key name of something like simply contact, sign in or sign up, just not super
appropriate because another engineer is not really going to be able to look at this and really immediately
understand what the goal of this key is.
We're going to come back to that tip right there in just a second.
I mean, tell you what a good key naming strategy is extremely common practice.
You're going to see just about every single greatest application out there use.
This strategy is to use a colon to separate different parts of a key.
So a very common practice is to use some kind of term that describes what the type of data is that we're
storing at this key and then a colon and then some kind of unique identifier.
So a key like user's colon 45 implies that this is a key that holds a reference to information about
some user with an idea 45 items.
Colon 19 implies that this is a key.
That's a reference to some kind of item and the items ideas 19.
We can have multiple colons, so we might have users colon posts and that kind of implies that these
are posts that belong to some user or something like that, use posts that are created by a user and
the posts might be all in the category of Idle 9 to 1 or something like that.
Of course, these ideas don't have to be plain numbers.
They can be a string of numbers and characters, just some kind of unique identifier.
Now, having said that, having said that, this is an extremely common practice.
We're going to use a very small twist on this common practice, something that's going to make implementing
a search feature much, much easier down the road.
The only reason that this is not yet super common practice is that we are going to be implementing search
using a rather newer feature in Redis that not a tremendous number of people use just yet because it
is rather new.
And as soon as more people start using the search feature, I think more people are going to start using
this little twist on the common practice.
The small twist is whenever we are putting in a unique identifier such as 45, 19 and so on, we're
going to use a pound symbol right before it.
Instead of a colon.
We can still use a colon such as in users colon posts, but if we have a unique identifier, we're going
to put a pound right before it again.
This is just to make implementing search easier down the road.
There is behind the scenes absolutely no difference between using a colon or a pound.
So you can use up here if you want.
Yeah, use pounds all day.
It doesn't make a difference.
It's just standard practice to use a colon.
That's it.
So as using pound symbols to make search easier, completely fine.
Not a big deal around it whatsoever.
All right, Lessing.
I kind of skip this one right here.
We are going to eventually create a couple of different functions and generate marquee names for us,
just so we avoid making silly typos all over the place.
And I'll show you exactly what I mean by that in just a little bit.
We're not going to do it immediately inside this video or the next one.
We're going to come back and do this step after we finish our feature, just so things don't get really
confusing if they're not already.
All right.
So with all this in mind, what keys are we going to use for our application?
Well, we have a couple of different pages that we need to cash for in total.
One is privacy page and a previous diagram.
I had said that there is a contact page we need to cash.
I was incorrect.
There is no contact page.
It's actually called the privacy page.
The small note we got about us.
Sign in and sign up.
Now each of these different pages is going to be displayed to the user depending upon what route they
go to and our application.
If a user goes to an address of local US 3000 slash privacy, we're going to show them the privacy page
about us will be displayed at slash about sign in at all to sign in and so on.
From these different addresses.
Whenever a user comes to our application, a unique identifier for each one is the route that belongs
to each page.
So we can use these root names right here as unique identifiers as our keys.
So here's what we're going to do.
The base name of our key is going to be page cash.
That is a very clear name.
Other engineers can look at that name and probably understand immediately what this key contains or
what it is a reference to.
We're then going to have a pound is we're going have a unique identifier right after it, and we're
going to have the full root of whatever page we are story.
So page cash pound slash about is going to store the HTML for the about page.
Each pound slash privacy will hold the privacy page, HTML and so on.
Again.
At a glance, any engineer can look at this key and have a pretty good idea of what is stored here.
So let's say that makes it a pretty effective key.
All right, so that's it.
We now have everything we need to actually go through the implementation.
So without further ado, quick pause and we'll put together this cash and feature in just a moment.