Finally time to start writing some code.
I'm back inside my editor.
I'm going to find the SRT directory inside there.
I'll go to services and then queries and then friendly page cache inside this page cache file.
There are two functions that we're going to put together, so get cache page and set cache page.
These are both about attempting to cache a page and then later on retrieve it for the implementation
of Get cache page.
The only argument to it is going to be the route that a user is trying to access.
So something like slash about or slash privacy and so on.
So inside of Get Cash page, we need to take a look at that argument and decide whether or not it is
in the list of routes that we want to cash.
If it is, then we're going to try to fetch the cash version of this page from Redis and return it.
Otherwise, we'll just return not to say, Hey, this is a route that we're not going to cash.
We don't care about it.
So we're not even going to try to look up the cash version.
Finally to just make sure that we've got a list of all the different routes you want to cast, we should
probably make an array of them.
We might make an array saying that we want to catch the routes about privacy.
Sign in and order.
Sign up.
Okay.
Let's write out some code here.
Now for this very first little edition.
Really just going to write out the code together very quickly.
And we're not going to worry too much about the specifics of TypeScript or anything like that.
So to get started at the very top, I'm going to make a new array called cache routes.
And this will be my list of all the different routes that I want to cash.
That's going to be about.
Privacy.
Sign in.
And off sign up.
Next up inside of Get Cash Page, we're going to take a look at the route that the user is trying to
access and see if that route is one of these.
We'll say if.
Ash roots includes.
Root.
So if the root that the user is trying to access is included in this list right here, then that means
we want to make use of our reddest clients and issue some kind of command to reach out and get the cached
version of our page.
Do write out that query or write up that command.
We need to get access to our Redis clients.
The red is client was already created for us ahead of time inside this project.
As you might recall, we looked at it very, very briefly inside the services Redis directory.
Yes, file.
This client acts file is where the red is.
Client is created and that's how we issue commands off to the right a server.
But to issue a command inside this if statements we need to import the register client at the very top.
Then finally inside the statements.
We will return clients client get.
And then we're going to get a very specific key.
And we spoke about our key design in the last video.
So it's going to be string.
And let's just take a look at that diagram very quickly.
So it's this right here is going to be page, cash, pound, and then the route that we're trying to
look at.
So page cash out and I'm going to add on to that string whatever route a user is access accessing.
Right.
And then finally, if we are accessing a route that we are not caching, then we're going to just return
null instead.
And that should be it for the get.
Let's also take care of the sets very quickly, because this one is going to be very simple as well.
So for the setting operation.
Our arguments are going to be the route that the user is visiting and a page.
So the actual HTML that was generated.
So we want to take that HTML and set it inside of Redis so we can cache it and get access to it later.
Inside of Set Cache Page, we once again want to see if the route that the user has visited is in the
list of all the routes we want to cache.
And if it is that we want to take that page html and stored inside of Redis.
So inside of the set function we can do if astronauts.
Includes Root.
And I will return client sets.
They're going to set a value in this case.
And once again, we're going to generate Aki using the same kind of approach.
We will improve that approach in just a moment.
But right now it will do.
I'll do page cache LB plus roots.
And then we're going to put in the value that we want to store at this key.
And in this case, it's going to be that page argument.
And then optionally we can also add in some arguments to the set command.
You might recall that we spoke about putting on an expiration value whenever we are using Redis as a
cache.
So at some point in time, we probably want to make sure that we expire this cash value in case a new
version of our about page or privacy page or something like that is actually available.
So to add in an expiration option, I'm going to put in a third argument here of an object with the
X arguments of two, which means expire this value after 2 seconds.
Now, 2 seconds is really short in general for a cache page of this nature.
I'm only using 2 seconds just because we can test it out very easily to make sure that the value is
being expired.
But depending upon your application, you might instead want to do something like 2 minutes, 2 hours,
or even two days in some cases.
Okay.
So that is it for our implementation.
Now to test this out, well, things are going to really appear to be completely the same when we use
our application because we are just caching these pages.
We're not really going to notice any distinct improvement or different behavior, but just to make sure
that our app still works as expected.
I will go back to my terminal, make sure my application is still running.
I'm going to go back to my browser.
I'm going to find the privacy apologist privacy policy page down here at the very, very bottom.
Right.
So here's the footer.
I can go to privacy.
And then if I refresh the page, everything should basically just still work as expected.
I should also be able to go down to you about us.
Refresh and still see everything work the same with.
Sign in and sign up as well.
Now in theory, all these different routes are incredibly fast, hopefully anyways.
But like I said, it's kind of hard for us to tell, since in general, rendering these pages isn't
super expensive right now.
Okay.
So that's it.
That's the first improvement to our application, a very small one, but we're just seeing kind of the
basics of a simple get insets.