There is one small improvement that I would like to make to our page cache functions.
You might recall I spoke a couple of minutes ago in a previous video about how we might want to implement
some kind of functions to generate arches or as I said, generally our keys for us.
I'm really just talking about this operation right here.
So this is where we take some of like, say, page cache pound or page cache colon and enjoy it together
with some dynamic value inside of our app.
And that's going to generate a key that we want to look at.
Now, what we've done here totally works only fine, but there's a very small downside to it at some
other point in your application.
Let's say down here, we later in another file you might write out something like client dot git and
then try to do something like page cache lb plus some value.
And at first glance, everything here looks totally fine.
Of course there's an error right here just because we have not declared that variable.
But in general, hey, we are generating a key.
At first glance, it totally looks fine.
But then you might run this code and notice that for some reason you're never successfully retrieving
any data from Metis.
And the reason for that is very simple.
It turns out that our key right here has a very small typo inside of it.
It's missing an E at the end of cache.
So making a very small mistake around a key name like this happens all the time when you are trying
to write out your keys as playing strings inside of your app.
So we're going to implement a very small set of functions inside of this application to essentially
generate this string or else very easily.
And the benefit to this is that we never have to write out our keys as playing strings, which usually
leads to us making small typos.
So let me show you what we're going to do.
First I'm going to find my SIRC folder again and services.
And then right here inside of services he's talked to.
Yes.
So inside of you, Scott.
We're going to write out a series of very, very small functions.
Each of these functions are going to be used to generate a key or a different key value pair inside
of our application.
Let me give you an example of the very first one I'm going to export.
New function.
I'm going to call it page cache key.
I'm going to say that this is going to take in as an argument, an idea that is a string.
And then from this function, I'm going to return page hash around plus ID.
Optionally, if you want to, you could rewrite this little expression right here where we are joining
together two strings, using some advanced syntax.
So optionally you can replace the single quotes with back ticks.
Notice those are no longer single quotes.
They are back ticks character to the left of the one on your keyboard.
And then right after the pound I'll put in dollar sign curly brace I.
Then inside our application whenever we need to get access to our page cache key value pairs.
So page cache or sign in or sign up or for the off page or for the privacy page or whatever else.
Rather than writing out these keys manually and trying to join together these strings manually, which
inevitably leads to some kind of typo, we will instead always use this function.
So we'll always get access to our page cache and generate the keys for it by using this function and
just putting in the name of the route that we are looking for.
That's what this ID argument right here really is.
It's the name of the route we are looking for.
The very clear benefit here is just that we don't have to write out that string, which again can very
easily lead to typos.
Let's now try using this new function back inside of our page cache file we just put together.
Now inside of here at the very top, IKEA on imports.
Age.
Cash he.
From Services.
He's.
That is the file we were just working on.
That is the function we just created.
And now where we generate these cookies.
So right there and right there, rather than generating them manually, we can instead call very simply
page cache key and put in roots.
And the same thing down here as well.
The page cache key.
But in the rat.
Okay.
So now zero chance of making any typo around our key because we're not writing out the plain string.
This is a pattern that we're going to use quite a bit throughout this application.
So eventually our key you start to file right here is going to have something like 20 different entries
inside of it for all the different types of keys that we're trying to generate across the entire application.
All right.
So that's a very good, very small improvement.
So now that we are truly done with this first addition to our small application, we're going to start
to move on to our next major topic around this.