Onto our next major data type that we can store in red us and our next type is a set.
Now sets are where red is starts to get really, really interesting because they allow us to model more
interesting relationships between different pieces of data.
A set by itself is a collection of strings where each string is unique.
So for example, I might have a key that references a set, and inside the set I've got red, green,
blue and orange.
I'm guaranteed that I will never have any duplicate record within the set, so I will never have, say,
two copies of red or two copies or three copies of green.
Each string will only appear exactly one time.
No matter how many times I tried to add in, say the string red or the string green.
Now, as usual, we're going to go over a list of very common commands that we're going to use with
this data structure.
We're going to write out a ton of examples into a artbook notebook, and after that, we're going to
go over some common use cases and then eventually use sets inside of our e-commerce application.
But right now we're going to focus on just how we create add and list elements inside of a sense.
Our first command is going to be at just about all the different segments we're going to learn about,
begin with the character s and that makes them really, really easy for us to identify.
The ad command is how we add elements into a set.
So for example, if we do s add colors red, we're going to go to the key colors.
If a set does not already exist there, one will be created and we will add the key read to it.
No matter how many times you run the same exact ad command, if they are all identical, no changes
will be made.
So in other words, if I've already got a set with the string red inside of it, and then I run that
command again, again and again, no changes will be made my sets, because I've already got the string
red inside there.
Before we test out this command, there's one other I want to tell you about.
That is as members as members returns, all the different values that are stored within a set.
All right.
So between these two commands, we can very easily test them out inside of our book.
Let's take care of that right now.
Back inside of our book, I've already created a new notebook called Sets as your guests.
First is ADD.
Let's take a look.
I'm going to do ADD.
Others read.
And I get back a one you might have noticed on the diagram I showed you just a moment ago, when we
run the ad, if we get back a one, that means an element was added.
If we get back a zero, it means that that element already exists inside the set.
And we did not add anything to the set.
The very first time I run ad colors red, I get back to one because I've added red to the set for the
very first time.
But if I run this command again, I get back a zero because Red already existed inside there.
If I add in a different value, say green, I once again get a one and then a zero if I run it again.
Now I've been saying string, string, string over and over and over again.
But remember, numbers are treated in a very similar fashion as strings inside of lettuce.
So I can add in numbers to a set as well.
For example, if I wanted to, I could do s add.
How about numbers three?
I get a one, I run again.
I get a zero.
I'm going to go back to colors, though.
Because it's a little bit easier to keep track of.
All right, so now you see what values exist inside the sets.
We can do an S.
Members.
And then the key representative said that we want to look up.
Now, if we'd run this, I will get back red and green.
Well, that's the basics of Assad and its members.
Now, once again, at first glance, kind of seems like this is a very basic structure and it might
seem like it doesn't really do a lot for us.
But if you start to use your imagination, you're going to start to see that.
Like I said, sets really start to unlock a lot of interesting capabilities in Reddit.
And we're going to see those very quickly as we discuss use cases and use them inside of our application.
Let's continue on with a couple more commands in the next video.