In this video, we're going to start looking at a couple of different commands that operate on multiple
different sets put together.
These are union stiff and inter.
Each of these three commands have related sub commands as well.
So for example, related to s inter is s inter store and s inter card.
We're going to first start off with just the base commands and then learn about the variations very
shortly after.
Okay.
So to get started, a little bit of pieces of terminology, we're going to first start off with just
union by itself.
So a union is defined as all the unique elements from a number of different sets put together into a
new set.
And in plain English, that doesn't make a lot of sense.
So quick diagram.
Let's imagine that we have three different sets.
Well, there's one, two and three.
And each one has a string representing a color inside of it.
If we wanted to find the union, that means we want to take all these strings and put them together
inside of a new set.
And we want to only keep the unique elements.
So one way we could do that is just adding in each element one by one.
And if it already exists inside the union, then we will not add it.
Let's see what that looks like in action.
The first I would add in red.
I would then add in blue that doesn't already exist inside the union.
Orange does not exist inside the union.
So add that in as well.
I'll then move on to the next set as blue exists inside the union.
Yes, it does.
So I'm not going to add it again as green?
Nope.
So that is purple?
So I'll add that.
And then finally, blue already exists.
Red already exists.
And purple already exists.
That's it.
That's my union of all three sets.
Now, just to test this out, let's go and run the Union Command very quickly over inside of RBA.
The back over here.
I'm going to first begin by creating three separate sets.
So add.
There's one.
And then when we do an ad, we can add in as many elements inside of one command as we want.
So we can add in red, green, blue right here if we wanted to.
Now, just to keep these examples very consistent, I can use the exact same colors.
The first set has red, blue, orange.
Well then do in sad colors too.
The second one has blue, green, purple.
And then sad colours.
Three as blue.
Red, purple.
All right.
I'm going to run that.
And then on another code window down here, I'm going to do s union among all three sets.
We should do colors one.
Colors two.
And Colors three.
Now if I run, that's all add up end up at the union.
So green, blue, orange.
Red, purple.
Yep.
Looks right to me.
All right.
So this first command union around these kind of comparison commands might not look, again, like the
most useful thing, but it's really amazing how many interesting features you can put together using
these otherwise simple looking commands like S Union, S and S2.
Let's continue on with S intersection in just a moment.