Our next comparison is intersection.
An intersection operation is when we take a look at two or more sets and we return only the elements
that exist in all of those sets.
So another quick example.
So again, we've got the same colors here in the same sets.
So inside the intersection, we only want colors that exist in all three of these.
So we'll go one by one.
Does Red exist in all three?
Nope, because it's not in color.
Two is blue exists in all three?
Yes, it does.
It's right here.
Right here and right here.
So I would add blue in.
About Orange?
Nope.
It's nowhere else.
Now, the interesting thing about an intersection is that we only have to go through all the elements
inside of one set, because if it's not a color list in here, then it's definitely not going to be
added into the intersection.
Well, we can go and test out this command inside of our book very quickly as well.
I'll add in another code cell.
I'm going to do se inter inter being short for intersection and then colors one, colors two and colors
three.
Sure enough, Blue.
All right, simple enough.
One last variation that's different.
We'll take care of that in just a moment.