Last variation is diff or difference.
This is where we take a look at the very first set that is provided to the command and we return elements
that are present in there but not in any other sets.
So as another example, we would take a look at the first set right here, and we want to only put elements
that are present in here, but not any others into our difference.
We'll start off one by one.
First is red.
While red is president over here.
So we will not add it.
Blue is president here and here.
Orange is not present anywhere else.
So we would add in orange and that's certainly it.
That's the difference.
That's all we have to do.
So take a look at the first set.
If it exists in there, but nowhere else.
Add it to the difference.
Well, once again, let's test this out inside of our book so we can do a stiff.
On colors.
One wears two and colors three.
And there we go.
We get orange.
One thing that's kind of interesting about SDF is that the order of keys that you put in here makes
a difference on the output with Inter and S union.
The order of keys we provide doesn't make any difference whatsoever.
But because SDF is going to look at elements that are in the first set and no others really comes down
to what is the first set that we are referencing and the first key that we provide to the inter command.
Well, that's all three comparisons.
Now, there are variations on this command, like I mentioned.
We'll go through each them very, very quickly, because each of them are pretty basic and simple in
nature.