The three comparison commands of s union, SDF and s inter all have a very small variation.
You can run s union store as if store and inter store.
Each of these three commands are going to run at the underlying operation.
So a union, a difference or an intersection and then store the results at a brand new key.
They're pretty simple in nature, just a very small variation that that saves the output in Redis.
We'll take a look at s store because once you understand this one, you're going to have a good idea
of what's going on with all three.
Okay.
So back over inside of our book, I'm going to do an S enter store.
And the first argument here is going to be where we want to see the results of our intersection.
So I'm going to save the results of an intersection.
AT How about others?
Colin Results.
And then I will do an intersection on colors one, colors two and colors three.
I get back 1 to 1 here means that there is one element inside of the intersection between all three
elements.
We can now do a s.
Back up here.
Just a quick reminder.
We go s members on colors results and will be told about all the elements that are inside that intersection.
So I will do a as members.
On colors results and I get just blue.
So clearly I did successfully find the intersection and store it at this Nike.
Well, that's pretty much it.
That's a variation on those three different commands with a store keyword on it, or just taking the
results of the operation and storing it at a brand new key.
Now, you might be curious, though, why would we ever use store?
Well, we would want to use it any time that the comparison so the intersection union or difference
was expensive.
So we had really, really, really large sets and it took a lot of time to run a union between them.
We probably don't want to do that union all the time, so we might just run the union once and then
stored at some key and then only rerun that union operation once every day or week or month or whatever
is most appropriate.
All right.
Couple more commands in the next video.