Our next command is s is member.
Very simple command just returns a one or zero if some elements that we provide is present within a
set.
The nice thing about SE is member is it allows you to check to see if something is present in a set
without first matching.
The entire set is sometimes a set, might have hundreds or thousands of elements in it.
It's a lot faster to have read it.
Just do a comparison for us rather than fetch the entire set and check to see if something is present
inside of it.
So we might do an SS member on colors one with red.
That's really just asking the question is a red present inside this set?
Now if we use the color sets we have already loaded up inside of our book.
Red is present.
The red would give us back a one saying, yep, red is inside this set, but purple is not present.
So we would get back a zero instead.
All right, quick test.
We will do a as is member colors one with red and we'll get back a one.
But if we do a purple, we get back a zero.
Very small variation on se is member is s m is member.
And you'll notice in this diagram I made the M here really large just to make sure it's super clear
that's the difference in the name we have s is member and s m is member.
The M pretty much stands for multiple.
We are checking to see if multiple different values are present inside of a set in one single command.
The interesting thing here is that we are not going to get a result saying if any individual, one or
all of them together inside of a set, we get back an array of results and the array says one if red
is present, zero if it's not.
One if green is present.
Zero if it's not.
And one if blue is presence present.
A quick example here.
So Esim is member alerts.
One will do red green lit.
We get back in, Ray?
Looks like red is present.
Green is not.
Blue is presence.
Once again, simple command.
All these commands, very simple in nature, just need to understand where to use them.
We've gotten through.
Just about everything on the bottom here except for scan.
Of course, we're going to go through some of the single set commands very quickly and then we'll start
to dive into the use cases, which is where, again, the stuff starts to get really interesting.