Last three commands we're going to look at first off as card.
This gives us the cardinality of a set or again, we mentioned cardinality.
It's a number of elements that are present in a set that we do.
S Card Colors.
One just tells us how many elements are in colors.
One quick example is card colors.
One we should get back a three.
Yep.
Looks pretty much right.
Next one is SRM.
As you could guess, this is going to remove R.E.M., remove an element from a set of video.
S REM colors one with red.
We're just going to take red out, and that's pretty much it.
I'll do a s REM.
I'm going to run it on colors too instead.
And let's see what's in colors too.
Inside there we have.
Back up here.
Where is it?
I'm going to take blue out of colors to.
So blue.
And then if I do un s is member colours too with blue.
We should get back to zero because it's no longer present in there.
Okay.
Finally a scan.
Now, this one is a little bit trickier.
So I put this one at the very end.
Now, we made use of a command a little bit ago.
S members.
And that gives us all the elements that are stored inside of a set.
But remember, keeping keep in mind here, in some cases, we might have sets with many, many elements
inside them.
So we might have thousands or even millions of elements in assets.
And if we ever wanted to get a list of all these different members, well, we might not want to use
as members, because it's going to give us back all the strings with one single command.
That might be way more than what we are looking for.
So if we want to look through all the elements and save a set, but not necessarily get all of them
at the same time, we can instead use S scan.
This allows us to walk through all the elements inside of a assets in a piece by piece, use scan.
There's just one tricky thing to understand.
We're going to call it scan, provide the key to the set.
And then the tricky part is the cursor ID right here.
We'll come back to that.
And then optionally, we could put on count two or count three, four or five, 50 or 100.
However many elements we want to get back inside of this first step.
If we do a count of two, that means give me back just the first two elements inside of this set.
All right.
Now, I said earlier it was the kind of tricky part.
I understand the cursor.
It lets first go run s scan.
And then we can get a better sense of what's going on with that.
I'm going to do an S scan.
On colors one zero.
Count two.
If I run that, I get back an interesting response.
First I get three, then orange and red, and the three here is not really meant to indicate that there
are three elements total inside the set.
Instead, that's our cursor ID.
Whenever we run an escort operation, we are getting back a single page.
If you kind of think of this cursor as being like a pointer to the next page, it says, Hey, if you
want to get the next page worth of data, ask for the page that comes back.
So if we run scan colors zero, count you the first time we get back a three right there.
And that three means if you want to get the next page to data run scan again with the same key, but
now put in a three as your cursor and still you can do optionally the count two or count ten, count
100 or 100, whatever you want to do.
So that three means we want to get the next page of results.
So if we do.
And scan collars.
One with three, count two.
Now we're going to get the last page of results out of our set, which is just blue.
And now our cursor ID is zero, which means we've hit the end and there's no more elements inside of
the set for us to fetch.
That's scant.
Wherever possible, if we expect our set to be very, very large, we would want to prefer to use an
S scan over an S members.
S members is far more convenient because you don't have to do any of the scanning stuff.
But again, it's going to get your entire set and in some scenarios that might just be too much data.
All right.
That's all the commands are going to cover around sets.
There are a handful that we didn't really talk about.
That is, for example, Se Inter Card.
Is that supported by Reddit seven, which you might not be running right now?
S Inter Card just does an intersection and then count the number of elements inside the intersection.
There's also se pop and s random member s remember is going to give you a random element out of a set
and a questionable on the use case there.
And s pop is going to give you a random element and remove it from a set.
Also kind of questionable on the use case.
Finally s move will move an element from one set to another and again, a little bit questionable on
the use case.
And at the end of the day, if you're interested in those commands, they're all extremely simple in
nature.
So I'm very confident you can read the documentation if you really want to be completionist and understand
every last command.
All right.
I understand the commands.
That's one thing.
Kind of got that down pat.
Now it's time for us to understand when to use these and how we can actually use a set to build an interesting
feature.