Let's take a look at some common use cases around sets.
As I mentioned several times, learning sets and understanding them really opens up a whole realm of
different possibilities in Reddit.
We're going to take a look at the most common use cases.
But if you're clever, you can probably think of even more use cases.
The first common use case we're going to look at is enforcing uniqueness of any value.
This is one of the most basic operations around sets.
So let's imagine that inside of our application, we want to make sure that every username can only
be used by one single person.
Let's imagine that someone is trying to sign up for a brand new account with the username of our seller.
One that request comes into our API.
So in our API, first thing we want to do is see if that username is in use.
To do so we could take a look at our set of usernames.
We can store inside of a set every username that has ever been made use up inside of our application.
We can see if our seller one is inside that set.
If it is, that means someone else is already using this username.
And if it's not, it means that username is available.
So we can create a user account for this person and add that newly used username to the set as well.
So after creating a new account, we might say, okay, our seller.
One is now in use.
Just to test our knowledge, how would we check to see if our cellar one was in use inside the sets
to check to see if it is?
We would write out a command of something like as is member.
We would want to look at the asset stored at the key of usernames and then check to see if the value
power cellar one is in use.
And that's it.
That's all we have to do to check to see if this username is available.
Next come this case is creating relationships between different records.
This is another very common one.
We're going to do a couple of times inside of our application that we eventually need to implement a
like system inside of our app.
We need to allow users to like different products.
We might represent that relationship using a set, we might have a separate set for every single user.
So we would have a key of something like users count 45 colon likes in this might mean or user 45.
Here are the set of IDs of items that they like.
So in this case, this user of 45 likes the items one, two, three, five, five, five, two, two,
two and nine or nine.
And once we have all these IDs inside the sets, we can very easily write out different commands to
ask different questions about what items this user likes.
For example, if we just want to find a big list of everything that this person likes, it would be
a command of s members.
Users 45 likes.
To see how many items this person likes.
We would do an SD card users 45.
Likes.
Member card is short for cardinality.
Counts the number of items that exist inside of a set.
And then finally, if you want to see if a user likes a very particular item, maybe one with an idea
of 1 to 3 that would be another is member users 45 likes one, two, three.
And that's it.
So once again, implementing these very basic questions, incredibly simple, using these very simple
commands.
All right, throw common use case finding common attributes or common things between different elements
or entities inside of our app.
Once again, this is something we're going to have to do in our application.
So let's imagine that we need to figure out what items to users, both like what are the common elements
or the common items that these people like.
So we might have one set per user with ID 45 listing all the items that they like and then a second
set for user ID 32 listing all the items they like.
But a find the items that both these two different users like we would do an intersection operation
that would be an S enter.
Users.
45 likes and users.
32 likes.
The intersection would give us back 55 or 55 and nine or nine because those are the two common elements
between both the sets.
It's just like that.
We know what items both these people like.
And then the last very common news case that we're going to run into quite often any single time, we
have a list of elements where the order doesn't really matter at all.
One of the very classic use cases of this is if you are trying to say limit what kind of IP address
is or domains or something like that, your application will connect you or see requests from.
Let's say that we allow people to sign up to our application using email addresses, but we want to
make sure that some email domains just don't get used.
We might make a set of email domains that are banned inside of our application, and we could say,
All right, if you have an email address and again, is email dot com for gmail.com or scam?
Welcome.
Sorry, but you can't use that email to sign up to our application.
So this is an example of where we have a list of elements.
What the order of that list doesn't really make a difference is it's not very often that we're going
to have to print out a list of these elements in really any meaningful way.
All right.
So, again, many different use cases.
And I'm sure you can think of several others that we are going to actually make use of these first three
right here inside of our e-commerce application.
We're going to do exactly what this first example was.
We're going to make sure that all the different usernames that are in use in our app are always unique.
We're going to use a set to model what items a user likes, and we're also going to use sets to figure
out what common items different users like inside of an app.
The lot of code for us to write.
Let's get started on some implementation around these operations in the next video.