We understand some of these basic commands around hashes.
And we're going to move back over to our code editor in this video and write out a little bit of code
to work with hashes.
Now, as we start to work with hashes from code, we're going to start to notice a couple of really
interesting things.
So in this section, we're not going to work on our e-commerce application just yet.
Instead, we're going to write out a little bit of test code and understand how these two very basic
commands we're going to use all the time.
Work with hashes are a little bit.
Well, it's strange.
They have some unexpected behavior when we start to make use them from a application or from actual
code that we are writing.
Okay.
So to understand why these things are strange, we're going to go back over to our code editor.
I'm again inside my RB project directory.
I'm going to find a folder inside of your called Sandbox and then inside their index dot.
Yes.
This is a file that is not connected to the rest of the code inside of our project.
Well, it kind of is because we're using the client, but really it is meant to be a standalone file.
The goal of this file is just to allow us to write out a little bit of code play around with read is
directly from a node application.
We're going to write out a little bit of code inside of here just to work with Redis directly with hashes.
And like I said, see a little bit of strange behavior.
Once we put some code inside this file to run it, we will go back over to our terminal.
We will open up a second terminal window.
Also inside of our RB project directory.
But here's my original window right here where I'm running our application.
There is a new terminal window and I'm going to run NPM run sandbox inside of here.
Okay.
So now that file that sandbox out to file is being executed and we'll see whatever console.log or whatnot
that we run will appear inside this window.
Okay.
So that might.
Let's go back over to our editor.
Here's the sandbox file.
I've opened up the run function and we're going to write out a little bit of code to just store a hash
inside of Redis.
But I will do an await client dot h set.
And I'm going to store a key of car.
And then here's the first thing.
It's a little bit interesting, but it's going be kind of predictable.
One nice thing around a lot of these client libraries, you're going to make yourself not only with
JavaScript but with other languages as well.
You'll recall that when we are making use of H set with the command directly, we have to just list
out the keys and values in alternating order.
But a lot of these different client libraries allow you to instead provide an object which much more
closely kind of mirrors how a hash is stored inside of Redis.
So we might do something like, say, color is red and year would be 1950.
So an equivalent age that would be something like age, that car color red year, 1950.
So again, we do not always have to make use of this alternating key value inside of our actual application
code, which is just a nice little convenience thing.
Okay.
So if I save this and then go back over to my terminal.
I should see something about restarting that file.
It's been modified, so that has now executed our code inside the file.
And in theory, we have stored this car inside of a hash.
So, hey, everything looks totally fine, right?
Well, let's now go ahead and try to retrieve the car.
So I'll do a car.
Is a wait client dot h.
Get all.
And get the key are.
And then I will print out.
The car.
I'll save this again.
Back over.
And sure enough, there's my console.log right there.
Notice I've got an additional key in there.
We can just ignore that for right now.
All right, so this all looks totally fine.
Looks totally reasonable.
Looks very similar to the H set in the H.
Get all operations that we just did inside of our notebook though.
Why was I saying that h set in h get all are a little bit strange.
Well, we're going to dive into why each set and each get all are not super predictable in the next
video.