All right.
Let's take a look at why each set and each get all are a little bit weird.
Sometimes we make use of them from code.
So to get started, I'm going to first add in a couple more properties to this object right here.
I'm going to add in a engine that will be an object.
It's cylinders eight owner of null and service of undefined.
Right away we do get a little red squiggly error message right here from the object we're trying to
provide for engine fully.
Fine.
Just ignore that error.
The error that we see right here is not the source of the problem that we are about to run into.
The idea behind these additional properties is that maybe we want to store some specification around
the engine in the car, maybe we want to record who the owner is.
Maybe there is no owner right now, so we might store null and we might also want to record some record
of service around the vehicle.
And maybe this vehicle has never been serviced ever.
It's never been repaired had the oil changed or anything.
So we might store a value of undefined for that.
So I would say that these values, with the exception of the obvious kind of air right here, they look
pretty reasonable.
Let's save this.
Go back over to our terminal.
And we'll very quickly see that we get a giant air message here.
I'm going to scroll up a little bit.
And take a look at what the ear actually is.
Here it is right here.
It says cannot read properties of no reading to string.
Huh?
Well, that's kind of a weird error message.
I will tell you that the error we are seeing is not related to the red squiggly right here in any way.
As a matter of fact, it's actually related to the null property here instead.
So what's going on?
Well, of course, let's take a look at a couple diagrams and understand what is going on behind the
scenes.
Okay.
Here's what's happening.
We are building up this object right here.
We are handing it off to the Node Redis library and asking it to get this object ready to send over
to Redis.
We need to take this object and convert it in some way to an equivalent each set amount.
Remember, whenever we run the H that commands all the queues and values need to be listed out as strings
in alternating order.
So this object is not sent over in its plain form to Redis.
Instead, Node Reddest has to do some processing on it first, and it's in that processing step that
this error starts to come up.
Here's what Node Reddit does.
It says, All right, I need to take this entire object and turn it into a plain h, get all command
that Reddit can understand so it starts to build up a string.
The first part of the string has the H get all keyword.
Then the key that we are trying to set, which in this case is car.
And then it starts to alternate just the same as normal h get all command e value, e value, key value
and so on.
You'll notice that in this example string right here, which is all the gray boxes I've already put
in all the keys.
So you've got color, your engine owner service.
So it's taking now all these values and inserting them into this string that we start to run into trouble.
All right.
So here's how no treatise actually gets our values into this string.
It's going to take a look at each individual value inside this object over here and call the two string
method on it.
That's where we're running into trouble.
So to put in a value for color.
Note this is going to take a look at this string right here.
Hold it to string method on it and the result gets put in right here and it ends up being a plain string
of red.
It then moves on to year and it's going to call 1952 string.
We end up with this string of 1950.
They'll then move on to cylinders.
Not going to really update these arrows.
I think you understand it's going to put engine right there.
So for engine, we're going to take the object.
Cylinders eight and called to string on it.
Whenever you do a to string on a plain object without any further configuration around it, you end
up getting a string of.
Objects which you might have seen before.
When using note, I can tell you that's probably not what we really expect to have in there for the
value of engine, but that's pretty much what happens.
You then try to do, you know, dot to string.
And that's where we get our air from.
So whenever you try to access a property on a value of null or undefined in JavaScript and try to read
any property, call it any function on it, you immediately get an error message one identical to what
we're getting back inside of our terminal right now.
The one that says you not read properties of null reading to a string.
That's what's going on behind the scenes.
That's why we were getting an error.
Note Bettis does not want us to allow to allow us to store a null value.
If we try to store null, it's going to call to string on it, and we're going to end up seeing that
same exact error message.
Well, this is definitely unexpected behavior, because in so many other databases and so many other
database clients that you might make use of.
Storing null or undefined is really not an issue, but it is with no reticence.
And it is you're going to see with many other programming languages as well when you're making use of
red.
So to get around this problem, what we might do is either remove these properties right here.
Or alternatively, if you really want to keep them around, but make sure that it's very clear that
no value actually exists here.
You might put in or empty string.
And that might indicate that hey, there is no owner.
Owners empty string therefore doesn't exist.
Might be null.
Now obviously having a string value here even of empty string versus null really changes the semantics
of your application.
Having an owner of NULL might have a different meaning than having an owner of empty string.
And that kind of means that we have to accommodate for this in some way as we're writing our application.
But this is the reality is all we have to deal with.
Okay.
So now if I save this.
And flip back over.
To my terminal.
Now I'll see that the set has succeeded and I've now stored empty string for honor and service and sure
enough engine.
It did get converted into that object object, which again is probably not what we really expect.
But what happens if we try to store an object?
All right.
Now, last thing I want to show you.
Very quickly, I'm going to remove those additional properties right there.
And we're going to take a look at some also interesting behavior around H get all but rather than let
this video get too long let's take a look at why each get all can sometimes be a little bit weird in
just a moment.