All right, so now h get all.
How could this command be weird?
All it does is look into Reddit, try to find a hash and return that hash.
That's pretty much it.
And it appears that everything is pretty much working as expected as we run the h get all inside of
our code.
Well where it starts to get weird is related to the default behavior of h get all.
Let's again take a look at a couple of diagrams and understand what I'm talking about.
Okay.
So let's imagine that we are again implementing some kind of API or web application and we expect at
some point time to receive a request that tries to retrieve details or get some hash stored in Redis
by a very particular ID.
Let's imagine that someone makes a request trying to fetch a car with ID by five three.
But very importantly, we're going to imagine that we do not have a car with an idea of five, five,
three.
We might have on it the idea of three one, two over here, but we definitely do not have one with an
ID of five, five, three.
VoLTE.
Regardless, we don't really know that until we look into Regis and try to access a key of five, five,
three.
So when we receive this request, we might make a command, send it off to Regis and try to do an H,
get all on a key of cars powered by five three.
So we sent off the H get all and then we get back response from retrofits.
And here's where things start to get interesting.
If we try to access a key that does not exist in reticence and try to read it as a hash, your expectation
might be to get back a value of null or undefined or something like that.
Something to indicate that we tried to fetch a hash, but it did not exist.
And Reddit's that is not the default behavior.
That is not what actually happens.
So you might expect to get back a value of null if you try to look up a key that does not exist.
But it's not what occurs.
Well, what would happen if we got back null?
If it behaved as we would probably expect back in our application, we'd probably take a look at whatever
was returned and say, Did we get back an object or did we get.
No, we get Noel.
We might respond with that for a for and if we get back an object or otherwise a truth value, something
besides null, we would probably take whatever that object was and respond with it.
But again, this is not what happens.
Here's what actually happens.
This is the actual behavior.
If you try to fetch a key with each guitar and that key does not exist.
The default behavior is to send you back an empty object.
That is very unexpected because now in our code, if we have that same kind of check, if we say, did
we get back an object or did we get null?
In this case, we are always going to get back an object because whenever we use it all, as long as
we are trying to look up either a key that refers to a hash or a key that does not exist, we will get
back an object of some kind.
So we're going to get back this object.
We're going to put in our same check right here and say, did we get back an object or null?
And we are always going to get back an object.
And so we're always going to respond with that object, even though we didn't actually find the car
that the request was looking for.
So we're never going to fall into this right hand path over here where we send back correctly a response
of four or four.
Okay.
So let's just verify this really quickly back inside of our editor.
So back over here.
We know that there is a hash or a key that refers to a hash of khat.
We know that exists.
So let's try looking up a key that definitely does not exist.
I can put in car and then some identifier like so.
So without a doubt that key does not exist.
No data is defined in red as with that key.
I'm now going to save this again, flip back over and sure enough, take a look at this.
I get a console.log of empty objects.
So if I had code inside my application.
That looks something like this.
If I had something like if car does not exist, if it's a false value.
So if it's false, null, undefined, empty string and so on, I might want to do a console.log of our
not found.
Respond with four of four.
And then maybe I would return right there and then otherwise console.log the car.
So with the default behavior of each get all, we are never going to enter the if statement no matter
what, even if we try to look up a car that does not exist.
So a very simple existence, Chuck, like this, which you might use and with just about any other kind
of database, is not going to work the way you would expect as we're never going to enter that if statements.
How do we solve this?
Well, the very simple workaround.
All we're going to do here is say.
If we get back an empty object, then we probably do not find the record we were looking for.
So I'm going to do a object that keys bar and look at the length.
If the length is equal to zero, then that means that we got back an empty object and we probably did
not find the car.
So we should respond to the four of four.
Now if I save this.
Go backward my terminal I see correctly card not found responded to borrow four.
But if I tried to fetch a car that does exist.
It's all change the age.
Get all back to just a string of car, which definitely does exist.
We're setting it right there.
Save this again.
Now I still get the original car that I was trying to fetch originally.
Okay.
So that is the really strange behavior behind each set and each get all.
And again, you need to know about these corner cases because these are really are the two main commands
we use all the time whenever we are making use of hashes.
So in summary, each sets, we always need to be very much aware of what data we are trying to save.
And number two, with each get all we need to be aware that we're always going to get back an empty
object, even if the record does not exist.
And so to see if we actually got the data we were looking for, we need to do a little bit more of a
complex check, like the one you see right here.
All right.
So now we understand these corner cases.
Let's go back over to our actual e-commerce application.
We're going to implement a couple of different queries using hashes.