We've taken a look at a couple of different house commands and as I've mentioned several times, they're
pretty simple and straightforward in nature.
Now, now it's time for us to actually figure out where to use hashes and how to use them effectively.
And believe it or not, even though the commands around hashes were very simple, well, it turns out
that actually making use of hashes in design, your application around them ends up being a little bit
more challenging.
So let me tell you about what we're going to do in this video and the next view.
We're going to first begin with a deep walkthrough of the eCommerce application that we are building.
Although we have installed it and written a little bit of code into it, we still haven't really gotten
a good overview of exactly what we are building.
So it's one make sure that part is super, super clear.
Once we understand what we are making, we're going to do some design work.
We're going to take a look at the different pieces of data that we need to store and we need to figure
out how we're going to store that data inside of Redis and out of all that data specifically.
Right now, I really want to figure out what data we're going to store as simple hashes.
And then finally, once we figure all that stuff out, time to write some code.
Okay.
So it's going to be a couple of videos to get through before we write some code.
And I got to tell you right now, the code that we're going to write really only going to be a couple
of lines.
So the real value here hopefully is taking a look at this entire design process.
Okay.
So first off.
The e-commerce application that we are working on your are some basic rules around this app.
So users are going to come to our application.
They're going to sign up, sign out and sign in.
Very basic, typical features.
Once a user has signed into our application, they can create an item to sell.
So an item is some kind of product that a user wants to sell on our platform.
All items are sold via auction type formats.
So a user can list an item at a certain price and then other users come and bid some amount of money
on that product.
Every item that gets created is going to have a starting price.
So you might list a say piano or something like that for $10.
Another user can then come and make a bid on that product or $10.
When the next user comes, they must bid a higher amount.
The next user who comes might be at 11 or 12 or $13, and then the next person would have to bid, say
15 and then 20 and so on.
Every item is going to have an ending time.
That's going to be some day, some very specific time.
Once that time passes, whoever has the highest bid wins the item.
Okay.
That's the general rules.
It's essentially just the same as, say, eBay or something similar to it.
So I'm going to take a look at some of the different mock ups around our application.
Now, as a reminder, the entire front end of this app has already been built for you.
So as we go through these mock ups is really just to help you get a better sense of what we are building
and some of the queries that we're going to have to write to actually make these different features
work.
We are not going to be writing any of the HTML or stuff like that to actually get these elements to
appear on the screen.
So first is our landing page.
On the landing page, we're going to have a very typical header up here that has a little search interface
buttons to sign in and sign up.
But then go on display three different carousels.
The carousel is a list of items that spans left and right.
A user can use these little arrows right there and right there to scroll through at this carousel and
see all these different items.
Every item is going to have a name and image the number of hours or really the duration left this auction.
So it might be hours, minutes, seconds.
And then the current bid price for this item.
That's true of all three sections.
The one exception is that most of you are down here at the very bottom.
One is also going to display the number of views that a product has received.
Now a very important requirement around views inside of our application.
We want to make sure that users don't try to game or kind of cheat the view system, because if a product
gets more views, it's going to show up more prominently on the websites.
We're going to make sure that whenever someone who is authenticated or logged into our application views
a product, we are going to count that as a view.
And a product can only be viewed by a user exactly one time.
So in other words, what I really mean by all that, if I click on this item right here and I go to
its particular page to show me all the details around it, I would add one view to it because I just
went to that page and looked at that particular item.
But if I then refresh that page, if I revisit that page many, many times, I'm not going to add on
any additional views.
So for any given user, they can only contribute one single view forever for any given product.
That might sound like a very small thing, but it turns out it's actually going to be a little bit of
a challenge to implement later on.
All right.
Lastly, want to mention here is that on these three different carousels, we are displaying items in
a very particular order.
The first is the most expensive.
So from most to least expensive.
Then the items that are an incident soonest and then the items to have the most views.
All right.
After that, we've got a sign in page where a user can enter in a user name and password to sign in
a sign up page.
Or user can enter in the username and password to sign up for an account.
Once a user is authenticated, the header is going to change up here just a little bit and the user
will get links to log out to go to a dashboard that's going to display all the items that this user
is selling and a link to list a new item to be purchased or auctioned off.
This page right here in particular is where a new oxygen will be created, which green auction a user
only has to enter in the name of the item, a short description and a duration.
Once the action has been created.
User can then go to the item show page.
This is where we're going to display information about a particular auction.
So there is a lot of content on this page right here.
We're just going to go over it very quickly because we're going to spend a lot of time on this page.
On the top left hand side is going to be a image of the product and the title, then a link to the seller's
profile page.
So that will be some information about the seller.
Well, then show the product description on the top right hand side.
We'll display an interface where a user can like this auction or like this product.
If I click on like right there, I would expect three, which is the current number of likes that this
item has to go up to four.
Well, then display the highest bid, the number of bids and win the auction or the amount of time left
in this auction.
Then a form to place a bid.
A little chart to display how the bid price has changed over time.
And then finally, another carousel down here not actually going to a carousel is just going to be a
static list of similar items.
So items that are somewhat similar in nature, we'll figure out exactly how we're going to measure similarity,
of course, later on.
All right, next page, just one or two more.
This is the cellar profile where you can look at all the items that another user is selling.
So on this page, we're going to display what items the seller likes.
And items that both the currently authenticated users.
In other words you and this person into like.
And then finally, one last page here, the dashboard.
This is where you can review all the items that you are currently selling.
So we're going to have a very fully featured table in here where we will list a ton of items that I'm
currently selling.
We'll have the name, the current price, I'm left bids, blah, blah, blah.
All that stuff on here.
Now, one thing to note in particular is that we were going to design this entire application, assuming
that this is going to be a very well trafficked website.
So we're going to assume that there could potentially be millions of different products being actively
sold at any given time.
But then mind, any time that we display a list of items like right here or any time that we display,
say, this table, we might be displaying just some records out of a set of thousands of different records.
So I wouldn't want to show a table right here with, say, a thousand different rows, which means we
need to implement some sort of pagination.
So we are only going to display, say, ten items at a time and then give the user a little paginated
down here.
That they can click on to look at different pages.
Same thing.
Back over here on the main landing page.
When we have these carousels, a user is not scrolling through all the different items we have on our
website.
They're only going to be looking at, say, the ten or 15 most expensive items.
Okay.
So that is the overview, overview of the features that are in this application.
So several different pages.
A lot of stuff going on here.
Definitely a lot of implementation that we have to worry about now that we've got this overview.
Time for us to jump into the high level design of all this stuff.
And remember, I want to really focus on in particular where we are going to use hashes to build this
application.
So let's start to think about the design of all this stuff in the next video.