Let's start to implement the get session and save session methods.
These are going to be very similar to the two functions we already put together in the last couple of
videos around saving and fetching a user.
Well, first begin with Git session.
So whenever this function is called, it's going to receive the ID and that idea right there is really
that session token that we were talking about in the last video.
So we want to take that ID right there.
We want to turn it into a registry key.
That was something like Sessions LB 551.
And you use that key to look up some hash that is stored inside of lettuce.
To do.
So first thing we have to do is create a new function.
Ember We are using these key functions to generate all of our keys for us rather than typing them out
from scratch.
So back inside of our services directory, I'm going to find that key state.
Yes.
File inside if you are going to create a new key function.
Of Sessions key.
That will take in some session ideas, an argument that's going to be a string.
And then we will return a string of sessions.
Hound.
Dollar sign really braces session ID.
Then back inside of our sessions.
It's vile.
At the very top, I'm going to import that helper that we just created.
And I'm also going to import our readies client as well.
So then inside of gift session.
I'm going to fetch our session out of treatise by doing and await client dot and then remember we once
again want to reach in a Redis, get a hash and all the data, all the key value pairs contained inside
of it.
And for that we can use the h git all command once again.
So h gets all.
And the very specific hash we want to retrieve is stored at Session's key ID.
After fetching that session, I'm going to return it.
All right.
Now, right before we return it, I also want to do a very quick console.log here of whatever we fetch
as we're going to very quickly see that we're going to run into a very small issue.
Okay.
I'm going to save this.
I'm going to go backwards, my terminal, and just make sure that my application is still running.
All right.
Looks good.
Definitely still running.
Remember, if it's not running for you, you can execute NPM run dev inside of your project directory.
And then going to go back over to the browser and test out our application.
So localhost 3000.
And sure enough, I end up seeing a kind of nasty error message here.
The data argument.
Blah, blah blah.
And some nasty stuff received undefined.
This is a little bit of a strange air, but clearly it is tied to the code that we just added in and
we did put in that console.log of session.
Let's go back over to our terminal and see what happened when we console.log that thing.
Here's my terminal.
Here's that same error message.
And then right above the error message is the console.log we just added in that says object, null,
prototype, and then curly braces.
The real console.log here is the curly braces.
And the curly braces means that we pulled out an empty object from Redis.
Now.
Why is that?
Well, remember, whenever we use the H get all command, it's going to go into Redis, try to find
a hash and get all the keys and all the values tied to it.
But if Redis does not find a hash stored at the key that you are trying to look at, it's going to give
you back an empty object instead.
So when we do.
A search or a lookup on some key that does not actually exist.
Let's say we try to look up sessions around something crazy and there is no key or no value associated
with that key.
Back inside of our code.
We are still going to get an empty object, though.
Is that an issue?
Well, yes, it is.
It turns out that everything else inside this application assumes that if you return any object from
JIT session, that must be a session object which implies that this person is signed into our application.
And that really makes a lot of sense in many different languages, lot of different cases.
Even with JavaScript, if you return some kind of object here, it kind of implies that the user is
signed in.
Well, we are only returning an object because that's the default behavior of it all.
So we really have to add in an additional check here.
We need to take a look at this session object and say if it is an empty object, well, then the user
is not actually signed in and we should return some kind of value that indicates that the person is
not signed in.
But if the user or the object has any properties inside of it, well, then this person must be signed
in and we should return that object.
So in short, rather than doing the console.log right there, I'm going to replace it with some code
to check to see if this is an empty object or not.
I'll put an object squeeze.
Session.
Length equals zero.
Let's go and take a look at all the different keys that exist on that object.
If there are no keys, that means that we just got back an empty object.
And this person must not be signed in.
They have no session tied to them.
So in that case, I'm going to return NULL.
That means user is not signed in.
Otherwise, if there are any keys on the session object, that means that the user is signed in.
We fetch a valid session object and so we should return that valid session object.
Now, if I save this and pull it back over.
I can refresh and the application works again.
All right.
Definitely good.
Now, we do have to create a serialize function here because we are attempting to retrieve some information
out of Redis.
We'll take care of that serialize function right now.
Just very quickly.
I'm going to create a new function at the bottom.
And we're really just going to do the exact same thing that we did back around our users.
So this function will receive the idea, the session and the session itself.
I'm going to give it that same type annotation.
Like.
So again, that just means we have an object with a couple of strings on it.
And then inside of here.
I'm going to return an object that has the ID.
A user ID.
And a username.
And then finally I'm going to make use of the serialize.
Like so.
And making the same mistake I made last time.
First argument needs to be about ID now once again.
Same thing that was going on previously.
Our DC realized function is going to take whatever we just pulled out of red is going to create a new
object that also has the ID attached to it, because that's probably how the rest of our application
is designed.
It's expecting it's going to get a session that has not only the session info but the idea of the session
as well.
Okay.
That looks good.
A quick pause will come back in just a moment and take care of our save session function.