All right, let's take care of our save session function that we're going to receive as an argument.
This session object.
If you hover over session right here and press control or command on your keyboard, you'll see that
we are receiving an object that has an ID, the user ID and a name.
So we need to take all that info and store it inside of Redis.
And once again we're going to implement a serialize function.
So we're going to take that whole object with those three different properties and we're going to pass
back an object that can be safely stored inside of Redis in particular.
In this case, all we're going to do is make sure we don't save that ID because although we can save
the ID inside this hash, it would be something like that only can do that if we want to.
But the idea is already contained in this thing's key.
We already know what the idea is.
It's right there and there's not any scenario where we are going to try to query over all of our different
sessions and find a session based upon that key value pair right there.
That's just a waste of space to add it into this object.
So we're going to implement that serialize function and just make sure we return an object that does
not have that ID property.
Okay.
Let's take care of.
How about the serialize function first?
So down here I will define serialized.
It's going to take in an argument of a session that is of type session.
And then return a new object that has just the user ID.
And just the username.
And that's it.
Now we can make use of this backup right here at save session.
So in here we will once again store some information inside of a hash.
Inside a lettuce can do so using the h set command again.
So I will return.
Client dots each set.
First arguments will be session key.
That's an I.D. So that's where we want to store this.
And the second argument is going to be the object we want to store.
So that's going to be our serialized session.
A serialized.
Russian.
And that should be Sessions key right there.
You'll notice that in this case we did not have to randomly generate an ID inside of here because the
such an object is being provided.
I already generated that unique idea somewhere else inside of our application.
That's the only reason we don't have to generate an ID.
If that should be it.
Well, that's pretty much everything we need to implement the sign up functionality inside of our app.
So if I go back over to my browser.
And go to the sign up page.
We need to sign up.
Right now.
Sign in.
Doesn't work.
I can then enter in a username here.
Now.
Just SDF and the password.
Well, then sign up, and that's pretty much it.
Now you'll notice that I do get a nasty error message once I am signed in.
We notice that at least the header up here has changed.
So it says that I am signed in as a user username of SDF and I can now see the ability to log out,
see my dashboard and so on.
There's still some stuff to fix up, but at least good enough for right now.