Last set of hashes we have to store inside.
Red is related to all the different items that are going to be for sale.
So let's start making sure that we can save and retrieve items.
Inside my code editor, I'll find the queries directory items and then items sorts.
Here it is right here.
So there are three separate functions we need to put together to make items work inside of our application.
First is git item which will retrieve a single item gets items which will get many different items at
the same time, and then finally creates item which will do exactly what you expect.
Let's first begin with create item.
All right, I'm going to open this function up.
So inside of here, we're going to receive some argument called outers and it is of type create item
adders.
Just to understand what we are trying to store, let's do a command click or control click on create
item adders.
Okay.
So our function is going to be called with an object that has a bunch of different properties.
And I want you to take note that a lot of these are strings and numbers, which we can, of course,
very easily store inside of Redis.
However, we have in this case to date objects.
And remember the whole reason we were talking about Serialize and this entire section we've been talking
about it non-stop is that whenever we are trying to take an object and stored it inside of Redis, we
have to convert it into something that can be safely stored in Redis.
And so this is a perfect example of that.
Read it at an ending at r two objects.
We need to somehow store this date information in some way that is safe to be stored in Redis.
Now, whenever we store a date of any kind in Redis, we have a little decision to make.
In the previous diagrams around serialization that I've shown you.
I've said, Oh yeah, we want to save the date as some useful formats.
And so it might be a string like this right here.
It has a year, month, day and time, and then a timezone offset.
We might do the same thing, but with a slightly different format.
Now we can definitely store dates in these formats because they are strings in Redis, but there's a
little issue with it.
By default, writers can't really do any kind of query or any sorting operation on dates that are in
these format.
This is by default.
We can technically add support for it, but it's just a little bit challenging.
So if we store dates in these formats, they're not immediately super useful to us in Redis.
So instead, we might decide to store our dates in a slightly different format and that is using UNIX
time.
Your next time represents a single time.
So both a day, month, year, our minute, second and A represents it as the number of seconds that
have elapsed since January 1st, 1970.
So this is a number.
So it can definitely be stored in Redis.
And because it is a simple number, we can very easily write code that will do queries or searching
for a value like this.
Alternatively, if we need a better resolution than just seconds because sometimes you want more fine
grained resolution on your dates and your times than just seconds, you can instead store Unix time
as milliseconds does the same idea.
It is an amount of time that has elapsed since January 1st, 1970, but instead of just the number of
seconds, we instead multiply basically by 1000 and we get milliseconds.
Given that you and I are making an auctioning application and we really care about having precise time.
Whenever it comes down to those very last milliseconds, whenever someone is trying to purchase an item,
we might want to store all of our dates using millisecond resolution, as that can make sure that we're
always very accurate in when we close bidding for an item.
Okay.
So that's what we're going to do in our application whenever we have a time value that we want to store
in anyway.
So like these to date objects right here and we need to store those in Redis.
We're going to take those date objects and convert them into Unix time as milliseconds.
And if you don't know how to do that in JavaScript, don't worry.
Of course I'll show you how to do that.
That is the easiest part of everything we're doing here.
All right.
Let's take a brief pause right here.
When we come back, the next video we're going to write out our serialize function that whenever we
tried to save an object with this structure, we're going to make sure we take those date values and
turn them into numbers.