For all the reasons we just discussed non-stop.
We need to take this abta's object and serialize it to serialize something.
Normally we would make a helper function inside the same file, but in this case we're going to eventually
have a lot of code inside this item sports file.
So I made a separate file inside the items directory.
It's called serialized.
Yes.
This is where we are going to define our serialize function.
This function is going to be called with that actors object.
So we need to return a new object where all the keys and values can be safely stored in Redis.
Now to create this object.
We could do the same thing we did previously around our sessions, where we list out one by one all
the different properties we want to serialize.
That could be something like name, address, dot name and then image URL at a resort image your you
are l.
These are just all the properties of that to create item adders object.
But listing all these different properties one by one gets really tiresome.
The only properties we really need to serialize here are the created at an ending at properties.
So to save ourselves just a little bit of time, I'm going to use a shortcut.
I'm going to write in dot, dot, dot outers.
Which is going to take all the different properties and values inside this object and just copy them
over to this brand new object.
And after the dot, dot, dot ATRs, I'm going to write out the only properties I actually want to reformat
or serialize.
Which are the.
Read it at an ending at values.
All put in created acts, and that's going to be matters.
Read it out.
And we need to convert this from the date time object that it currently is into a millisecond unique
value.
But to do that conversion, we'd right out to Mills and that's it.
That's how we do that conversion.
So now when we return, this object, we're going to have to redo that.
Instead of being that big datetime object, we've got that millisecond value which can be safely stored
and very easily queried inside of Redis.
Well, then do the same thing for.
Ending at what it's called?
Yes, ending at.
So Adam Scott ending at the noise.
And that's it.
That's our serialized function.
Okay.
So back over two items.
Yes.
Once again, we're working on every item right here in order to create our item and save it.
We need to import a couple of things at the top.
First, I'm going to import our Rita's clients.
I will import the serialize function we just put together.
I got to get the gen I.D. function.
Oh, bad import there.
There we go.
Now a quick reminder on Gen ID, we spoke about this when we were saving users registers not create
keys for you automatically doesn't create IDs for you automatically.
So if you want to have unique identifiers for all your different keys, you need to create those IDs
on your own.
And that's what the gen ID function does for us.
This creates random IDs that hopefully are not duplicated inside of our database.
Now the last thing we need because we are going to store some information.
Remember, we are using those key generation functions.
Make sure we never make a typo around our different keys.
We have not yet created a key function for our items.
So let's go and make one right now.
We've been through this process a couple of times.
So back inside of our services directory.
I'm going to find keys.
Yes.
I'm going to make a new generation function specifically for saving items.
The argument to this is going to be the idea of our item.
I'm going to save all my items under these different keys that will have the format items.
Around.
Dollar sign, curly brace item ID.
And once again, don't forget, we got back text right here.
Those are not single quotes.
All right, that looks good.
Now, we can import this very last piece back into the items file.
Okay.
All for imports.
I think that finally is all we need to actually create an item.
Now inside of create item.
We will make our I.D..
We will serialize.
The actors.
So now a serialized is ready to be stored inside of our database.
We can do and await clients.
Each set we're going to generate our key using items key and pass in the ID.
And then finally, second argument will be the data we actually want to store serialized.
Then after actually saving that information, last thing you have to do is return the idea of the item
that was created.
Now, this is not strictly necessary in every reddest application.
It's just the way, again, I put this app together.
I need to know what the idea of the item was.
We just created in some other part of the application.
So I'm going to return the ID.
And that should be it.
Now we are actually ready to do a very quick test.
So if I go back over to my browser.
I'm going to make sure that I am signed into the application.
I should see the dashboard up here again.
Looks like this or the header.
I'm going to click on new.
And we go to a form where we can actually create an item.
There's already some default values in here.
I put the default values in just so we don't have to type out some values every time we want to do a
test.
I'm going to click on Submit and then we will probably see an error right after.
But we should have created our item and to verify that.
Take a look at the URL inside your address bar.
The very last part of the URL I'm going to copy it over here is as you can read on my screen very easily,
the very last part of the URL should be the idea, the item that was just created.
But to make sure our item truly was made.
I'm going to copy that.
I'm going to go back over.
Our book.
And we can do a little query here so.
And get all.
And look up the E responding to our house.
And that should be item's colon or items found.
There we go.
And then the idea that we just got, if I run that well, sure enough, it looks like we have successfully
created an item.
We've got the name, description and duration stuff.
Lot of stuff here, but this looks pretty good.
Now that we've got this saved and start to work on making sure that we actually match items so we can
actually view these things inside the browser as well.
Let's work on those other two functions in just a moment.