Let's get started on the git item function.
So inside of here, we're going to go through some operations that are just about identical to when
we fetched a user and a session a little bit ago.
But first, we're going to take a look in red is using our red is client.
And do a each gets all.
And we want to look up the key specifically at items key with this particular ID.
That's going to give us back our item.
Now, remember what we've been discussing nonstop here.
Whenever we do an H, get all using Redis.
If we find some key or we're trying to find a key that doesn't actually exist by default, we're going
to get back an empty object.
And we need to handle that because if we get back an empty object, we didn't actually find what we
were looking for.
Now we need to return some signal to whoever is calling this function and let them know that they tried
to look up some data that does not yet exist.
But I'm going to do a if object he's item that length is equal to zero.
Okay, we got an object, but it wasn't actually the data we were looking for.
I will return null in that case.
And that is the sign to whoever called get item that well, they're trying to find an ID or an item
that doesn't actually exist in Redis.
Then if we get past that statement, it turns out that we actually did find the item we were looking
for, but we need to now serialize it.
Before we return it.
Let's make sure that we implement a serialize function once again inside of our items directory.
I'm going to find D serialized.
Yes.
Here is d serialize.
So our function is going to be called with the idea.
The item we just found and the raw attributes we got out of red is as well.
And then we are expected to return an object of type item.
That's what the colon item over here at the very end means.
You need to understand what attributes an item has.
We could always do a command click on item.
And it will be told that an item should have an ID name.
Blah, blah blah.
All this stuff.
And most notably.
It needs to also have a created that's an ending at property and both those need to be actual date time
values.
Remember, we stored our date times as millisecond values.
We're really, really just plain numbers, but they represented milliseconds in Unix time, so we now
need to take those values.
So we just got out of Redis and turn them back into DateTime objects.
The other thing to be aware of is that when we get our data or views likes price and whatnot out of
Redis, they're going to show up as strings because everything that gets stored in Redis is stored as
a string.
So when we get these values back from Redis, we need to make sure we turn them back into numbers.
So a lot of work we're going have to do inside of D.C. realize here.
Let's get started.
The inside of DC relies on an returning new object.
And unfortunately, in this case, we're gonna have to write out pretty much every single property,
one by one.
But first, we're going to say, here's the ID.
Name will be item name.
Description of the item dot description.
Image u.
R l the item dot image url.
And then just two others that are not going to require any kind of messing with or anything like that.
So highest.
Bid user ID is item Dot's highest bid user ID.
An owner I.D. is item, not owner ID.
You'll notice, though, we haven't really spoken about some of these properties at all just yet, such
as high speed user ID and owner ID.
Don't worry, we're going to do a deeper dive on what all these properties are related to an item later
on.
But as you can guess, they're really tied into the bidding system and whatnot.
So not super relevant to discuss just yet.
Now comes the interesting stuff.
Here are the properties we actually have to mess around with a little bit in order to make sure that
they are actually available to the rest of our application in a format that we kind of expect and want
to work with.
The first will be repeated at again when we get this item object right here.
This is the data that we pulled out of Redis.
We're going to get a millisecond value and that's going to show up as a string.
So we have to do a couple of different operations.
We have to take that created at string value.
We have to pass it into an integer and we have to take that integer and turn it into a datetime object.
So in total.
You have to do a pass int an item created at.
That's going to give us a number.
We then will do a date time from Millis.
That's how we get back into a date time object.
And that's it.
So now we're going to have created that as a date object.
Well, then repeat that same operation for ending that as well.
If that looks good.
Now there are a few other properties.
So these different numbers right here, we have to do use likes, price bids.
And again, all these are going to show up inside of our DC realized function as strings.
We need to parse them back into integers or floats.
The four views will have pass int item dot views.
Four likes will have passed into item dot likes.
For bids.
And then finally.
And in the case of price, rice is going to be a float or essentially a number that has a decimal is
we want to allow users to bid, say, $5.30, assuming they are paying in U.S. dollars.
I'm going to float instead.
Item dot price.
And that's it.
As soon as I do all this parsing now, all the errors inside this file go away.
I don't have any issues whatsoever.
I am now returning an object that is truly an item where I had previously started off with an object
where everything was a string.
All the keys were strings.
All the values were strings.
Okay.
So that's it for Serialize.
Now let's step back inside of items.
Yes.
Here's the one we were just working on.
Item starts right here.
I'm going to import the cereals at the top.
And then inside of get item after we make it past the if statements we can return.
E serialize.
Item.
And I spell that correctly.
Yes, I did.
Well, that's right.
I made November 3rd time.
I made this mistake.
Now, the first argument is supposed to be the idea, the item we just got so we can merge it into the
object that gets returned.
I can't believe I've made that mistake three times now.
My mistake.
There we go.
That works.
Okay.
So now in theory, we should be able to create an item and then view it.
We might still see a couple of errors.
We probably will see an error or two, to be honest.
But let's at least try it very quickly.
Though, back over at our application.
Oh, I actually kind of worked the test out.
In total, I would go to new after signing up to the application.
Remember, we don't have any sign in just yet.
So if you need to sign up again, go and sign up.
We can then use the default info right here.
I'll click on submit and sure enough, we can then see the item that was created.
So I've got the title, I've got a description and some other info in here as well.
Now, if you start to place a bid, of course, that's not going to work just yet.
You can't like it because we not actually implemented any of that stuff just yet.
But at least we can actually view an item though.
Good progress forward.