Okay.
Time to think about the data design of our application.
Now, as a reminder, we came up with this design methodology couple of videos ago.
I told you that if we were working in the SQL database world, the general strategy that we use for
designing an application is to just throw all of our data into tables, and then after that we can figure
out how to query all that data.
And that totally works in a sequel world.
But when we are making use of Redis, we approach these problems in a reverse order.
We instead first figure out what queries we need to answer, what data do we actually have to fetch
out of our database, and what changes do we need to make?
And only after we make that list of what queries we need to answer are we going to figure out how to
structure our data specifically to answer those queries and nothing more.
In other words, we're not quite planning for the future with readies.
We're not quite planning.
Say what is a possible feature, we might add, in ten years down the line.
Instead, we are designing for our requirements right now.
By designing for our current set of requirements, we almost always can come up with a much better design
and by better, I really mean faster.
We can come up with a much faster way and more compact way of storing all the data for our app.
So if we were in a school based kind of world, I could tell you right away this is probably exactly
what we would end up doing.
We'd have a table users that stores all the different users we have and a table of items that we're
trying to sell or really those users are trying to sell.
And then we might have some number of relations between those two tables tied together with other tables
of use likes and bits.
And that's pretty much it.
That would be our entire sequel type database design.
Pretty easy, straightforward.
We can just throw all the data into our database in the structure and then figure out how we want to
query it later on.
But again, that's not what we're doing.
So.
To figure out what queries we need to answer.
A good strategy for this is to take a look at our mockups that we just went over and figure out all
the different elements on the page, what data is required to actually make them function.
So let's do that right away.
Okay.
So we're looking at the same mock ups here and we're trying to figure out what queries or changes to
data.
In other words, what are we really doing inside of our database to implement all the features on every
page?
Going through each page.
And I wrote out some distinct queries or operations that we need to make each of them work as expected.
I'm going to very quickly we're not going to go through all them in great detail.
I'm going to very quickly go over some of them.
Vast majority.
These are going to be pretty obvious from the get go.
The first the carousel right here, right there and right there.
We need to be able to find a list of items sorted by price, sorted by ending time and sorted by use.
We also need the little search widget at the very top, the ability to search for items by name.
So that's a little search bar up here in the header.
On the sign in page.
Whenever a user enters in a username, we need to find some user inside of our database with the same
exact username so we can compare passwords and make sure that the user is trying to sign in with some
authentic credential.
We need to be able to find a user with a given username.
Also to support our entire authentication system, we need to be able to create something called a session,
find a session, and also get a user with a given ID.
These three right here are tied to the authentication system.
We'll go over them in greater depth.
On the sign up page.
We need to be able to create a user.
On the item page.
We need to be able to, of course, create an item.
An item show lot of things going on here.
So we need to go to you in the item by ID.
Fine.
Number of likes.
Like an item.
Unlike an item, you need to go to see if the current user is the person who assigned in to our app
and viewing this page likes the item they are looking at.
We need to be able to create a bid.
We need to be able to get the bid history for an item so we can display this nice looking chart right
here.
We need to be able to find similar items and in addition, we need to take care of that view behavior
that I mentioned in the last video.
So remember, views are unique per user, so any user can only ever contribute one view per item.
Okay.
Last two pages right here.
So on the seller profile page, you need to find all the items that a user likes so we can display that
section and then find all the items that two different users, both like that section right there.
And then finally, for this big table, we need to find a list of all items created by one particular
user, and we need to be able to sort them by various criteria.
So you can't really tell in this diagram right here in this mockup, but if I click on say view's a
little header right there, my intent is to see this entire table sorted by the number of views that
a product has.
And same thing for price time left, number of bids and so on.
So we need to be able to support some very robust sorting criteria.
All right.
So that's a lot of stuff going on.
So I took all those different theories, all the different operations, and here they all are on one
screen.
So, again, a lot of stuff going on here.
But the important thing to note, these are the only operations that we need to implement.
We have been given a design for an application at this point.
We see those mockups, but we only need to meet that specification.
We don't really need to plan for ten years down the road because remember with Redis, what we're really
targeting is speed.
That's what it's all about.
We are trying to build an application, be as fast as possible, and in some cases we are willing to
let go of some flexibility in our data model.
So it might be a little bit harder to implement later additional features later on compared to a small
database.
But in the meantime, as we build this application, it is probably going to be far faster than if we
were using a cycle database.
Out of all these different features, I've grouped them into read operations and rights operations.
Everything on the left hand side is a read.
We are trying to query or retrieve some data from the database and everything on the right hand side
are rights.
This is data that we are trying to change.
Okay.
So now that we have a little bit of backstory, we understand or at least we can say that we've got
a list of the different things we need to build into our application.
Now it's time for us to figure out what is the actual design here?
How are we going to actually represent all the data inside of our app?
Well, the first thing that we should do is figure out how we are going to represent the different things
we're kind of records inside of our application.
So as I look over the map or any of our mockups, I really see six distinct things that we need to store
six different types of records.
I see that we need to store users.
We need to store sessions, which you recall are tied to the authentication system.
We will go over those in greater detail.
We need to store items, IDs, views and likes.
So these are distinct records we need to store inside of our database.
And the question that I want to answer for right now is simply which of these should be stored as hashes?
Let's try to answer that question in one last video around all this design stuff.