After going through our mock ups, we have identified six different kinds of resources that we need
to store inside of us.
For each of these different resources, we need to figure out whether or not we should represent them.
Inside bread is using a hash.
That's we're going to figure out inside this video how to figure out whether we should represent each
of these different kinds of resources as a hash or not.
We need some reasons to say, hey, here are scenarios in which we should use a hash and here are some
where we shouldn't.
And so that's what I came up with on the left hand side of this diagram.
I have some reasons where we should use a hash to represent some kind of data, and then some cases
where maybe using a hash is not super appropriate.
So we are going to want to use a hash any time we have a record that has many different attributes tied
to it.
A good example, this would be an item.
An item has an image URL.
So the location of an image for the item, a title, a description, it has probably a price and some
other information tied to it.
So a item has many different attributes tied to it, which is probably going to make it a good candidate
for being a hash.
We also are going to only access one item at a time in many different scenarios.
We have an entire page, as a matter of fact.
This one right here, the item show page that is entirely dedicated to just showing information about
one single item.
Whenever a user comes to this page, they intend to look at one item.
And so we want to reach into our database and fetch all the different pieces of information tied to
this information with as few a queries as possible.
So in a perfect world, to get all the information for this page, I would only have to make one single
query into our database that would allow us to show a single item show page very efficiently.
And then finally, if we ever intend to, that's a collection of a record, and we want to sort them
in many different ways.
That is a good candidate to use a hash as well.
And that is also very true of items, for example.
So for our items, we've got this table over here.
And as I mentioned, as we click on these different headers, I want to sort all of these items in different
ways.
So if I click on name, I want to sort all my items by name.
I click on price, I want to sort them by price and so on.
So without a doubt.
As you could probably guess, we probably are going to want to store our list of items using hash data
structures.
We're going to have every item, every individual item that we are selling stored as a separate hash.
Eventually, we'll have many, many, many different hashes stored inside of our database, each of
which represent a single item.
Now, how about some cases where maybe we don't want to use a hash?
Well, we probably do want to use a hash any time that the record that we are storing is only used for
accounting purposes, we're enforcing some kind of uniqueness.
Good examples of this would be our views and our likes.
This likes thing is really just about enforcing uniqueness and counting so any user can only like an
item one single time.
So there's kind of a uniqueness check in there, and it's also being used to store the number of likes
that a product has.
So we're probably going to want to find some other data structure to store a list of likes.
Same thing for views as well.
Views is really just counting up the number of views that a product has.
And remember, we are only going to allow any user to view a product one single time.
Well, a pro can be viewed as many times as you want, of course, but only the very first time that
you view a product.
Are we going to increment the number of views that that product has?
Other cases where we might not want to use a hash is if our record has only one or two attributes,
if the record is only be used for relational data.
We'll go into some details on that later on.
Or finally, if we are only using this record to store some kind of time series data.
So kind of snapshots of a single value or one or two values that are changing over time.
All right.
So those are reasons where we might want to use a hash or not use a hash with all those in mind.
Let's categorize the remaining records here.
So for storing all the different users inside of application, well, they're going to have many different
attributes.
And we're probably only going to need to access a single record at a time.
And that's definitely true of users.
We are going to have many, many different users stored as separate hashes or probably only every one
to fetch a single user at a time.
In other words, there is no page inside of application where we need to fetch all of our different
users and show them any table.
The users definitely satisfy.
This rule right here.
Sessions are also going to fall into a similar category.
And remember, we're going to go into more on sessions very shortly.
And that really just leaves.
Bids for bids might have many different attributes.
And well, I don't think we're ever going to really need to access a single record or a single bid at
any given time, because usually whenever we are showing information around bids, yes, we are showing
like the latest price of a product.
Whenever we are showing information about bids on this item at Show Page, we are definitely showing
collection of all bids.
So we've got the number of bids right here.
And on this chart right here, we are displaying the change in bid price over time.
And you might recall I just said a moment ago.
If we are using the record only for time, series data might be a better data structure for representing
that.
Though bids may be not going to be represented as a hash inside cyber application.
It definitely could.
Let's say that right now we're going to see that there is perhaps a better data structure that we could
use.
Okay.
So that's it.
So the end result of all this work is we are going to represent sessions, items and users making use
of hashes.
But for representing bids inside of our app likes and views, we're going to see that there are perhaps
better data structures to represent them.
Okay.
That's it.
We've got some direction to go in here.
So we're going to come back in next video.
And we're going to start to write some code to store sessions or users and items inside of our database.