I'm to work on some implementation.
So in this video and the next couple, we're going to work on storing and retrieving users sessions
and items.
The first function we're going to work on is the create user function, which will allow us to store
a user inside of Redis.
We'll go over the implementation of this function very closely.
But first, one small reminder inside of your code editor, we're going to find the CRC folder and then
services and then keys.
Yes.
Inside the ski resorts file.
You might recall that we are going to put together a couple different functions that just make it easier
to generate.
The different keys that we want to access.
Inside of red is the only goal of these different functions is to avoid having to write out these strings
all over the place inside of our code base, which would definitely result in some typos.
So I'm going to immediately add in a new key function inside of here.
The goal of it is to give us a key where we can store a hash for a user or a hash that represents a
user.
So here's the user hash.
We're going to eventually store users username and password and possibly some other information.
We are writing the function that is going to generate the key that is referring to that hash.
Yeah.
So I'm going to create a new function and export it.
I'm going to call it user's key.
This will take as an argument the user's ID, so I'm going to call it user ID and it's going to be a
string.
So we're going to say that every user inside of our application is going to have a unique ID, we're
going to take the string users pounds and then join that together with that unique user ID.
And that's how we can refer to any user that is stored inside of Redis.
So as an example of this inside of lettuce, we might eventually have a key of users pound and then
some unique ID right after it's.
So if we now had that unique I.D. right there or if someone gave us that I.D., they provide it to our
application and they asked us to find a user with that ID, we would put that ID into that function.
It would give us back this entire key.
We would look up that entire key inside of lettuce, and we would get back our hash data structure that
has all the information about our user.
Okay.
Now, as a reminder, you don't have to join together strings in JavaScript or TypeScript like this
if you don't want to.
So optionally, you can replace the single quotes with back ticks.
And then right after that pound sign put in a dollar sign user ID all the optional don't have to do
it if you don't want to.
Okay.
That looks good.
Now we'll start to work on the it creates user function.
So to find that function, I'm going to again go to my services directory.
I'm going to go to Redis.
To me, queries.
And then users got to.
Yes.
Inside the queries folder.
There are three functions inside of your right now it user by username, get user buy ID and create
user.
We're going to first work on create user.
So let's take a look at how this function is going to work.
Here we go.
So inside of our application, someone is eventually going to make a request to sign up as a brand new
user.
So a user is going to give us a username and password.
That username and password is going to be put into a plain JavaScript argument and provided as an argument
to the create user function.
You can verify that very easily by finding great use right here.
You'll notice there is an argument called ATRs.
So that is an object that contains the username and password that the user wants to sign up with.
If you mouse over, create user adders right here and hold down the command or control key on your keyboard,
you'll notice.
Yep.
TypeScript says that this is an object that has a username and password.
That's all it is.
So that object will be provided to create user inside the create user function.
We have to do a couple of different things.
First, we have to generate a unique ID for this user.
Reddest does not generate IDs for us, so we need to come up with some unique ID that refers to the
user that we are about to create.
So we might generate an ID inside of your.
Of something like, I don't know, something like that right there.
Once we have generated this ID, we can then use it to store this brand new user as a hash.
So we're going to take that ID, we're going to put it into the key function that we just put together.
And so we're going to end up with a key of users account and then that unique ID that we just generated.
And then we're going to store at that key our hash, which has a username.
And a password.
And then from the great user function, we're going to return the ID of the user that was just created.
So the idea that we just randomly generated.
That's it.
That's what's going on inside of create user.
Now, just, you know, the only reason that we are returning the idea right here is because another
part of the application that's going to eventually called create user just needs to know the idea.
The person that was just created.
That's it.
It's not strictly required that we always return the ID from these functions or anything like that.
It's just how I built this application.
All right.
So now that we've got the overview of what's going on here back inside of user, yes, I have already
imported a function right here called Gen ID that we can use to randomly create a brand new unique ID.
So that's what we're how we're going to create the unique I.D. We're going to use that function that
they already imported for us.
In addition to that import, I'm also going to import our red clients.
And I'm also going to import that key function that we just put together.
So that's user's key from.
Services.
He's.
Okay.
So now, finally.
We can put together our creat user function.
So inside of here I going to first generates our brand new random ID to identify the person we are about
to create.
And then going to use our red list clients to store our information inside of reddish reds using the
h set commands.
I will do and await client dot.
H.
That's.
The first argument to set is going to be the key where we want to store our hash.
So in other words, that entire key right there, that whole big string.
So the first argument we will put in users key and provide that the ID so remember that's going to generate
our whole big key, the place inside of Redis where we are storing our house.
Then as the second argument.
I'm going to provide an object that lists out all the key value pairs I want to store inside of Redis.
Now, this is very different than the set command we used.
Back inside of red is cloud.
Just a moment ago, the here is the documentation or the notebook we just put together.
So we made use of H sets and when we used H that, we put in the key where we wanted to store our information
and then we alternated key value.
Key value.
And those key value pairs were the information we wanted to store inside of our hash.
ENCODE registry library that we are using does not work in the same way.
Instead, the H set command expects to receive an object that lists out all the different key value
pairs that we want to store inside this hash.
So we're going to put in an object right here.
And just to be super clear about what's going on.
We're going to write out manually the key value pairs.
So we're going to store inside Redis.
It's going to be a username that comes from Adam Scott username.
And a password that comes from at her source password.
And then finally after doing that h that operation, we can finally return the ID that was created,
which you will recall I said, is not strictly required.
When we're using Redis, we are just returning the ID because another part of our application expects
to get that ID.
Okay.
Two notes here.
First note.
The Outers object that we are receiving is basically identical to the Adders or this object that we're
putting in as a second argument to each set.
There is a reason for that.
There's a reason we're basically recreating this object.
I'll show you why in just one moment.
There's a very good reason for it.
Second thing, I just want to remind you about the set command.
If you are following it.
The official documentation uses this key value in a simple list, but when we are using this particular
client, they use a different syntax for the set command and that is give us an object with all the
key value pairs.
You want to store it inside of Redis.
Third note I just remembered there's one other note very quickly, just, you know, usually when we
store passwords inside of a database, we salt and hash these passwords for security purposes.
Just you know, I'm already doing that operation for us.
So if a user tries to sign up with a password of three three, another part of the application is automatically
salting and hashing this thing.
So the actual password that gets stored is something like that.
Okay.
That's it.
We've got great user put together.
Now.
I'm still going to tell you why we are duplicating this object right here in just a moment.
Two other things I want to mention as well very quickly.
First off, there are some other checks that we might want to do when we are storing a user.
For example, we want to make sure that the user name that they are trying to sign up with is unique.
We might want to make sure that the idea is unique, but definitely the username.
That is something that we will add in later on.
We'll make sure that the user that a person is signing up with is unique and is not in use by anyone
else.
The other thing I want to mention, I know this video has been very long for a very small amount of
code right here.
Don't worry, as we add in more functions to this project, we're going to go through these much, much
faster.
Right now, I just want make sure that everything is super, super, crystal clear.
So I know adding in code to an existing project can sometimes be really confusing.
Okay, so that's it.
Just one or two quick notes around this second argument right here in just a moment.