In this video, we're going to discuss why we created that separate object right there as opposed to
just directly passing in the Outers arguments.
Remember, ATRs is going to be an object that has a username and password.
And rather than just passing that argument directly through, I said, let's create a separate object
and be really explicit about what data we are trying to save in Redis.
Now I want to show you why that is in a series of different diagrams.
All right.
A lot of stuff going on here.
So let's just dive right.
Let's imagine for just a little bit that we were working on a different application that is all about
storing company info inside of Redis.
So we might have a company object like what you see right here.
It has an ID, name, screenshots and a revenue value.
So we want to save this entire object into Redis as a hash.
Let's imagine that we build a save company function and its goal is to save that object into a hash
that looks like this right here.
Now, one thing to keep in mind is that whenever we save a number into us, like one, two, three,
four, internally that gets saved as a string, a one, two, three, four, as the ID would show up
as one, two, three, four, as a string.
Then concrete co revenue would be the string 89 and an over here credit at is a JavaScript date object.
Now internally whenever the node readies library that we are using and remember that is the library
we are using to communicate with Redis.
Whenever we provide a value like a JavaScript date object to it node Redis is going to call the two
string method on this object right here.
Automatically, even though we are putting in a date object node, Redis is going to turn that thing
into a string to the best of its abilities by calling the two string method.
The result is that we would end up with a created at value right here.
That is a string with some kind of weird formatting to it.
It is essentially the default way in which a date object gets represented as a string in JavaScript,
so would end up as something like Tuesday, March three, 1915, and then 90304 Central Time or something
like that.
That would be the string representation of a JavaScript object, date object.
There's nothing inherently wrong about that string.
The issue is that it's really hard to query in any reasonable way.
Not a super common format.
In addition, it is formatted according to your local time zone and we might want to have it in a different
time zone.
They're just relying upon the default behavior of note reticence, not the best thing in the world.
There are.
There's one other small issue here as well.
So when we store that object in Redis, not only do we start to run into this issue around the date
formatting as it shows up in Redis.
The other issue is that we included the ID in the hash.
So in other words, that ID right there is included.
Is that inherently a problem?
Not really.
But let me tell you what I mean.
Whenever we want to look up some value inside of Redis, specifically for a hash, we are always going
to need to know the idea of the hash that we're trying to find.
So in other words, if we want to find this hash right here, we need to know that we are looking for
the hash with ID.
One, two, three, four.
And if we have that ID, well, rather than trying to find some hash that has ID, one, two, three,
four, we can just take that ID and use it to generate our key.
So we can create a key company at one t34 and immediately get access to this entire hash.
But what I'm trying to say is we don't really need to store the ID as a key value pair inside the hash
because we already know what record this it it is.
It is the company with I.D..
One, two, three, four.
It is recorded right there inside the key.
I recording the ID inside of our house.
We're just using up a little bit of extra memory and remembering, remember, whenever we stored information
in memory.
Memory costs more in general than hard drive space, so we usually want to pare down our records with
readies to be as small as we possibly can.
Removing that ID field is generally a little bit desirable.
Okay.
So these are two distinct issues that we run into when we start to try to save a plane JavaScript object.
Now, I want to look at the flip side of the equation here.
What happens when we try to pull out information from Redis?
Okay.
So let's imagine that we put in a couple of corrections and we now have a company stored in Redis without
an ID and we have also formatted that created app field in a slightly better format.
Now let's imagine that we tried to get this information out of Redis by implementing a function called
Get Company.
So get company is going to find this hash right here, get access to it as a plain JavaScript object,
and then return that object for the rest of our application to use.
So this is what gets returns whenever you call get company.
Now there are a couple of issues with this object as well.
Let's lay out what the issues are.
First off, when we make this object available to the rest of our application, we probably want other
parts of our application to know what the idea of this record is.
But because we didn't directly save that idea with our hash, well, it doesn't really get communicated
to the rest of our application.
Secondly, whenever we pull a hash out of Redis, it shows up inside of our application with all the
number values still encoded as strings.
The revenue would be a string of 89.
Finally we did figure out or we kind of are imagining that created out was stored as a useful string
right here with useful formatting that is easy to query.
But when we pull it out of lettuce, that string is still going to be the string.
15th March 1915 and the rest of our application might expect created out to be a JavaScript date and
not a plain string.
All right.
So let's kind of review where we are at right now.
The issue that we are running into is that if we just rely upon the default behavior of the note ratings
library that we're using and readies itself when we save info in treatise, it is kind of being saved
in a format that we don't really like.
And when we pull information out.
It is coming out.
Not quite in the way we really want.
Not in a way that's super useful.
We don't know what the idea of this record is.
We don't have our numbers as true numbers.
And some things like, say, a JavaScript date object might be in a format that we don't really care
for.
So how are we going to solve all these problems?
Well, we're going to solve them by introducing two functions that we're going to use rather often whenever
we are saving data in treatise or matching data.
The name of these functions are serialize and serialize.
Now, one thing to be clear about right away, the name Serialize as a helper function.
There's nothing special about the name of this function.
This is not plugging into any library.
It is not plugging into any framework or anything like that.
The only reason that I'm calling these serialized.
Serialized is that many engineers understand the words serialize and de serialize in general, in web
development and in systems program in general.
Serialize means take some information and encode it to be sent off and stored or used by some other
kind of system.
And the term e serialize in general means receive some information that might be encoded in a strange
way and prepare this information to be used in a format that is readily consumed by our application.
Again, the names serialize and de serialize.
Nothing special about them.
So whenever we are going to save information.
Internet is not always but vast majority of time.
Rather than just take this entire object right here and throw it directly into lettuce and allow red
s and the note read as library to format all the keys and values in there as it pleases.
We're going to instead do the formatting on our own.
We're going to use a serialize function to take that object and possibly remove fields from it, or
encode other fields in a way that we are happy storing inside of lettuce.
So, for example, Serialize might take that big object.
It might decide to remove the I.D fields, and we might decide to take that date object and encode it
in a more useful way.
That is all serialized and I just want repeat one more time.
Nothing special about the name here.
It is not plugging into any library or any framework.
It is just a pattern that we like to follow as software engineers.
Anytime we are storing information in Redis.
Those same thing with DC realized, but it works in the opposite direction.
Whenever we pull information not 100% on time, but very often when we pull information out of Redis,
we are going to run it through a serialize function.
It's going to take the object that gets returned from Redis.
So pretty much that thing right there.
And it's going to do things like say add in the ID that might turn any numbers from strings back into
true numbers and it might take a encoded deep value and turn it back into a date object.
Okay.
So that's serialize and serialize.
The serialize is whenever we are trying to put information into red as DC relies is when we want to
get information out.
And I'm saying here that serialize might remove the ID, it might turn a date into a better format.
Those are just examples.
It's not 100% of the time.
There might be scenarios where you do want to store an ID inside of a house.
There might be other examples where you just want to allow a date to behave as it is and not do any
special formatting around it.
Same thing with DC serialize as well.
Do you realize in D.C. your lives are just patterns that we often use to make sure that the information
going into and coming out of retests are always consistent and in the format that we truly expect.
So how does that relate back here?
Well, we are essentially doing the serialization step right here in line, just not really using a
separate function.
That's all that's really going on.
So we're going to take a quick pause right here.
When we come back, the next video we're going to write out an extremely simple serialize function.
The serialize function will take in that address argument and it's going to return basically exactly
that same object.
Right now, our serialized function that we're going to implement, it's not really doing anything whatsoever,
nothing special.
We are just setting ourselves up so that in the future, if we decide that there's any additional special
stuff we want to do around the user as we save them, we can easily implement that inside of our serialize
function.
All right.
So long video.
I apologize, but hopefully we got a better idea of what's going on with these two functions.