Let's create a serialize function back inside of our users file.
So at the very bottom I'm going to create a new function called Serialize.
This is going to receive a single argument, which I would call user and it's going to be of type read
user adders.
And then from this function we will return a plain object that has exactly the properties we want to
save into this in exactly the format that we want.
But once again, in this case, the serialize function is going to be very plain and very boring.
And it doesn't really do a whole lot in general, but that should be a user right there.
But on future serialize functions, it's going to be a lot more complicated and we're going to be removing
more properties and making sure that other properties are once again correctly formatted.
All right, now that we've got your lives put together, I'm going to go back up to the H set operation
right here.
I'm going to remove the plain object we are passing in and replace it with serialize adders.
Like so.
And that's it.
Okay.
So now we've got great user put together.
We're going to come back in just a moment and put together or get user buy ID.