Next up, let's work on our git user buy ID function.
So inside this function.
I'm going to use the as clients and I want to reach into Redis and get a hash in all the keys and value
stored in that hash.
You might recall that we learned about a command a little bit ago that allows us to retrieve an entire
hash is called H get all.
So that's the function we're going to use here.
H gets all.
And then the argument to this command is going to be the key that we want to retrieve out of Redis.
We've got our users key function that we use to generate the key of the user we are looking for.
So I'm going to put that in right here as well.
In passing the idea the user that I'm looking for.
That will give us back our user.
Now before we just return our user, we really need to think about what this object is right here and
what properties it contains.
So remember, we are storing a user inside of us and our user is a hash that has a username and password
and nothing else.
Now, when we send this hash back over to our application, we end up with an object with the exact
same properties.
So it has just a username and password.
But remember one reason that we used serialize functions when we passed this object around our app.
It's very common for us to want to also know the idea of this person.
So we might want to know that this is the user with ID.
One, two, three.
There might be many parts of our application that require that piece of info.
But right now, what we got out of practice doesn't have the ID.
So we are going to build a d serialize function.
DC realized function is going to take the hash that we just got out of Redis and the idea of the user
that we just retrieve, that's going to return a new object that has all three properties put together
in one single object.
Let's go back over.
At the very bottom of this file, I'm going to create a d serialize function.
So this will take arguments of an ID that is a string.
And then a user.
And this is going to have a little bit of a complicated type annotation.
I'm going to put in some curly braces right there.
And then a square brackets will say key string, string like.
So I pretty much just means we have a plain JavaScript object that has a couple of keys and the values
are all strings.
Then inside of here, I'm going to return an object.
And this is going to be our nicely formatted object that has all the properties with the appropriate
types of values.
So I want this object that we're going to pass around our entire application to have the idea, the
user username and the password.
I'll say ID.
My username will be user account username.
And my password is user password.
And we can condense this just a little bit down to I'd like so because the key and the value are the
same.
All right.
So now we can make use of DC realized up inside of our get function.
Go back up here at git user buy id.
I'm going to ask as in the user that we just fetched into it d serialize.
And you notice I'm getting an air here.
I did not provide the ID.
There we go.
That's better.
Okay.
Well, this looks good.
So we've now got our get user buy ID and our creat user functions put together.
Now we're not going to work on git user by username just yet.
And you might be kind of curious when we would even use that function.
I'll explain why we're using it at all or why it exists.
In just a moment, when we start to talk about our authentication system.