We are all done with our get user buy ID and create user functions.
We have not yet put together git user by username.
I'm going to tell you why that is in just a little bit.
In this video right now, I'm going to find my queries directory and then inside there find the sessions
dot yes file.
So the next piece of information they were going to store in Redis is around sessions.
Sessions are tied to the authentication system or this app.
In this video, I'm going to give you a description of what these sessions are all about.
If you're already familiar with sessions in general, with web applications, you can skip over this
video and just move to the next one.
Okay.
So quick couple diagrams to understand what sessions are all about.
So in this diagram, we're going to go over the flow of signing up and specifically sign up, not signing
in, but signing up to our application.
So a user in their browser is going to fill out a form and enter in a username and password.
They'll then send off a request to our API.
Now internally.
Firstly, it's going to happen.
We're going to take the username and password that the user just provided and store that in a new hash
inside of Redis.
That is what we just did two videos ago when we implemented the create user function.
So inside of create user, we generate a random ID.
We then store a hash containing the username and password at a key of something like users account and
then the randomly generated ID.
That stuff is all taken care of.
Now, after that step, after we read the user, a couple of things go on behind the scenes and you're
not really going to see the code around a lot of the stuff because it's code that I already wrote for
us as a part of the starter point or the boilerplate this application.
But what goes on behind the scenes?
First step.
After signing someone up, we are now considering this person to be logged in or authenticated with
our application.
You consider someone to be logged in?
We're going to create something called a session tied to this person to create a session.
We're going to make something called a session token.
And then inside of Redis, we're going to store some information about this person who we now consider
to be logged in.
So in this case, I might generate a random session token of 551.
And then here's what you and I need to do.
We need to store another little piece of information in addition to this original user account up here
that says that there is a session with an ID of five five, one.
And tied to that session.
It is going to be a user ID and a username.
Now kind of mysterious what's going on there?
Well, here's the last important part.
Here's what's really tying everything together.
After we stored this little bit of information, we're then going to send that session token back to
the browser.
That number of five, five, one, we're going to tell the browser that if it ever makes an additional
request for application, it needs to include that session token, that very special, very unique identifier
right there.
And that's going to allow our API to understand who is making requests to our app.
So let's kind of examine that part of the flow in more detail.
All right.
Let's imagine that later on, someone is attempting to create a new item to sell it.
So someone might make a request.
Once again.
And the request might have some details about the item they're trying to sell, and they might also
provide that session token of five, five, one.
So our APIs can receive that request and understand someone is trying to make an item.
And as you can imagine, we are only going to allow people to sell items if they are authenticated or
signed in to our application.
The first thing we have to do here is make sure that the person making this request is signed in.
To verify that this person is signed in.
We're going to take a look at the session token that is included inside that request.
And remember, it was an identifier, five, five, one.
But make sure this person actually is signed in.
Then we're going to take a look inside of house and see if there is a stored session with that particular
identifier.
We're going to go back and look at us.
We're going to look up a key of sessions found by five one, and we're going to find this hash stored
there.
That means that, yeah, this person is signed in, and right away we have some information about this
person.
We know their user ID, and we also know their username right away.
So we can make use of that information to create the item or do whatever else it is that we need to
do it inside our application.
That's it.
That's the purpose of the session.
It allows us to implement our entire authentication system and understand who is making requests to
our application over time.
Now, lastly, I want to mention very quickly.
Is the fact that all this stuff that I just mentioned was really around the sign up low.
And you might recall that just a moment ago I said, Oh, yeah, don't worry about that.
User by username function just yet.
But here's one of the first really awkward things we're going to see inside of Redis.
I want to think about what occurs whenever we go through the sign inflow.
So whenever someone tries to sign in, they're going to make a request to her application, including
a username and a password that they are trying to sign in ads and inside of our API.
The first thing we probably need to do is find a user who is saved inside of Redis with that given username.
But there's a big problem right now that we have inside our application.
Right now we are storing all these user records as hashes, and Redis doesn't have any good built in
way where we can very easily run a query over all of our different hashes and find a hash with a particular
key value pair.
The only way that we can access hashes right now are through these top level keys, like this one right
here that says users.
One, two, three.
So in other words.
If someone tries to sign in with a username of user seven, that's the only thing we know about this
incoming request.
At this point in time, we only know the username.
We have no idea what the ID is of the person with the username of user seven.
We have no way whatsoever to somehow reach into Redis and find this record so we can figure out if the
user entered the correct password or not.
This is a huge deficiency and it's something we're going to have to solve eventually.
We're going to solve it by adding in another data structure to relate all of our different usernames
to user IDs, which will allow us to take that username of User seven and eventually figure out what
the ID is of that person and eventually use that ID to pull this hash out of Reddit's.
All that stuff is not super relevant right now.
The only reason I'm mentioning it is that we're not going to worry about a little bit of sign and stuff
just yet until we start to introduce some data structures later on that are going to allow us to do
this additional kind of look up step.
Okay.
So now that we understand a little bit more about Sessions, let's start to implement get session and
save session in just a moment.