Another section, another data type.
So in this section, we're going to be focusing on lists in this diagram up here at the very top, I've
got an example of a list.
So this is storing a collection of different strings in some very particular order.
In this example in particular, I've got the temperature recorded at, say, some weather station once
per day.
And so moving from left to right, I've got the newest records on the right hand side and the oldest
records on the left hand side.
It's on the far right right here.
I might have today's temperature than the element right before it is.
Maybe yesterday's the day before it's the day before it.
The day before it and so on.
Now, as soon as you learn about this, you might start to think that they're really useful and just
fantastic.
But there are a couple of very big downsides to lists specifically around their performance.
If you use them in an incorrect way, in a later section, we're going to be discussing a lot of performance
characteristics of Redis, which we haven't really done just yet.
So I will tell you exactly why in great detail why you don't want to very often use lists, but just
understand right now that in general you often less you frequently do not want to use lists, even though
you might think you might want to use one.
And that'll make a lot more sense as soon as we start to go over their performance characteristics.
Couple other quick notes on lists right now.
So in general, just use your store and ordered list of strengths.
Very important for you to understand.
These are not arrays.
Not arrays.
They don't follow typical array implementations.
Instead, behind the scenes, they are implemented as a doubly linked list that has big impacts on their
performance.
And again, we'll discuss that later on.
The most common use case of lists that I find are for time series data.
So any time where I'm adding on new elements over time to the very end of the list.
And that's why in this particular example, I chose to use temperature being recorded once per day.
For this list, if I imagined implementing it inside of a real application, I would only be adding
on elements to the very end over time.
And lists are very good for that.
They're very good whenever we are trying to add on elements.
So the very end or it's the very start, it's when we start to try to iterate over all the elements
or whenever we start to try to access elements at the very middle of the list that we start to run into
trouble.
Lastly, I want to mention red list right now.
There are a couple of commands around them that are not very often used these days.
Lists used to be used to implement a couple of other very important features in red.
That was many, many years ago.
And these days, redesigns added in new structures and new commands that made some of these obsolete
list commands a little bit less useful.
So I will point out some of these less useful commands that I don't think you're going to use just because,
again, there's better ways of doing some of these particular operations in red is.
Now, having said that, let's take a pause right here and start to dive into a couple of commands around
lists in just a moment.