Let's take a look at some different commands around handling lists.
I've taken all the different commands for lists, and I've broken them up into three categories.
So we've got a couple for getting information out of the list.
We've got many different commands for adding or moving or updating data.
And then we've got a couple, like I mentioned at the end, the last video that used to be used for
implementing some important features around Redis.
But now there are some better ways of doing the same exact thing.
And we are going to learn what those better ways are in a later section.
So don't worry.
You know, we're skipping over these things.
We're going to figure out better ways of doing pretty much the same thing these commands do.
And we're going to use less fort breaking is a more ideal structure.
All right, let's get started.
I've already created a notebook back over here on our iCloud for lists.
First, two commands are going to take a look at are exact opposites of each other.
One is going to be used to add in elements to the left hand side of the list.
The other is used to add in elements to the right hand side.
So both these commands pretty straightforward.
Add in an element to the left hand side of a list stored at, say, stamps, and this would add in the
value 20.
So if I ran l push on a list that looked like this, I would add in a brand new element at the very
start over here on the left.
If I did an R push, I would add in a new element on the right, and that's pretty much it.
Let's test out these two commands very quickly.
I can do an el push temps 25.
And I'm going to get back a number.
That number is going to tell me the number of elements that are now stored inside the list.
If I just add in the very first element of this list.
So there's now one element in there.
I'll add in another code.
So.
With an R push temps about 27.
And now I've got two elements in there and that's pretty much it.
So pretty easy to add in elements to either side of the list.
Now, once we've got some elements in there, naturally we want to get them out or get some information
about the list in general.
So we've got two different commands for reading information out.
There's one other that we will or two others that we will take a look at in just a moment.
But these are two the more basic ones.
So l.n or list length gives us the number of elements in a list, and l index is used to get the value
stored at a particular index.
Let's try those out as well.
If I do a l.n temps.
There we go two elements in it and I could do an index temps and it is zero indexed so if I put in a
zero I'm going to get the very first element which for us is 25.
I do a one, I'll get 27.
So that's the second element.
We can also put in the negative values here to go to the very end of the list.
So if I put in a negative one, that means go negative one, go all the way to the very end of the index
or the very end of the list, and give me whatever is stored there.
In our case right now, our list contains 25 and then 27.
So a negative one means go to that last element of 27.
And sure enough, that's what I get.
I could put in even more negative numbers, which means go further back from the end a list.
That's negative one.
That would be negative two.
So I get 25.
All right.
So in general, these commands definitely not too bad compared to some others that we've seen.
Got Elle push our push Ellen and L index.
Every other command we're going to look at is going to be pretty predictable in nature.
They're all just about accessing elements inside of a list, which, as you can guess, can only be
so complicated.
Let's move on and start to burn through these other commands in just a moment.