Let's take a look at two more commands.
First of all, is going to be l'orange.
This is going to give us a range of elements coming out of a list.
Again, pretty simple in nature as a very quick test.
I'm going to go back over adding a new code cell.
And then as we start to run commands inside of this notebook, we're going to be adding and removing
elements quite a bit.
So at the very start of this command, I'm going to delete the temp list we had already created.
Or do we call it temps?
Temps.
And I'm going to add in a couple of values immediately in the cell.
So we always know that we're working with clean data.
So I will do a R push temps of how about 25?
Copy that down a couple of times.
I'll do a 27, another 25.
A 30.
And a 24.
Now try using the command.
We're just looking at L range.
I can look at my temps list and I'm going to add all the elements starting at index zero and going up
to and including three.
So that would give me back four elements total.
I'll do a L range.
0 to 3.
And there's my four elements.
So first four on the list.
Naturally, if I wanted to, I could start at index one instead.
That would give me everything from 27, 25, 30.
Brought to for.
We can go out of bounds.
And that's totally fine.
We can also make use of negative numbers as well.
So if I did everything from 0 to -1, that means start right here, start the very first element and
go all the way to the very last element that will give me the entire list.
If I did a negative two, that would be start at zero and then go all the way up to the second to last
element, which in this case would be 30.
I'll get 25, 27, 25, 30.
And that's it.
All right.
So again, not too bad.
Let's move on to a little bit more challenging command.
Now, it's not challenging in what it does, but is just challenging to understand a couple of different
options you can provide to it.
The command is L ports.
This is essentially a query or a search.
So we're going to provide a value in this case that we are looking for inside the list.
L paths will tell us where that element or the index of that element if it does exist inside the list.
So the most basic implementation, this command is just what you see up here.
Not that bad.
Like I said, it's once you start adding these arguments that things get a little bit more strange.
So let's try the base version of L parse.
All right.
I'm going to do a little pause on temps and let's try looking for the value about 27.
So it's at index one.
I can do an l odds of 30, albeit index three right there.
And if I do at 24, I would get index or.
If I try to look for a value that does not exist, I'll get back.
Not.
All right.
And yet again, just like I said, basic version.
Not too bad.
Let's now start looking at some of these different arguments we can provide.
The first is rank.
So in a list, there's no guarantee of uniqueness.
So the El Lpas, we might want to find multiple copies or skip over some copy of a value.
We can use rank or count to do.
Rank is used to say ignore say the first or the second or the third instance of the value we're looking
for.
And give me the fourth instead.
So if I do a rank two, that means ignore the first instance of 25 and instead find the second instance.
We could try that out.
We do have 25 in here twice.
So if I do El Paso temps 25, I'll get zero.
That's the first one.
But if I do a rank two, that means find the second instance.
That one is at index two.
Naturally, if I do a rank of three, there's no third instance of 25 in my list.
So I get null in that case.
In addition to rank, you also have counts.
So Count is going to give us back a array of indexes.
So count two means find two instances of the value 25.
I'm going to add in a new code cell for this one, just so I have an example of rank by itself.
I'll do a l pause.
Temps.
25.
I want to find two copies of 25.
Tell me where those indexes are.
They're at zero and two.
If we put in a three right here, we are not able to find three instances, so we're just gonna be told
about the first two that were actually found.
All right.
Final variation is max length.
In some cases, we might have a list with many, many, many elements in it.
So hundreds of thousands or even potentially millions.
And in many of these cases, you might not want to run El Paso and try to look up some value that is
way deeply stored inside that list, because it would just take a lot of time and a lot of performance.
So we can limit how deeply we search the list with Max.
Len We did a max line of ten.
That means only take a look at the first ten elements or of course the first 5/1 thousand or whatever
you might want to limit this thing to.
We're not going to do an example of Max Len because very simple of a you can guess how would work.
All right.
So once again, as I mentioned a couple of times, these commands are not so bad.
They're definitely not the worst.
It's just understanding all the very small variations and the sheer number of them that gets a little
bit confusing.
Let's take a look at some more commands around adding, removing and updating data in the next video.