Two more pretty simple commands to take a look at.
First is l l pop is going to remove an element from the left hand side or the start of a list.
If we just call L pop with a key and the very first element alone will be removed.
Optionally, we can also provide a number if you put in a number than the first.
However, many elements will be removed.
Let me do l pop tends to.
That's when to remove the first two elements.
Our pop is the exact opposite.
It's going to remove some elements from the right hand side or the end of the list.
Once again, if you don't provide a number, only the last element will be removed.
Otherwise, you could put in a number and remove that many elements.
All right.
Quick example.
Let's go back over here.
I'm going to scroll up a little bit to the cell where we created a couple of different temperatures.
I'm going to copy all those.
So from the Dell to the end of the R push.
Well, then go down to the bottom.
Is that in?
I'll then do a L pop on temps.
That's going to remove 25.
And then I will do an L index temps on zero and that will print out the value stored at the first index.
So if we remove 25, we should have 27 at the first index.
All right, so I'll run this and sure enough, I get 27.
If I do an L pop temps two, that's going to move 25 and 27.
So I should see 25.
And if I do a three, obviously that's going to take the first three and so I'll get 30 instead.
All right.
Quick example of the exact opposite.
So I will do an R pop tempts with no number seller removed 24 and then to get the element at the very
end.
Lowest I can do a negative one.
So I should see now 30 once again.
Yep.
There we go.
If I take off the last two elements and then take a look at the last element I should see.
25.
Yeah.
Just all pretty straightforward stuff.
Okay.
Two other commands that are a little bit more involved ever so slightly.
First one is all set.
So this allows us to go to a very particular index and change the value stored there.
So l set temps to means go to index to and update whatever value is currently stored there to 32 instead.
I'll add in a code cell.
I'm going to copy the DEL and R pushes down once again.
Well then do an L set.
En temps.
Let's try updating.
How about the very first elements?
And I'll update it to you.
How about, I don't know, 25 or 35?
There we go.
And I'll do an index.
Zero.
There's been attempts on zero.
So give me what are the first element is.
We get 35.
We can also set the very last element by putting in a negative index right there.
So a negative one needs go to the very last element, set it to 35.
Also update the index right here to negative one to get the very last element once again, to get 35.
Again, not the worst thing in the world.
Okay.
Last command for right now is l trim.
So this allows us to select a range of elements and we delete everything outside of that range.
So naturally, we want to be really careful, careful with L trim because we could very easily destroy
quite a good bit of data.
L trim temps to five means go and take a look at the list stored at temps starting at two and then ending
at and including five.
Keep those elements and delete everything else.
All right, I'll take Del down to the R pushes once again.
He sit down here?
Now let's do an l trim en temps and let's try starting at index one and then we'll include two and three
and delete everything else.
So one and three.
And then after that, let's print out EL Index on temps at zero and we should see 27.
Very good.
And if we look at the last elements after the update should be three.
Okay.
That's pretty much it for the more basic commands.
The ones that are now going to move into starting in the next video, start to get just a little bit
more complex, mostly because there are a different variation of arguments we can provide to them.
But still, they're not the worst thing in the world.
Only a couple more to go through, so it should be pretty quick.