Last two commands.
First one is l insert as the name of the command implies.
We use this to insert a new value into our list.
But rather than adding in a new value to the far left or the far right hand sides, it allows us to
look for an existing element and then add in a new value right before it or right after it.
Without a doubt.
See an example.
This is the best way to understand inserts.
So let's go back over to Arbor.
All right.
Back over here yet again.
Another new cell.
I'm going to copy the Dell and R pushes from above.
Now let's say that we want to add in a new element right before 30.
So I want to have 25, 27, 25, and then a new value right here, something like 15 and then 30 to
do so.
We would write out l inserts.
Temps.
Well then say before the value of 30.
Insert a new value of 15.
So that would be at index 0123.
So to make sure that it works correctly, I would then do a L index of temps at index three.
Turn out to get 15.
Just to double check that I'll do an R person.
The L range on temps and let's go from 0 to -1.
Now we get 25, 27, 25, the new value of 15 right there and then the rest of the list.
One very small alteration on this command will be to put in after instead of before.
So if I do after, as you guess, that means go and find the value 30 and then put in the new value
right after it or one that I get 25, 3015 now and then the 24.
Last command for right now around this.
This one is the most complicated, but it's still really not that bad.
El Ram allows us to remove some elements from a list.
So the big kind of variation here is this second argument that we put in.
That's the kind of complicated parts may show you a couple diagrams to help you understand what's going
on with it.
So if I do a l rem temps and then negative two, here's what the negative two is really saying.
The fact that it is negative.
So negative two specifically means starting at the right hand side, move over to the left.
So starting right here, go back to the left and try to find and remove two copies of 25, specifically
25, because that's the value we put in right there.
So we would start at 24.
Go to the left.
There's a 25.
We're going to remove one and then keep going until remove a second copy.
And we'd remove that one right there.
If we put in a positive value, that means starting at the left hand side and going to the right.
Remove one copy of 25, though, in this case, right here at the very first element is 25.
So I would remove it and that's it.
I remove the one copy.
I don't need to remove anything else.
And then finally lrm temps of zero means just plain remove all copies of 25.
So we would dump photos.
Okay.
Last quick example.
So once again, Dell, our push is you get the idea.
We've done that many times now.
So I'll throw those in.
And then do a LRM on temps.
Let's start off with a how about a zero and 25?
So that would remove the 25 right there and 25 right there.
And then I will do an L range on temps from 0 to -1.
So I just took off all instances of 25.
If I put in a one, I mean, starting at the left hand side or the start removed the first copy of 25,
but leave all others.
So I would now remove that first copy and still leave the 25 in the middle.
And then finally, if I put in a negative, I mean, starting at the very end and going up.
Or alternatively, starting at the right hand side and going to the left.
So I remove the 25 right here and there we go.
Okay.
So that's it list again.
These commands are really just tedious more than anything else, and I apologize for what has probably
been a rather boring stretch of videos because these are just not super interesting.
This is another one of those areas where reticence giving you a lot of an A basic operations and it's
up to you to figure out interesting use cases for each of these because as you just look at these things,
you might be sitting there saying, where would I ever use this in practicality?
Well, you have to be a little bit clever and think of some interesting way of making use of it.
So having said that, we are naturally going to make use of lists inside of our application.
Let's start to take a look at some use cases around lists and how we're going to use them inside of
our app in the next video.