Let's take a look at a couple of scenarios where we would want to use a list data structure.
Remember, in general, you probably don't want to use a list as often as you might think.
There are many scenarios where a sorted set is probably more ideal, but certainly there are some scenarios
where you would want to use a list.
Those would be any time that you have any append only or prepared only data.
So if it turns out that you just keep on adding in additional readings over time or additional records
over time to some set of records, well, that might be a good use case for a list.
And examples of that might be, as I showed in last couple of diagrams, temperature readings or maybe
stock quotes, financial quotes or something like that.
Anything where we just keep on adding in additional data non-stop over time.
Another good use case is any time that we need to only fetch the last or first couple records of some
collection of records.
Examples of this might be if we are trying to show social media posts and we only want to see the latest
five posts from someone.
We could store the IDs of those posts inside of a list, and then whenever we want to find the last
five, we can use a very simple l range and always be guaranteed that we're going to find the last five
posts by that person.
Naturally, we could also use a sorted set for this very easily by storing each member or storing the
post IDs as members, and then the timestamp when they were created as the scores for each.
So definitely could use a sorted set there as well.
And then finally, any time that we have a collection of records where there is no real sort order to
the data outside of the order in which we are inserting it.
And again, an example that would be social media posts.
We want to show the last five or the most recent five posts.
The order in which we add those posts into a list is really the only order we care about around those
posts.
Now, just as importantly has understanding use cases of when you should use one.
You also need to know when you shouldn't use a list.
Probably.
Now, little caveat here.
If you've only got a list of, say, ten items or even 100 items, you can basically do whatever you
want.
You do not have so many records where you have to worry about performance.
We are really talking about when you might have thousands or tens of thousands of records.
So if you have many records in a list, then you probably do not want to use a list at all.
Any time that you need to apply some filtering criteria to the elements in the list, you might have
noticed that in all the commands we looked at, there was no filter command.
There was no ability for us to go through each element in red itself and specifically say, Give me
all the elements that are greater than or less than or equal to something.
We can't do an equal to you.
Let me be precise here.
There is a command for that.
We can't do a greater than or less than.
Another scenario in which we probably don't want to use a list is any time our data is sorted by some
attribute other than time or insertion order.
So if we are trying to sort by say alphabetical order, that would be really challenging to do with
a list.
All right.
So now a couple of little tips and some scenarios where you might run into where you could definitely
use a list.
All right.
So the first example we're going to take a look at is if we were building a book reviewing platform,
effectively, this is kind of like the same thing as if we were doing a social media network, so we
might have a list of reviews.
So reviews are being created for different books.
Over time.
We might store the idea of all these different books or these reviews inside of a list, and we might
just keep on appending onto the very end to list each new review as it is created.
So this right here, one is the idea of some review and here is the hash representing the view, the
review right here.
And then two is a review that was created just a little bit ago.
And so here's the hash representing it.
So one thing we might need to do on this book reviewing platform is get the titles of the two most recently
reviewed books.
So in other words, get A1 and B2 right here, find the respective hashes for each and then get the
title property of each one.
We could definitely do this in two separate commands.
We could do a L range to get the last two elements and then two separate H get alls, or just simply
each gets to get the title using both those IDs.
But one other thing we could do is you get all the data we need, but just one single command is to
use sorts, you might recall going over sort a little bit ago.
So let's go through this example and how we would solve this using the sort command to merge data from
multiple different locations in the exact same way that we did with sorted sets a while ago.
All right, back over to our booked cloud.
I'm going to create just an A1 and a B2 hash, and then I'll create the reviews list and just put in
A1 and B2 and we'll try to get the titles of those two books.
So inside of your.
Because I might run this code cell a couple of times.
I'm going to delete the review key.
I'll then do an R push into reviews of B to.
And A1.
So that's going to give me a list just like this right here, but without those additional elements
in it.
I'll then create two different structs.
So books a one with the title of say good book.
The title of bad book.
Oh, that should be, too.
There we go.
Now we've got all of our data and now to join these two records together, I guess three records, the
list and the two hashes.
We could do a sorts on reviews.
We want to specify the sorting criteria because we don't want to apply any additional sorting.
This data in the list is already sorted.
It's sorted in the order of which review was added first.
So to tell the sort command to not apply any additional sorting.
I'm going to put in some key here that just does not exist.
And once again, a very common convention is to just put in no sort.
We can then specify what data we want to get out.
So my template here will be books.
Colin Starr era title.
So this effectively means no end on all the different elements inside the list.
And then just as we saw with sorted sets, iterate through each member one by one.
So take that number right there.
A one.
Inserted into the template that we provided for gets that's going to result in book's colon A1 that's
going to point at a hash and then arrow title means go into the title or go into the hash, find the
title property and give us whatever string is there.
And that's what should be reported in the output output results set.
So if I run that, sure enough, I get that book and good book.
Okay.
So that is once again use case of the list command where we just want to show the most recent something
in our application.
But one other quick tip I want to give you.
You might be looking at lists and saying, gee, it sure is not very useful to only be able to store
a simple string here or essentially a simple number.
Naturally, we can get around this really, really easily.
Let's take the same example we were looking at a little bit ago of temperature records.
Last time I showed you this diagram, I said, Oh, yeah, these are going to be temperature records
from today, yesterday, two days ago, three days ago, and so on.
So presumably there's like 24 hours exactly between each of these different records.
Let's imagine for a second that we are getting this data on a very inconsistent schedule.
So maybe today we got this temperature data at 4 a.m..
And yesterday we got the temperature data at 8 a.m. and then before that we got it at 11 a.m..
You get the idea.
So there's a variable amount of time between each of these different records, and we might want to
record exactly when this temperature data was taken.
We could obviously use a sorted set here instead where all the members are, the temperatures and the
actual scores would be maybe a timestamp of when the record was collected or the recording was collected.
But another way we could do this is by using a list and just storing a little bit more clever value
in here.
So we might do something like this.
Now, first glance, it looks really nasty, but let me just show you exactly what's going on here.
I've encoded inside of each of these values which are being stored as strings.
A little bit of a schema of sorts.
So I'm saying that I want to restore the temperature that was recorded and then a colon, which is just
a random specify a random separator here.
I could have just as well done a space where a dot or a dash or slash whatever I want to use just some
separator.
And then right after that, I could put in, say, a UNIX timestamp.
So now for each of these different records, I know exactly the temperature.
Was recorded and the time at which this temperature was recorded.
So I've got all these records there, all sorted in the correct time, and I know a lot more information
about each one.
And actually, we could expand this quite a bit more so I could do temperature and then time stamp and
then another colon and maybe a location after that.
So this was the temperature in New York or something.
The sky's the limit here.
You can stuff just about as much info in here as you wish.
If you want to put in more data into your list.
The only downside to this is that we start to lose the ability to join this data with any other key
insider application.
So now if we wanted to somehow join this data with the hash, we would have to have a hash with a key
of something like 25 colon timestamp poll in New York.
And maybe you do have a key like that.
Maybe you don't.
But just keep that in mind.
All right.
So that is enough around some use cases here.
So last thing we're going to do is go back over to our e-commerce application and actually make use
of lists.
We've got one more feature we need to build out using them.
So let's get started in just a moment.