Let's take a look at where we might use a list on our e-commerce application.
I'm on the main landing page right now.
I'm going to scroll down to the most viewed section and then just click on any item on here.
Then once on this page, I'll scroll down a little bit to the bid history section.
So this is intended to be a chart displaying what the current bid is and how it is changing over time.
So the vertical axis is supposed to be the amount of money that has been bid on this product.
And then from left to right, going in the right direction, we should see time increasing.
So we should see newer bids over here on the far right hand side.
Because we are trying to show pretty much one single value here and we're just appending on new values
to the far right hand side over time.
This is probably a good use case for a list, so we'll use a list to store our history of bids and then
display them on this chart.
As a reminder, we haven't really dealt with BET bids at all inside of our application just yet, so
we do have to come back and have a larger discussion around bids and how they're going to be used in
our app.
Right now we are only going to focus on implementing the bid history parts.
All right.
So back inside, my editor.
I want to find these services.
Queries, bids, dots, file.
In here, you're going to notice that there are two functions, one called create bid, and another
is get bid history.
Inside of Create bid, we're eventually going to have a ton of logic.
So not just the speed history stuff.
We're going to have a lot of other stuff going on around Pids notably to handle some concurrency issues
that we're going to discuss a little bit later on.
But right now, again, we're just going to worry about creating a record saying some amount of money
was bid at this particular time.
Then our second function here get bit history is where we are going to naturally try to get some data
out of Redis.
Get our list of bids.
And how is Japan changing over time?
So how are we going to actually store the bids?
Well, for every item, we're going to have a separate list.
We're going to store these at History Pounds and then the idea of the item.
So in this case, the item ID is A1.
Then in our list, we're going to use the same kind of structure or kind of serialization that I mentioned
a little bit ago around storing temperatures.
So we're going to have the amount of money that was bid on this item and then a colon and then a UNIX
timestamp of when this bid was created.
So in one single record, we'll know the amount of money and we'll also know the time at which the bid
was created.
So over time, as more bids are added, we're going to add them onto the right hand side of the list.
So first $25, then 30, then 40 and so on.
Now as far as those two functions, we just looked at creep ID and get bit history again, creep ID
is going to eventually have a ton of logic in it.
But right now, just some stuff around inserting a new record into the list and then on Get It history.
Something that I really want to make sure is very clear.
This is a function that's going to return an array of objects.
So we need to go into Redis.
We need to take a look at the list or some particular item.
We need to pull out all that data.
We need to parse it and turn every one of those little number, colon number things into an object that
looks like this.
So I want to see the amount that was bid created out and created out.
Should have the UNIX timestamp right here.
I'm just abbreviating it as 1002 thousand.
So again, we need to have an array of objects.
Each object is going to have an amount and created out and we're going to go from the later earliest
bid.
That's I'm looking for.
So the oldest bid and then next element should be the next bid that was added, then the next bid and
so on.
All right.
So a lot of information here, but I just want make sure, again, it's super clear what's going on
because we're going to pretty quickly run into a interesting issue here.
So let's take a pause right here and start with the implementation in just a moment.