Let's get started on our implementation.
So to get started back inside my code editor, I'm going to find these services keys, dots file.
Inside of here.
We need to make a new key function that is going to point us to the list for any particular item.
So every item is going to have its own separate list of bits.
We need to make a function that will generate this key right here, given an items ID.
So at the very bottom, under the item section, I'm going to add an export consort.
Did history.
He.
This will be called with some item ID.
And then we're going to return a template string.
So as usual, back ticks, not single quotes we'll add in history.
Pound and the dollar sign.
Curly braces.
Item ID.
Back over inside of Bizkit's.
So this is as a quick reminder inside the services where each directory.
At the very top.
We'll add in a couple of different import.
I'm going to get the key function we just put together.
So that is it.
History.
He.
From Services Keys.
I'm going to get my read his clients.
Ron's services.
Rita.
And then we're also going to get something called the Date Time constructor from a library called Luxon.
You'll see why that is in just a moment.
Before we work on create bid and get bid history.
One quick reminder.
When we take these incoming bids that people are trying to add to an item, we need to extract the amount
of money that they are bidding and the Unix time stamp as well.
So when is this bid actually being created?
Now we're going to stored this inside of our list with these two values being separated by a colon.
So this is one big string right here, the amount colon and then the time.
So we need to write out a serialize and a serialize function.
These functions are going to be used to take a incoming bid and then turn it into a string that looks
like this.
That's going to be the serialized.
And then we need to have a matching de serialize function to take a string like this and turn it back
into something that tells us the amount of money that was bid and the time at which it was bid.
So remember, an object that looks like this right here needs to take that string and generate an object
that looks like a mount and accreted out with the date time.
So let's first begin by creating that serialize and serialize function.
All right, so back over here at the very bottom.
I'm going to give these things very explicit names because we're not really working with bids here.
We're working with a history of bids.
So I'm going to call it serialized history as opposed to just plain serialized.
Then as arguments, we're going to receive the amount of money that is being bid and created at time,
which we will receive as a number.
So again, UNIX time milliseconds.
Then the serialization is can be very simple or put in another template string with dollar sign curly
braces.
First the amounts.
Then a colon.
And then the accreted value.
Once again, just as a reminder, we don't have to use a colon here.
We could just as well use a slash a dash.
8% doesn't make a difference.
I'm just choosing to use a colon as a separator.
Then we can make a matching d serialize function.
So I'll make another function called serialized history.
So this will take in these stored string value.
I'm calling the store.
It is whatever string we are getting out of our list.
So these individual strings are here.
That is going to be these stored value.
So we need to take that stored value.
We need to separate it into two separate elements based upon that column.
Once we do that separate separation, we then are going to have to separate strings.
One string is going to be the 25 right here.
So it's going to be a string.
Remember, we are always getting strings when they come out of Redis.
And then the second string we're going to get during that split operation is the number over here.
I say number, but it really is a string.
So we need to parse both these things into actual numbers and then once again put them into an object
that looks like that right there.
So I'm going to do a amount.
And created at.
That's going to come from stored.
Split on colon.
The square brackets over here are doing some deep structuring.
So just a little bit of a JavaScript thing.
When we do these stalks split, that will give us back an array of two strings.
So we're going to take the first value inside that array and assign it to Arial called Amount and then
take the second element in the array and assign it to another variable called read it out.
Once again, I want to remind you these are currently strings, so we do need to parse them into numbers.
All right.
So down here at the bottom, we're going to create that object that we need to return from this function.
So it's an object that looks like this right here.
The amount will be our float on amount.
I'm using parse float here because I'm assuming that I am allowing people to bid amounts of money that
are going to have a decimal component.
So maybe something like $1.05.
The passport will give us back a number with a decimal component on it.
And then the it at.
Is going to be date time.
From Millie's.
And we'll put in.
Pass it.
Of created apps.
So once again take created out, which is currently a string.
Turn it into an integer and then make a deep time object out of it.
And that's it.
We've now got the serialization and this realization put together.
Now, one more quick pause.
We'll take care of Creed bid and get bid history.