All right, let's work on create bit.
So create that is going to be called with an object called adders.
We can do a command click on created adders right here to see what properties that object will contain.
So we're going to be told the items, ID, the amount as a number and create it out as a daytime object.
So we're going to have to take those two values right there, pass them off to our serialize function.
That's going to give us back our serialized bid history, and then we're going to store that inside
of our list of bits.
So inside of your.
I'm going to do what we call it, serialized.
That's going to be serialized history.
The first arguments will be the amounts.
And then the second is going to be the date at which this bid was created as a plain number as opposed
to a date time object.
So that's going to be matters not created at that is a date object right there.
So we need to turn it into a play number and we do that with a dot to Millie's.
So there's our string in our very special format.
Now we need to store it inside of our list.
Our list is going to store all of the different bids over time.
So the oldest bids are going to be on the left hand side of the list, and all the newest bids are going
to be on the right hand side.
So we need to add in additional elements over here to the right hand side.
You might recall that you add in a new element just on the far right hand.
We can use the our push command.
So that's exactly what we're going to do here.
So I'm going to do return client, not our push.
I'm going to add it to the list stored at bid history key.
I'm going to put in the item ID that was just bid on and then the serialized bit.
And that's it.
Not let me do that format.
Just you can see the whole line.
Well, that's create bit.
So now we need to work on get bit history down here.
Now get it.
History is just a little bit more complicated.
For one very simple reason.
Whenever gifted history is called, we need to return an array of bid objects.
And once again, I know I've reviewed this so many times, but we need to return an array of objects
that each look like this.
The other thing to keep in mind is that this function is going to be called with a couple of different
arguments.
First, we're going to be told which item we're looking up the history for.
And then, very importantly, we are also being given an offset and a count.
So the thinking here is that an item might eventually have many, many, many bids, maybe a hundred
or even 1000 different bits.
And if we ever try to show the history of an item all the different bids it has received, we might
not want to show all thousand different bids at the same time.
Instead, we might only want to show the ten most recent bids.
Remember, that's a super common use case of a list to only show the most recent and number of something.
So the offset and the count right here are being used for pagination to allow us to show only the ten
most recent bits.
Now offset.
Just make sure it's super clear.
Means go to the very end of the list.
So the very end over here.
And then looking back to the left, skip over zero items.
So offset of zero means start at bid five right here and then a count of three really means.
Take the three most recent bits.
If we had an offset.
Of one.
And a count of three.
And that means go to the far right hand side.
Skip back one item.
And then take the three previous items before that.
So that would be offset of one with a count of three.
So skip the first one on the right hand side and then take the next three.
And as you can guess, if you had an offset of two.
That means skip the first two on the right hand side and take the next three.
So a little challenge that we're going to run into here very quickly.
We need to somehow take these offset values to offset and count and translate them into something that
we can actually use to retrieve information out of Redis.
Quick reminder, back over in our book.
As we were going over some different commands a little bit ago, we learned about a command called L'Orange.
And here it is right here.
So we can use EL Range whenever we want to retrieve a couple of different elements out of a list.
So it seems like El Range would be very appropriate for what we are currently trying to do.
The only issue is El Range works by receiving some indexes.
So if I do zero and one, that means take the first element and the second element, or I should say
the first element all the way up to the second element.
And give us just those two and let me do that again.
I got a little bit of a bug here.
It's not actually airing.
There we go.
That's better.
So take the first all the way up to the second element.
So I get the 25 and 27.
And then if I do something like say three, that means go all the way from zero up to the third index.
So zero, one, two, three, that's 30.
You get the idea.
We went over this in great detail.
The other functionality around L'Orange that we have, we can do everything from say zero up to negative
one.
And negative one means go to the very end element of the entire list.
But the point here, what I'm trying to say is that to get some number of elements out of a list, this
is really the one command we have.
And it works based on indexes.
But the arguments that were being given to our get bid history function are not indexes.
That's not what we're being given or being given an offset and a count.
So we need to somehow take this offset and count value and translate it into something that the Range
Command understands.
And that's where the challenge is.
So we need to somehow take these two values and use them to calculate exactly what index of values we
want to actually retrieve.
Okay.
So let's imagine how that would come together.
So this is the same diagram I'm going to write out some kind of equation right here on what we're really
trying to calculate.
Well, I think what we need is to do an L range.
It needs to be on the key of history account and then the item is sourced.
Imagine it's a one.
And then we are going to put in the start index of where we want to retreat from and then the end index.
Remember that as we start to go into negative indexes, that's going to give us elements going from
the right hand side back towards the left side of the words.
The far right hand side is always going to be negative one.
And then the second from the right hand side is negative two, negative three, negative four, negative
five and so on.
So if I wanted to get everything from it three, four and five, as indicated by offset of zero and
a count of three, what I would really need to put in here is go from index -3 to -1.
That's how I would get the last three elements and I can very easily verify that this would work.
If I go back over to our book very quickly, back in our book, if I did -3 to -1, that should give
me 25, 30 and 24.
And sure enough, it does.
Yes, that definitely works.
But like I said, we need to take the offset number and account and use them to generate or calculate
what negative indexes we actually want to access.
So here's how we can figure this out.
To calculate the ending index.
So this negative one right here to calculate what that should be based upon the offset in the count,
we're going to do a calculation of negative one minus offsets.
So if offset is zero.
Then that would go to zero and we'd end up with negative one, which is what we want.
If we had a.
Offset of, say, two.
And that would imply that we want to get those elements right there.
So our stopping point needs to be negative three.
Let's make sure that works as well.
So if I put in an offset of two.
We'd calculate negative three.
So it looks like that works as well.
That's how we're going to calculate the closing side of the index.
So now we need to calculate the opening side of the index.
To get the opening index or really the start, I should say that needs to be negative three.
In this case, we're going to do a calculation of negative one times the offset minus count.
So once again, we can test this out really quickly.
If the offset is zero.
And the count is three.
And we're going to end up with zero for that term right there.
Minus three.
We get negative three.
Yeah.
That definitely lines up.
And again, if we do.
Test of something like this.
So in this case, the offset would be two and the count is still three.
And this is negative one offset minus count.
So now we can substitute in these numbers and we're looking to we're trying to calculate negative five.
So if I put in the offset of two and a count of three, I'm going to end up with negative two minus
three, which is in fact, negative five.
That's it.
That's how we're going from a offset and account into some values that can actually truly be used by
L range.
This all might seem really complicated.
Totally understand.
But if you really kind of think through it, the only other way that we can avoid this complexity is
if we knew the entire length of the list.
But to get the length of the list, you have to run a separate command.
And ideally, we don't really want to have to run two separate commands.
We want to just run one command to get the last couple of elements out of our list.
Okay.
So we need to do a l range inside of get bit history and we need to put in indexes of these two equations
right here.
So let's get to it.
Back inside my editor.
At get get bit history.
I'm going to delete that return and then replace it with first our start index.
Which is going to be the equation we have right there.
So it's negative one times the offsets, minus the counts.
And then the end index.
Is going to be negative one minus the offset.
Now that we've calculated those two index values, we can use them to run our L range commands.
I'm going to get back a range with a weight.
Wyandotte L range.
I want to do my range on it.
History key at the item ID.
And then I want to get the range going from start index to end index.
Then when we get back our range.
So whatever values are coming out of that list member they are encoded strings.
They have been serialized, so we need to serialized them into plain objects.
So I'm going to return down here.
Range dot map.
I'm going to take a look at each bid that we are getting back.
And I know we're all going to end up with an error here from TypeScript until we find we'll deal with
it in a moment.
And then for every single bid that we got back, we're going to serialize it.
So serialize history and put in the bid and okay, the error went away.
Thank goodness for that.
All right.
That's it.
That's our get it history.
I know this took a lot of time, but the big challenge here, like I said, was taking the offset in
account and converting those values into something that the L Range Command would actually understand.
Let's save this.
And I think we're ready to do a quick test.
So to test this.
I'm going to go back over to an item that has been created.
Here's one right here.
And then going to place a bid about ten.
And it worked.
So I immediately see bid history be updated.
So initially there was $0.
Now we're up to $10.
And if I now put in another bid, say, of 12.
Very good.
14.
19.
60.
You get the idea.
Excellent.
Well, that was a lot of work, but we've got this chart put together and we know how the bid amount
is changing over time.
So this looks pretty good.