Up to this point in the course, we have focused on some pretty basic data types, such as sets, lists,
hashes and so on.
We've been able to make a pretty interesting application.
So the e-commerce app, it's not totally done, but it's definitely at least somewhat working.
So we can definitely make an interesting application by using these very basic data types.
But as we start to add in additional features, well, using some of these basic data types for implementing
things like, say, search starts to get a little bit more challenging.
So at a certain point in time, rather than trying to build advanced features using these basic data
types, we might try to instead enhance the capabilities of Redis itself.
We can make read this little bit more feature full.
We can add in additional capabilities to it by using something called modules.
Modules are separate programs that we're going to load into Redis.
When we load up a module, we are adding in some additional data structures and some commands to work
with those structures.
So it's plain and simple enhancing the capabilities of Redis.
It adds in more advanced features that we can make use of to build more advanced features ourselves.
There are many different modules out there, but two are the most popular and the two that we're going
to really focus on in this course are called registration and ready search.
Registration allows us to store and manipulate JSON very easily inside of Redis.
Remember, we already do have hashes, but hashes don't allow deeply nested data.
They are simple key value pairs.
With registration we can store true JSON data.
So nested arrays, nested objects and equivalent any kind of basically any kind of JSON structure we
want.
A second module they were going to make use of is called Ready Search.
This is going to add in true text search and true querying and filtering of different keys across our
entire register to store.
Whereas before we had to keep track of relational data or dual filters and queries by using either that
sort commands or sorted sets, we can now make use of ready search to take a look at a ton of different
hashes at the same time and find very specific hashes based upon some filtering criteria.
The registry site and research just plain make Redis little bit more useful and feature full.
Okay.
Now we're going to start to focus on how we actually make use of these modules in just a moment.