Let's start to take a look at text queries.
Once again, we write out a text query.
Using a set of parentheses so I can find the name of all cars that includes, say, fast.
Or old.
Or a car or whatever else.
As I've hinted out several times.
Understanding the syntax around these text queries can be a little bit challenging.
So in this video, I want to give you a kind of a high level overview on some of the easier to understand
topics.
Then we'll go into some deeper things in the next video.
Okay.
So when we are doing a text query, some important things to understand.
First is the actual query text in addition to the text that exists inside of your hash field as well,
is going to go through a little bit of a preprocessing step.
So all the different stop words are going to be removed.
Remember, stop words are like a or the and so on.
All spaces are going to be removed and all punctuation is removed as well.
So if we ever enter into a hash field or a text query, something like a fast, fast car, then it's
going to be actually processed or kind of reduced down.
We can imagine behind the scenes just something like this.
Just fast, fast and car.
Second thing to understand.
Is that reticence going to apply a technique called stimming to your queries?
This is where a complicated word that might have a prefix or a suffix on it are going to be reduced
down to a more common form of that word in whatever language you are using for your searching.
Understanding stimming is really easiest if we make use of a quick demo.
So I'm going to open up my browser and go to the link shown right here.
We're going to try entering a couple of terms and just understand how this stimming thing works.
All right.
So over in my browser.
Here's that page.
Now on the left hand side, I'm going to enter in some English word and then I'm going to be shown on
the right hand side.
The actual term that red is would be using whenever it does a search.
So if I enter in the word fast.
Gas is going to be used in the actual query.
If I put in fast Lee, even though that's not actually a word, the algorithm that this library uses
is still going to reduce that down to just the word fast.
So in theory, if I do a query right now on our for cars and I search for fast Lee, I should see the
car marked as fast car.
I'm going to try that really quickly.
So back over here.
I'll try doing fast.
Lee And sure enough, I do actually get a result.
Stemming some can sometimes give you unexpected results.
So for example, you might expect something like faster to reduce down to just fast.
Nope, not the case.
We get still just faster.
If I do it faster.
LI Which is once again not an actual word that is also reduced down to just faster.
So stimming is usually going to make all of your search terms a little bit more flexible in nature.
Users can add on a suffix to a word, and it's still going to match up with the more common non suffix
version of that word.
So in general, we do not want stimming inside of any given app.
Okay.
So now a couple of basic forms of syntax and we'll start going into the much more complicated stuff.
A lot of the different forms of these queries are very similar to what we saw around tags and numbers.
But one important exception, and that is if we put in just a plain string by itself as the query without
doing any ATS or anything like that, then already search is going to take that string right there and
use it to search over all the different fields marked as type text.
It was a quick example.
If we do just fast by itself, we're still going to get our fast car.
And of course, I can also do fast Lee and I get the result as well.
That's only true of text queries.
We cannot use this little shortcut with number or tag.
With that in mind, I really recommend you don't use this too much.
It's usually better to just be a little bit more explicit and say, I want to specifically search these
fields for the term fast.
If we ever put in multiple words into a query that is going to be interpreted as being an end statement.
So find me all the different cars with the name of Fast and Car.
We can split up these words with a height symbol once again, and that's interpreted as an author statement.
Now, one thing to note here is that this is not an either or.
It's not going to exclude any cars that have fast and a car in the word or in their name.
Quick example of that.
If we do an ad name fast or car, we're still going to see NASCAR in here.
So it's not an either or.
It's a give me all the cars with a name and or of asking me all the cars of the name of fast and or
car.
And then we can also use that same dash technique as an negation that we do minus at name fast.
Give us all the cars that do not include the term fast.
All right.
So that's the easy stuff, though.
Let's start to take a look at the more complicated things in just a moment.