Let's take a look at our first variation on text searching.
So one thing that a lot of users do when they are searching for some information is, of course, make
a typo.
So let's imagine a user is trying to search for a car, but they accidentally enter D.R. instead.
And well, of course, we're going to get back to your results.
But it sure would be nice if we could somehow figure out that the user might have meant to say car right
here.
But that's a technique we're going to cover in this video.
Okay.
So whenever we are trying to do some kind of fuzzy matching between what a user entered as a search
string and what they're actually looking for, we can make use of the percent sign.
The percent sign is not a wild card.
I want to clear that up right away.
So we do not make use of percent to do a wild card or anything like that.
Instead, the percent symbol is going to try to find the number of characters mismatch between what
a user typed in and what they actually were trying to search for.
Let's imagine a user meant to search for car, but they accidentally entered in D.R. instead.
In this case, there is a one character mismatch between these two strings.
So to account for that in the query, we can wrap this string right here with percents on either side.
A percent on either side, once again is not a wild card.
Instead, the percent means try to allow for a one character mismatch inside the string and any possible
results.
If I now run that, I will get back all the results that have car C.A.R. inside the name.
We can use the same technique if you're looking for, say, a string of fast.
So if the user was looking for fast, but they accidentally typed in gas instead.
There's a one character difference.
So that's going to match up with fast.
Yep.
There we go.
Percent that we add on on either side, as I mentioned, is only going to allow for one character mismatch.
If I enter in a second incorrect character here now I'm going to get back zero results.
But if we want to, we can add in additional percent signs.
So let's say that a user meant to look for car, but they actually typed in DJR.
In this case there is a two character mismatch.
So we can account for that by putting in an extra set of parentheses, not parentheses, but percent
signs.
On either side.
I'll put in the air.
Now there is a two character mismatch, and if I run that, I'm going to find all the cars with the
name of car.
We can go up to 3% signs on both sides.
That's going to allow for three characters of Mismatch.
Now, if I put in D a RR, that's three character mismatch against car.
So I'm still going to get back results.
But if I put in another character here.
About Da e.
Now I've got four character mismatch and so I'm going to get back zero results.
Okay.
So as you'd imagine, using this percent technique is really, really handy when we want to allow for
users to put in perhaps a small typo or two when they are actually searching for something and still
give them back some intelligent results.
We're going to take a look at one other technique similar to this in just a moment.