Last technique we're going to look at around text searches are prefix searches so we can use Star at
the end of a string to do a prefix search.
In other words, if we enter a star as our query, that will be automatically expanded to cover fast,
far fact, often fantastic and so on.
All words that begin with F and A.
There is one or two requirements around this you need to know.
First, at a minimum, we have to have two characters to do a prefix search so we cannot do F star or
just a star or B and so on.
It has to be a minimum of two characters.
We can add on additional characters if we want.
So we could go up to a fast star if we want.
Let's take a look at a couple of examples of this.
So back over here.
If I do a star, I would expect to match up against fast car.
And I did not get that.
Let me try.
Now and then the thing gets a bit wonky.
There we go.
Now I got fast car.
I can do something similar for a star that will get all the different cars.
There we go.
Could you hotel DA to matchup against old and so on.
You get the idea.
Okay.
So at this point, we have spoken a little bit around text.
So we've covered stemming we've covered a little bit around tokenisation and stop words.
We've also discussed the Levenstein Distance.
This is the kind of fuzzy search we discussed just a moment ago and prefixes.
So at this point in time, you might be thinking, Steven, you really over blow this stuff.
This is not as complicated as you said it would be.
This was not that bad.
But the real question here, the real complexity starts to come in.
Once we start to match in or kind of combine all these different techniques together, that's when things
start to get much more complicated.
It really comes down to how are we going to implement some of the stuff in code?
How are we going to actually take in some string from a user kind of search query and turn it into an
actual query that we can run with ready search.
That's where things really get challenging.
Let's start to focus on some general design patterns in just a moment.