We now understand some behind the scenes stuff around full text search.
So we know that stop words, spaces and punctuation are removed.
We understand that we can use the percent sign to do a fuzzy search and we can add in a star to do a
prefix search.
Now we need to use these different techniques and figure out how to use them on an actual search interface.
So remember users when they enter in some search criteria to a field like, say, when they're trying
to search for products or something similar, they're not going to enter in some stars or percent signs
or anything like that.
They're going to enter in some plain text.
And so the question is, how do we take this plain text and actually put it into some kind of query?
I'm going to give you some recommendations in this video.
The first thing to understand is that a search operation is really broken up into two steps.
The first step, which is kind of optional, is to show an auto complete list of options to a user.
So if a user adds in F a, we might want to show some autocomplete options, stuff like Fantastic Bar,
Fast and so on.
And then at some point in time, user goes on to step number two.
That's when they submit the query.
So they hit enter on their keyboard or whatever else.
We need to show them some actual search results on the screen.
So for showing an autocomplete that's we want to use a prefix search.
That's where we want to take the users search string right here and add on a star to the end.
When a user actually submits their search, that's when we probably want to do a fuzzy search.
For example, if a user enters F HSR and they actually met you fast.
Well, in that scenario, we probably want to use that fuzzy search technique of adding on those percent
signs on either side.
Go for auto completes use prefix for just about everything else.
Probably want to do a fuzzy search.
Now it gets a little bit more complicated than this and the user enters in some search term here.
They might enter in something like Fast, fast, fast car.
And maybe some of these are misspelt as well.
Can't really just take this entire string, put percents around it and throw it into ready search.
We have to actually do some pre-processing on this thing.
So I want to focus on some steps we might do for pre-processing when we are trying to implement either
a fuzzy search or a prefix search.
Okay.
So prefix search first.
Here is an example of some steps we might go through.
We're trying to build up our query to send off to ready search.
Let's imagine that a user entered fast CAA.
And remember, we're trying to do a four prefix here.
We're trying to do, in theory, some kind of autocomplete option.
So ultimately, I want to end up with something like Fast K and Star on the End.
Or in other words, I want to put a star somewhere inside of here.
The first thing we might do is decide to split on all the space characters and all the punctuation characters.
You get an array of strings that looks like this.
And we might put on a star on the very last term over here, because that would give us results.
Results like fast car, fast, California, fast.
Whatever else starts with K.
But then there's a couple of questions that you need to answer for your particular application.
You might want to append on a star to all the other terms in this array as well.
So if a user is entering into a search field based CAA, do you really want to do autocomplete options
only on Vasya or do you want to see possible autocomplete for Fast and K separately?
That's a question that you need to answer, need to figure out what is best for you.
And then finally, when you actually take these two separate strings and put them into the query, you
have to decide whether to join them together with a space which remember implies an and operation or
an or with a pipe that you want to do fast and K or a vast or C a lot of decisions here.
And it's really going to come down to what data you are trying to search and what works best for your
application.
All I really want to do is kind of put these questions in your head so you can think about them as you're
working on your own app.
Okay.
So a similar series of operations for Fuzzy Search as well.
Let's imagine the user enters in fast.
DA We need to process this somehow.
First thing we would do is probably split on spaces or all punctuation.
And then once again, we've got a big question here.
Do we want to wrap each of these terms with 8%?
Do we want to wrap them with two percents?
You allow for more typos?
Or even three.
And again, it's going to come down to your application, how rigorous your users are or knowledgeable
they are in searches.
And then finally, we also need to decide when we take these two strings and need to join them back
together to put into our actual query.
Are we going to join them with a space implying an and or a pipe implying an or.
All right.
So again, just repeat for the third time now, my only goal here is to help you think about these things.
It really comes down to your data set as you are implementing your application to decide how you're
going to do this preprocessing stuff.
We are going to implement all this pre-processing inside of our e-commerce application.
So you will see all this in action and we're going to maybe play around a little bit on some different
alternatives and see how it affects our search results.