To make use of modules.
We're going to get the raw source code for the module we want to use.
So we might get the raw source code for registration.
We will then compile that code on our local computer, will then load that module up into Metis by using
a command called module load.
Now, this entire process, even though I'm showing it with a very simple diagram, ends up being really
tedious and a little bit error prone because we have to download some source code and copilot.
That can be a huge challenge in its own right.
As I was getting started on this course, I swapped over my personal laptop and laptop and used you
right now.
I started using an Apple MacBook with a M1 processor inside of it, and it turns out that compiling
Reddit's JSON for use on an M1 processor platform right now is rather challenging.
And I spent a lot of time debugging and getting this thing compiled.
Once I got it compiled, I was able to do the module load rather easily, but just compiling registration
was a big pain.
The manually setting up these modules can be a little bit of a challenge.
Fortunately, there is an alternative available to us and it's called Redis Stack.
So this is an alternative copy of Redis that you can download at Register IO and I'll show you a link
here in just a moment.
If we download read a stack, it includes a bunch of different modules pre-installed that we can make
use of without any additional setup.
You might have seen a reference to read a stack a while ago, much earlier on inside the course when
we were at red escort's io.
So this page right here.
At Red.
It's not EO.
If I hover over, get started, I'll be shown red reds and red is stack.
The red is is red is core.
It's the very base version of red is that includes just a bunch of very simple basic data types.
But if I make use of read a stack instead I'm getting some basic copy of ES with a bunch of different
modules preloaded inside of it.
So this is going to include Ready Search Readiness, JSON, and then a couple of other modules called
read as Graph Time Series and Blue.
When General where possible, we kind of like to use read a stack because it includes all these additional
capabilities without us having to do a bunch of additional setup.