In the last two videos, I've made it seem like these different modules are just the best thing in the
world and they make us better, and there's no question about it whatsoever.
So you might be kind of curious, why didn't we just start using these modules at the very beginning
of the course?
There's a very important answer to that very important answer that you understand this is extremely
critical.
So depending upon how you deploy your application or specifically how you run Redis in a production
environment, you might not be able to use modules.
So I want to expand on that in this video and help you understand when you are able to use modules and
when you can't.
Okay.
Though we are developing an application right now, our e-commerce application, and in theory we might
eventually want to go and deploy it to some provider such as IWC or Google Cloud.
When we deploy our application, we're going to have to connect to a production instance of Redis.
The question here is how are we going to create this instance?
We're going to take a look at three different options.
The first option is possibly the easiest, but there's a very clear downside to it in option number
one.
We can ask MWC or Google Cloud to run a copy of Redis for us.
We refer to this as a managed copy of Redis because someone else is managing.
Read it for us.
DWC or Google Cloud is going to handle the setup, the security updates, general updates, handle backups
and so on.
They're going to deal with everything related to managing Redis.
That's absolutely fantastic because it frees us as developers up from having to do a lot of extra work.
But the clear downside here that is very important to understand, as you see in this huge red box,
when you are using these managed offerings provided directly by IWC and Google Cloud, you cannot use
Redis modules.
So if you are running your application on ABC or Google Cloud and you definitely have to be using a
managed copy of it, you can't use modules.
And that's why it's important for you to understand all the different basic data types we've learned
so far.
In the course.
You have to understand how to use strings, sorted sets, lists and so on, because if you can't use
modules, you're going to be relying upon those basic structures.
Now.
Not all hope is lost here.
Even if you do have to run your application on IWC, there are still some scenarios, very common zeros
as a matter of fact, where you can make use of modules.
So let me show you two other options on how we can run our application on IWC or Google Cloud and still
use modules.
So the second option.
Is if we just run readies ourselves.
So we might create a virtual machine or a container run readies inside of ourselves.
And in the scenario we are allowed to use modules, we can freely load up Redis, JSON or ready search
and everything.
Everything's going to work just fine.
We can use any module we want if we run Redis ourselves.
The downside to this approach is that it just requires a lot of additional setup on our side.
We have to do the initial setup.
We have to install these modules, we have to do security updates, we have to handle backups and so
on.
So that's a lot of additional developer time just to set up all that infrastructure in Manjit.
All right.
On to option number three, which I think is really a happy medium.
And option number three, we're going to rely upon the company.
So there is a company called Redis to run Redis for us.
Now, let me give you some more information about this, because it's a little bit more challenging
to understand.
You might recall much earlier on inside the course, we went to RedState.com, we signed up for an account,
and then we created a free read as instance on a dashboard that looks like this.
When you created that free Redis instance, it was actually created on AWB or Google Cloud or Microsoft
Azure.
So it's a red instance that is still being executed or running on these cloud providers.
You can see right now I have two separate instances and they are both truly running on AWB and these
are managed instances, which means I don't have to worry about security updates, backups and so on.
So the only difference here is that someone else is doing the managing for us as opposed to just IWC
or Google Cloud directly.
The nice thing about having Redis do the managing for us is that in this scenario we are allowed to
use a couple of very specific modules so we can make use of read as JSON, ready search and all the
others that are listed under read a stack right here.
So if you are using RedState.com to run your copy of Read, is it still going to be hosted on IWC or
Google Cloud?
So your application can still connect to it directly without having to go to some external cloud provider?
It is still managed and we still get to use all these different modules.
So personally, I think ops number three right here is a very happy medium.
We still get our copy of Redis publicly located with the application, but we still get all the modules
as well.
So this is the approach that we're going to focus on in this course.
Because again, happy medium, I'm only giving you all this information because if you are working at
some company that is already making use of a copy of Redis, well, you might be in scenario one right
here where you might be working on an application that has to use an existing managed copy of Redis.
And so modules might not be available to you.
Okay.
So now that we have this little caveat here in mind, we're now going to start to focus on these modules
themselves and just understand how to make use of them.