The first module that we are going to discuss is called Ready Search.
Let me first tell you why we are using this module at all.
One thing that you might have noticed earlier on inside this course as we are building the e-commerce
application, is that implementing any kind of query operation on a collection of different hashes was
kind of challenging.
For example, if we wanted to find all the items that were ending soonest were the items that had the
most views or the items that were most expensive, we had to create some accessory data structures.
So we had to create some sorted sets on the side and maintain those structures over time.
That was a lot of extra work and definitely something that I personally would not really want to have
to do all the time.
Redis search is going to allow us to skip that entire process.
So 3D search, we get the ability to run arbitrary queries over a collection of different hashes without
having to maintain a bunch of structures on site like sorted sets, sets, lists and so on.
In addition, Ready Search allows us to do queries with multiple different pieces of criteria so we
can do a query like the one you see right here where we try to find all the items with a price less
than 45 and a color of green.
Implementing something like this with just plain lettuce would be a little bit more challenging.
So ready search really is fantastic.
The use ready search.
We're going to go through two separate steps.
Step one, we're going to create an index.
An index is a data type that points to all of the different records that we want to be able to search.
We only have to do this one time for any group of records that we want to search.
So if we want to search over all of our different items, we have to create one index one time.
If we want to search over all of our different users, we have to create a second index one time.
If we want to search over, say, all the different bids, that's going to be another index.
And it only has to be created once.
Whenever we make an index, we have to specify two different things.
The first is going to be which records we want to build a search for.
And we do this by providing a prefix.
So this right here is treated as a key prefix.
It means find all the different hashes that start with a string, or I should say all the different
hashes that have a key of items out.
When ready search creates the index.
It's going to go to Redis, find all the different keys that start with items pounds and then say,
okay, there's a hash here.
The user must want to be able to search for this record.
For each of these different hashes.
Ready search is then going to record a tiny piece of info about that hashes, name, color and price.
Once the index has been created, we can then use it as many times as we want to run the query so we
can run the query and look for some item with a particular name, colour price and so on.
And for each of these different steps, we're going to learn about just one single command.
But to create an index, we only need to understand one command called for dot create and for running
a query.
We only have to understand one single command to dot search.
Now, this might make everything sound really simple.
Everything around.
Ready?
Search for just two commands.
That sounds really simple, but in reality, it turns out that there are a tremendous number of variations
around these two commands.
So we really can spend a lot of time just learning about how these things work.
Okay.
So let's take a pause right here.
We're going to come back in just a moment.
We're going to build our first index and run the query in the next video.