To get a better idea of how ready search works.
I'd like to create a new hour book notebook.
You'll notice I've already done that myself.
I want to create a couple of different records by hand, so they're all going to be hashes, but then
going to create an index around those and then run a query or two.
Once we get some hands on experience will then come back and understand what those two commands of FTA
create and FTA search are doing.
All right.
So step one, we're going to write out a couple of different hashes by hand very quickly.
We're going to have four hashes in total cars, a one B1, C1 and D1.
Each of them is going to have a name, a color and a year.
Let's write out the commands to create these very fast.
The back and side of our book.
I'm going to do a couple of eight set commands.
I'll do a H set RS, a one with the name of fast car, a color of red.
And a year of 1950.
I'm not going to copy that command down three times just to save a little bit of time.
I'm going to edit each these lines one by one.
So the next one is going to be a key of cars B one, c one, and then D one.
And the second car will have a name of just car.
An old car and then new car.
And for color, first you will be red.
Then the second two are going to be blue.
And then finally I'll leave the year on the first one in 1950, then 1960, 1970.
And 1990.
Okay.
I'm going to run this and create those four different hashes.
So now we have some datasets, we've got four different hashes and we want to be able to search over
all these different records and write some kind of query to find only some specific records for to make
use of ready search, as we just saw just a moment ago, we're going to go through two different steps.
First, we're going to create an index.
We only have to do that one time and then we're going to use that index to actually run a query.
For this video in particular.
We're just going to write out the commands and we'll understand how they work.
Starting in the next video.
So let's get to it.
Back over here.
I'm going to add in a new code block and I'm going to create a new index with.
FTA dot creates.
I'm going to give this index a name of index cars.
Then on hash.
Prefix one rs lb.
I'm then going to add on a second line here.
Remember, when you add on a second line, you have to indent.
You have to tab in.
If you do not tab in, if you just put in the continuation of the command right here, you will get
an error because our book is going to think that this is a separate command right here.
On next line down, I'm going to tab in.
And then do.
Schema.
Name.
Text.
You're numeric.
And color tag.
Now.
Double check your spelling on all these.
Make sure you've got the same typing.
Everything is identical.
Once you've confirmed that we're going to run that cell, we should see.
Okay.
The index has now been created and we can use it to write out a couple of queries and find some very
particular cars.
So let's now try that.
We're going to write out three different queries down here in the bottom cell.
The first query that I would like to write out is going to find all of the cars with the name of a fast
car.
In this case, we've only got one record with the name a fast car.
So that's cars at A1 right here.
Let's write out the query and we'll make sure that we get back just that particular record.
For this first query.
I'll do not search IDC's Colin Carr's.
And then inside of a string at color.
A colon or something.
Hot color, but name.
There we go.
So at name colon.
And then inside of parentheses, fast car.
If I run that, I'm going to get back.
Kind of a confusing result right here.
But if we look really closely, it appears that it actually is correct.
We get back in Ray.
The first element is the number of results we got.
So in this case, one.
The one result we get, we got will then see the key of that record.
And then inside of an array we'll see the keys and values of that hash look.
Get a name, a fast car color, red year, 1950.
That looks correct to me.
Let's try another query now.
This next one, I want to find all the cars with a color of blue.
That would be RC one.
And cars D one.
I'm going to comment out the first query and then do an FTA search.
Idk cars.
During.
At color.
In.
Really braces.
And then blue.
L run that.
And then correctly, I get two results.
A kilo of C one and D one.
Okay.
Looks like it's definitely working out as expected.
Let's just do one more.
I want to try to find all the different cars that have a year between 1955 and 1985.
That would be just be one and see one.
So for that, we'll do an FTA search.
RS.
You're.
And then square brackets this time that they.
1955 in 1980.
I run that.
And once again, I get to results here.
So I've got cars C one and B one, and that's correct as well.
Okay.
So we've now seen an example of reading an index and then using it to run a couple of different queries.
And the first thing I really want to highlight here is that there's definitely a wide range of syntax.
We're actually writing the query.
So in one case, we use parentheses, in another we use curly braces, and then in another we use square
brackets.
Turns out that understanding the search command is probably going to be the most challenging aspect
of understanding ready search.
So we really have a lot to learn, but let's start to dive into the innards of these commands in the
next video.