In this video, we're going to start to dive into the creates and search commands.
Before we get started, however, I want to have a very quick side discussion.
If you look at the official documentation around ready search, you're not going to see anything that
really distinguishes the idea of querying from searching.
It's not in there whatsoever.
I think that it would be very helpful to just get you thinking about the difference between a query
and a search, because it is going to make a couple of topics along the way a lot easier to understand.
Okay.
So first off query, what are we doing when we write a query?
Whenever we write a query, we're usually trying to find a set of records that match some existing exact
criteria.
So if we said Get all cars made in 1955 with the color of red, I would expect that all the results
and the result set match exactly these requirements.
Every car must be made in 1955 and every car must have a color red.
Same with the other two queries here as well.
So I might look for all cars made before 1960 with a name exactly.
Of Fast car and same thing for all cars with the color of blue.
Now compared to Queering.
There's also the idea of searching.
Usually with searching, we're not going to get really an exact result set.
All the results we get might not exactly fit our criteria, but they are kind of like a close enough
guess of what we're looking for.
So an example of search might be if we try to get all cars with a name like car, that goes fast.
If we're trying to search for a car that goes fast, we might actually be trying to find a record.
This one right here.
Cars at a one with the name of fast car.
So a car that goes fast that does not match the value right here of name.
The value is fast car, but it's kind of close enough to what we're looking for where if I was doing
searching, I would expect to find that results.
If we had a search for all cars related to 90 Blue Fast, I might be looking for cars made in 1990 with
the color of blue.
It has a name, including the string fast.
And if I did a search for Gast var in this case, I just have some typos here.
So Gast, that key is very close on the keyboard to F, so my user might have meant to say fast.
And in the case of v, v is right next to C on the keyboard.
So user might have been meaning to say car.
So user possibly was trying to say find all the fast cars, but instead they might have entered gast
var and we would still want to find some record that well how a name of fast car.
Again, querying is when we are trying to find a exact result set.
Searching is really where we are trying to interpret some possibly flawed query coming from a user or
some possible flawed string, and we're trying to show the best possible results.
You can really see this in action if you go to any e-commerce website such as, say, Amazon.com.
I pulled up Amazon.com really quickly.
Here it is right here.
I'm looking at men's boots right now.
If I scroll down on the left hand side, I can see examples of queries that I can enter so I can try
to find all the shoe sizes exactly equal to 12.
I can search for exact shoe widths and brands and occasions, closure, colours, heights and so on.
These are all examples of query able criteria so I can find all the boot colours that are exactly black.
On the other hand, I could go to the very top up here at the search fields and I can enter a search
instead.
So I might put in something like Boots for Men That Is Black.
So it's up to Amazon to somehow take this string, which might have typos in it, and try to figure
out what I am trying to say.
That is an example of search.
Okay.
So this might seem like totally irrelevant right now, but trust me, it's really important to keep
this idea in your head because as you start to look at the already search documentation, there's going
to be some aspects of these commands we're about to learn about that are really talking about doing
a query type operation and then other aspects that are really talking about doing a search type operation.
And life is going to be a lot easier if we just make a distinction between them.
All right.
So enough of this aside, I apologize the for 4 minutes deep here in this video and I've spent all this
time talking about this.
So let's just move on very quickly.
And I want to give you a brief overview on that create right here.
Okay.
So after that creates I took the command, I broke it up piece by piece.
We're going to go over each term one by one.
The first idea, cars, this is the name of the index we're about to create.
And you can really think of this as being just like a key in any other command that we've ever written.
Every index we create is always going to follow a very similar naming convention.
We're going to do something like index short for index colon, and then a name for this index are really
the kind of thing that we are searching for.
In this case, we are searching for cars.
So I might end up with ADX cars.
If we ever create an index and then want to later on delete it, we can use F.T. Dot Drop Index.
We're going to do that several times inside this section so that we can recreate our index with different
attributes tied to it.
Next up is on hash.
This describes the kind of values that we're going to search over.
The only valid values here is either hash or JSON.
We're only going to use Jason if we are using that other Redis module called Reddit JSON.
Right now we are not using writes Jason, so we are making use of on hash instead.
After that we got prefix one cars.
This is how we tell our index which records we're going to want to search over.
So internally, FTA Dot creates is going to try to find all the different keys that begin with a string
of cars out and it's going to inspect all those different records.
You'll notice there is a one right here.
Whenever we create an index, we can have multiple different prefixes.
Let's imagine that maybe you want to build a prefix and look at all the different keys that begin with
cars.
And we also want to look at all the different keys that begin with, say, trucks as well.
So we might do something like expound.
And then because we are now providing two prefixes, we would change the one to it to.
And then onto schema schemas, how we're going to describe the different properties that we want ready
search to look at inside of each of these different hashes that it's going to inspect the we're going
to list out right after schema the name of a field inside of our hash and then the type of value inside
there and the name type, name type.
We only put down schema once and we can list out just about as many name type pairs as we want.
You don't have to list out every single field inside of your hashes.
So for example, if we did not ever want to do any kind of searching or crying or filtering over color,
we would just leave color out entirely and think for a year if we didn't care about doing any kind of
search around here, we'd delete that as well.
Now I want to have a quick side discussion here around these different types that are available to us.
And this is where the idea of querying versus searching is going to start to become very, very important.
Let's start to discuss.
The different types are available in just a moment.