After we list out the schema keyword, we then place the name of a field inside of our hash and then
the type of value that is stored inside there.
So now I want to tell you about some of the different types that are are available to us.
Okay.
So the first one is the easiest to understand the numeric type so we can mark a field inside of a hash
as storing a numeric.
Any time that we want to do some kind of number based query over our index.
So in our example.
We marked the year as a numeric and because we did that, we can then do a numeric type query.
We can try to find all the cars that were made before 1950, after 1950, or exactly on 1950.
So any kind of basic numeric query.
Next up is Geo will mark field as GEO.
Any time it contains geographic coordinates and that allows us to do a geographic type query.
We're not going to go too much into geographic queries, so we're going to skip over to the next one
vector.
We're also not going to go too much into.
This is a very advanced type of query that allows us to find similarities between different records.
We might touch on it a little bit later.
But right now on, move on just once again and focus on the two most important for us to understand
for right now, which are tag and text.
You'll notice a moment ago when we defined schema, we marked name, which refers to a string inside
of our hash as text, but we marked color, which is also referring to a string as tag.
So what is the difference between text and tag?
Well, it really goes back to what we discussed just a little bit ago between querying and searching
in general.
If we are using a string inside of a hash as a query term, then we're going to mark that string as
being type tag.
And again, in general, if we are making use of a field inside of a hash for a search operation and
we're probably going to market as text.
So querying is tag, searching is text.
Let me tell you why that is.
Whenever we have marquee field as tag, we can use that field for exact string lookups so we can try
to find, say, all the cars with a color exactly equal to red for all the cars that do not have a color
of red.
When we mark a field as containing text, then Ready Search is going to do a lot of additional analysis
on that field and we will be able to search for the text inside that field using fuzzy search.
We can handle typos.
We can do a lot of very fancy search operations that you would really expect out of any kind of typical
search field.
Just like the search field I showed you a moment ago over on Amazon.
Let's show you some more examples of where we might use a tag versus text.
So if we are ever trying to refer to a string idea that is stored inside of a hash, we're probably
going to try to do queries in the future where we look for IDs exactly equal to that or exactly not
equal to that.
That's where we might want to use attack.
We might want to use a tag any time that we are trying to record the color of a product and the color
is only ever going to be a member of it, a very strict set of colors.
I'm assuming that we're not going to want to say allow any user to enter in any kind of color for a
product.
We might just want to have a very thick set of colors for products.
So red, green and blue and that's it.
Nothing else.
If our products are made in a very specific country, we might want to reflect that country using a
tag because again, we might try to find all the products that are made inside of a very specific country.
Likewise, any time we are doing a search operation, we want to use text.
So good options of using text are really any time a user is entering data themselves.
So something like a product name, a description or a review.
These are all opportunities for us to use text.
Now, even in these examples right here, I don't think I'm really giving you the full sense of where
to use tags or text.
Let me give you one last example that is kind of like a little test that I think is really going to
work the vast majority of time when you are trying to decide which to use.
Let's imagine we are building a website and on this website you cannot create a new product and a product
is going to have a name and a color.
So for your product, you probably can have an open ended text field where a user can enter in any value
they want.
If you have some property in a hash that would be best represented by an open ended text field like
this.
Chances are you want to mark that field as being text because a user can enter in any value.
And that might include.
Some typos or something like that.
It might include some unexpected characters.
Whenever we are trying to search over unexpected strings or user provided strings using radio search,
we usually want to mark that field as text.
And if you have an attribute inside of your house that would be best represented by a dropdown where
it can only be selected from an existing set.
That's probably a good example of a tag.
So I might have a dropdown right here.
If a user clicks on it, I'm going to show options of red, green or blue.
So it's one value out of this possible set of values.
Again, that'd be a good example of where to use a tag.
Okay.
So text first.
Tag one gives us really fancy search capabilities.
The other is really just about exact string lookups.
Now we've got text and tags done and we've got a better understanding around indexes.
At least right now, let's take one more pause and we'll start taking a look at the search command in
just a moment.