Let's move on to the search command.
We make use of search to run a query over an index that has already been created.
The general command is after that search.
The name of the index we want to use and then a query right after that.
Before I show you anything else, I want to point out the official documentation around this command.
So at Redstone EO commands for search, you're going to find a page that looks like this.
By showing you this previously with all the different arguments you can possibly add on here.
So a lot of stuff going on.
But on this page, if you scroll down a little bit.
Under the section of parameters right here.
There's a section on the query that we are writing out.
The query is that little bit right after we list the index.
For us, it was that string.
And that string and that string.
Even though it looks like there's already a lot of documentation on this page, there is an entirely
separate page for understanding the query syntax.
You can find a link to it right here.
So if you open up that page, you'll see something like this.
You might see a slightly different looking page just for the purposes of this video.
I've manually edited the page just a little bit so you can see everything on the screen very easily.
On this page, you're going to see a huge document around the syntax of the query that we put in.
There's a lot of information on this page.
I'm going to try to give you as much of it as I can in the coming videos.
But if you ever get stuck or you're trying to figure out how to write some kind of query, I really
recommend you come back to this page and use it to figure out the syntax around all these different
variations.
So let's get to summarizing everything that's on that page.
The first thing to understand is something that you might have already picked up on your own.
Whenever you write out a query, we're going to put the at then the name of the field that we want to
look up inside of each hash that we are searching over.
We're then going to put a call in and then depending upon the type of data in the field that we are
looking at, we're going to put in either parentheses, really braces or square brackets.
So parentheses are used with text, really.
Braces are with tags and square brackets are with numbers.
If we want to, we can combine together multiple different queries into one query string.
So quick example of that.
Back over here.
Let's say we want to find all the cars that were made between 1955 and 1980 that are also of color blue.
So inside the string, we would add in at color colon really braces blue.
And we get the one result right here.
One other thing I want you to understand around the documentation, around all these queries we're going
to write out, we are always going to wrap them in quotes.
Even if the documentation doesn't specifically show it though, in the docs, you might see a example
at Tag Query that looks like this right here.
When you actually go to make use this inside of a search command, you are going to wrap it with quotes.
You can not use either single or double.
It doesn't make a difference.
Just keep in mind that if your query itself needs to use quotes, let's say for some reason we wanted
to quote New York right here.
We would use whatever quote style we did not use on the outer string.
So we have single on the outer.
I would use double on the inner.
Now I want to give you some specific details around numeric queries.
A lot of these things are going to be pretty straightforward, easy to pick up, but we're going to
go over them regardless very quickly.
So you understand that you can write queries that look at numbers in very specific ways.
So we want to just look at all the records that have some range of numbers.
We use the square brackets like we saw in our example, carry a moment to go back where he is inclusive.
So at year 1955, 1980 is going to find all the elements are all the hashes with a field that has a
value of between and including 1955.
In 1980.
If you want to do an exclusive query.
So if you want to go from 1956 up to but not including 1980, we're going to put an open perennial just
right before the number.
So this would be really give us all the different cars between 1956 and 1979.
You do not have to use both brands at the same time.
So we could do something like that.
That would be everything from and including 1955 up to but not including 1980.
Much like the sort command we had taken a look at previously and range we can also make use of plus
or negative infinity.
So in 1955, dual plus infinity means give us all the records with the year greater than 1955, greater
than and equal to.
To be precise, we can use negative infinity as well.
So this would be all the way from 1955, including 1955 and less than that.
And then finally, if we have a range or really a negative range, there are a year, a range of years
or range of numbers that we do not want to include in results that we can put in a dash right before
the query.
So this would be give us all the cars that were not made between 1955 and 1980.
The Macquarie's pretty simple, pretty straightforward.
It's really just an issue of remembering to go look at the documentation and understanding these four
different variations.
It's really when we start looking at tags and text that things get a little bit more complicated.
So let's look at those two query types in just a moment.