Let's look at some variations on tag queries.
But as we saw just a moment ago.
Whenever you are trying to query a tag field on a hash, we're going right out at the name of the field,
really races.
And then the tag we are looking for.
We make use of tag queries or tag fields anytime we are trying to find a value exactly equal to some
string.
Just like numbers.
There are a couple different variations on these queries that we can do at Color Blue to find all the
different records with a color equal to blue.
We can do dash hullabaloo if we are trying to find all the records that do not have a color equal to
blue.
We can make use of an order by using the type symbol.
That's not an I, it's not an L, it's the pipe.
That's the character.
Right above the return key on your keyboard.
Red pipe blue would give us all the different records with red or blue.
And then finally, if we ever have a tag that has spaces in it.
So the string lights, space blue.
We need to escape that space by using a backslash.
Let's try out a couple of these really quickly.
The back over here.
I'm going to copy the existing tag query that we have.
If we get all the cars with a colour of blue, we get back to results.
If I put a minus or a dash right in front of that, I should get back all the cars that are not blue.
Now I get red and red down here.
And then finally, if I do read Hype Blue.
That will give me all the cars that are either red or blue.
There's one last little thing I want to mention are antiquities very quickly, because this is a real
gotcha that you're going to run into.
Sometimes whenever you are trying to run a query on a text field or a tag field, there are some words
that are going to be automatically filtered out of your query by Redis.
We refer to these as stop words.
These are words that are really, really common in the English language and don't really add a whole
lot to any typical query.
So if you ever have a tag query with a value of A is the everything you see in this list right here,
those terms will be filtered out automatically.
So in other words, if you do a query of something like at Cities two or meet two or a or then you can
kind of imagine that behind the scenes register is going to interpret this as at cities with nothing
in there because these all three are stop words.
So they are going to be automatically removed.
The reason I mention this is that every now and then, as you are getting used to ready search, you
might try doing a query for just the character A or something like that.
That is a stop word.
So it will be filtered out of a query.
Finally, I want to mention that this is true not only of tags but text queries as well.
We're going to look at text queries a little bit more in the next video.
Okay.
So that in mind, let's move on to text queries, which is where syntax really gets a little bit more
intense.