We've now ran into a couple of different concurrency issues on our application.
And remember, we have seen these issues whenever we tried to fetch some data, allow some time to pass,
and then attempt to save some data back into Metis.
The issue is that while this time is passing, some other requests might have caused this data to be
changed.
Another issue that we haven't really ran into just yet, but I'm sure you could see that this might
be a problem, is if we're trying to fetch a lot of data from lettuce and there's no command that really
supports a particular query that we're trying to run.
Let's imagine that we have a sorted set with members of ABCD e and scores of one, two, three, four,
five and maybe for some crazy reason, who knows why we want to do this.
But for some reason we want to find all the members of that sorted set the score that is a multiple
of two.
Then the words, all the even scores.
That would be B and D right there.
Without a doubt, there's no command that allows us to do this right out of the box with reticence.
So the only solution we could probably put in here would be to find all the members and scores match
them all over to our server and then apply some filtering logic there.
So in this case, we are fetching way more data than we need just to implement what is otherwise a pretty
basic query.
So in this section, as you can probably guess, we're going to figure out a way to deal with this.
We're going to figure out a way to solve these problems of data over fetching and also solve some concurrency
issues as well.
And this feature, we're going to learn about our Lua scripts.
So let's take a look at what a Lewis script is.
Lewis scripts are little bits of code that we write on our server.
We're then going to take the script and send it off to Redis.
Reddit is going to run.
That script produced some amount of data depending upon what code we write in the script and then send
us back some results.
Is.
Lewis Scripts are written in a programming language called Lua.
If you are not familiar with Lua, don't sweat it.
It's really, really easy to pick up.
And I'm going to give you a brief overview on some major topics around it.
Is Lewis scripts have access to the full set of commands a reticence so a Lewis script can access a
simple string or a hash is sorted, set and so on.
A single Lewis script and a run multiple different commands in a row so we can have a Lewis script that
attempts to say, access our sorted sets, use some filtering logic on it, and then return all the
results that we find that match some kind of filtering criteria.
We can then run some other commands on the data that comes back we want to before we attempt to return
those results, back over to our server.
So the very nice thing about Louis Scripps is that allows us to run multiple different commands without
ever returning any data back over to our server except for the final result that we actually care about.
So you can imagine that it's very much going to solve problems related to data over fetching or other
related issues.
All right.
So like I said, we do need to understand a little bit about Lua.
We're going to do a little brief aside in the next couple of videos, and I'm just going to give you
some high level points around Lua.
We're going to write out a couple of code snippets and just understand how the programming language
works at a very basic level.