All right.
No more lecturing for right now.
Let's go back over to our editor.
And like I said, we're going to implement this add one and store function II to work clients and it's
going to be implemented using a custom Lua script.
But to get started back inside my editor, I'm going to find the services Redis folder and then clients.
When we are making use of no treaties, we have to define all of our scripts and provide them to the
create client call.
Right here you define a new custom script that's going to be written in Lua.
We have to import the you fine script function from Redis up here at the top.
And then inside of this options object right after password, I'm going to put in a comma and then a
scripts section.
As you guess, this is where we are going to define all of our different scripts.
Inside this object is where we are going to provide these five pieces of information, the name of our
function script itself, blah, blah, blah.
Inside this object.
The key is going to be the name of our script.
So it's going to be how we are going to eventually call this function from inside of our code base.
We want to have a function called something like add one and store.
I'm going to put in, add one and store and then the value of this will be define scripts.
I'll pass in an empty object for right now.
I know we have an error right here.
We'll fix that for just a moment.
I just want to highlight, because we have now added in ad one and store anywhere inside of our code
base.
We could now call client dot, add one and store.
That is going to run the custom script that we are about to define right here.
If we instead put a key right here of something like the Tract one and store.
Well, now we can run the function, subtract one and store, and it's going to run the script that
we defined right there.
Again, whatever kiwi add in this object right here, it adds additional methods to this client object.
Okay.
So going to undo that back to add one in store because that's what we actually want.
We've now achieved step number one right here.
We have defined the name of the function we're going to call inside of our JavaScript code.
Let's move on to step number three.
We're going to go over number two really quickly.
We're going to define how many keys we are going to provide when we try to run our function.
This essentially means how many keys are we trying to pass off to the shore command?
When Node Redis runs it for us, in our case, there's only one key that we are trying to access.
Remember, we have to mention the exact values of all these different keys ahead of time.
When we tried to run our Lewis script, the only key that we were going to try to access is going to
be whatever this first argument is right here.
In this case, its books count, but naturally it could be any other kind of key we want to put it.
But to instruct no treatise on how many keys we are going to eventually provide to it.
I'm going to add in number of keys.
One.
And that's it.
Whatever value you put right here, that's essentially going to be passed directly through to the shore
command when no treatise runs in store for you.
As a part of this script, we are defining.
All right.
Next up, we're going to define the script itself.
So this is going to be our loose script.
Script that's going to receive some arguments, receive some keys, and then run some read commands
and possibly return a results.
The for our scripts.
I'm going to add in script in all capitals and then a template string.
Notice the back ticks right here, not single quotes.
I'm only using a template string because I want to put in a multi-line string right here.
We can define multi-line strings with a template string.
So inside of here, we're going to put in all the logic required to implement our scripts.
Remember, all we are really doing in our case is taking in some number, adding one to it, and then
storing it at some key.
I'm going to return.
Right.
A skull.
I want to run the set command in my scripts.
I want to put in arguments for sets of first the key where I want to store of value.
And then, of course, the value that I want to store there.
So I'm going to run a set.
On Keys at one.
And then I'll put in the value I want to store there, which will be one plus.
To number.
RGV at one.
This goes back to some stuff we learned around Lewis Scripps a little bit ago.
Remember, the keys array is going have a list of all the different keys we provided to our scripts
when e-mail Shaw gets called, and then RGV is going to be an array of all the different arguments that
are provided.
All right.
That's number two.
Now we're going to move on to four and five.
One, step four, we need to provide node readies, instructions on how to pass arguments to our scripts.
And what I mean by this is when we call Add one and Store, we're going to provide arguments right here
of some key and some number.
No treatise out of the box doesn't really know how to take these arguments right here and pass them
off to the e-mail shore command.
We have to define a function that's going to take in these two arguments and then return an array that
says here is the exact order and the exact values of what we want to be provided to evil.
Shaw.
Let me show you how that works.
I'm going to put a comma at the end of our script and then transform arguments.
The arguments to this function are going to be whatever we expect to be asked to the function that we
are trying to run or tied to our node readiness library.
So in other words, the arguments to transform arguments are going to be these exact values right here.
So for us, the first argument is going to be a key.
That's a string, and then the second will be a number.
Let's call it.
How about value instead?
The number that we are trying to add one, two and store.
Again, we only are using these arguments right here because that is how we want to call add one in
store.
We instead expected to put in first a number right here.
And then a key.
Then we would have flipped the order of key and value right here.
Now, we would have been receiving first the value and then the key.
Then inside of here, we have to return an array that exactly describes how we want to take these arguments
right here and provide them off to the email shore command.
But for us, that's going to be return whatever key.
And then the value to strength.
Now internally when we try to run this function, when we tried to tell node readies to run our custom
script node Redis is going to take those two arguments right there.
The books count and number six.
It's going to provide them to transform arguments.
We are going to return an array that has the key and the value as a string.
So imagine what that's going to eventually turn into.
It'll be an array that looks like books count and say the number five as a string.
No treatise is then going to execute evolution, but the script ID is going to insert number of keys
right here.
The one, and then it's going to take this entire array of strings right here and just basically put
that in right after that one that's going to insert books out.
And five.
And this right here is a valid way of running al-Qaida.
That's what transform argument is doing.
It's how we are mapping the arguments we're passing to our function right here to the evil shore command.
Okay.
Last step, step number five.
The Stettner five is very similar to a D.C. realize function we've already put together many times throughout
this course.
All we're doing is telling Node, read us how to take the results or the return value from our Lewis
script and pass it into some value that can be used by the rest of our application.
Russ We don't really have any particular way that we want to transform or serialize the results.
I'm going to put in a transform reply.
I'm going to receive whatever is coming back from running our scripts.
I don't know what the value is going to be.
It's going to be whatever the result of a red skull set is.
It's really the result of a set command.
I don't really want to do anything in particular with it, however.
So I'm going to say take whatever that value is and return it.
But now whenever we run.
Ad one in store.
That's going to execute our Lewis scripts take whatever value gets returns, it's going to pass it through,
transform reply.
We are not doing anything in particular or anything special with it, so we are just going to return
it back to whatever part of our code base ran, the ad won and store function.
No additional parsing required in this case.
Okay.
So that's it.
That is our custom function.
Now to test this out.
Here's the fun part.
Underneath this entire client block.
I'm going to add in a client dot on.
Next.
And then inside of here, I'm going to try to call my custom function.
So I will do a client, not add one and store two books.
Count it five.
And just to make sure this thing is working, I'm going to mark this as async.
I will then await the execution of that script.
And then immediately after we run that.
I'm going to get.
Whatever value is stored at Brooks Counts.
And just console.log it like.
So that's how we're going to check and make sure that everything is working as expected.
Run the script, wait for it to be executed, and go ahead and get whatever value is stored at books.
Count and console.log it.
Okay.
So I'm going to save this.
I'm going to go back over to my terminal.
And sure enough, there we go.
I got the value six, which is exactly what we want.
So it looks like the script worked.
Naturally, if I wanted to, I could change what value we are passing into the script right here.
I could put in a ten instead.
If I save this, look back over.
I get back 11.
But definitely looks like everything is working as expected.
I want to show you one last diagram to just summarize the different parts of that little code block
right there.
The actual script we wrote out was a little bit different than what I show in this diagram, but essentially
the same thing.
And this diagram I just showed assigning keys and arguments to local variables just to clarify their
use.
But other than that, everything is just about identical.
Once again, I just want to repeat, I know this stuff is nasty because we're taking a look at a complicated
topic of race within throwing on top the idea of custom functions or Louis snippets.
And on top of that, we're looking at how to integrate these custom lua snippets into the Node Redis
library.
So it's several levels of abstraction being stacked up on top of each other.
That's it.
We got through a basic function.
Now that we understand these basics.
We're going to define another custom script in just a moment.
Just like what we did right here.
And this custom script is going to replace all the logic that we currently have inside of Increment
View.
Let's get started on that in the next video.