All right.
We're going to go through the same process as the last video.
We're going to define a custom function ID to the node ratings client that we are using.
This custom function is going to run a custom Lua script that is going to be loaded into Redis or us.
The entire process is going to be identical to this entire add one and store thing.
We're going to add another key to the scripts object.
We're going to call define script again and put in all the same arguments.
This time, however, the actual lua we have to write is going to be much more complicated as we need
to implement all these steps right here in Lua as opposed to in JavaScript.
Now, any time we have to write out a more complicated script, I got a little design process.
I recommend you follow.
We're only going to do this this one time in the future.
I'm not going to make you repeat it because it is just a little bit tedious.
But I think just one experience of it will help you understand what's going on.
Okay.
So we are trying to take a little bit of JavaScript code, really TypeScript and translate it into Lua.
The first thing we're going to do as a part of that process, we're going to take a look at the existing
JavaScript code and identify all the keys and the arguments that we are going to try to make use up
inside of our Lewis script, because we need to provide those keys and those arguments ahead of time
when we try to execute the script.
For this.
I'm going to go back over to the logic I'm trying to replace.
I'm going to look over all this code and find all the keys and all the arguments that I will need.
And then going to take a couple of notes down here at the bottom, we're going to put in a comment that
says Keys I need to access.
The first key is going to be our items view is key.
That's the first one.
Let's put a note down here.
Items.
U.S..
The second one is going to be items key.
That's another key we need to access.
And then finally, items by view key.
So those are the three keys that we need to access.
Now, one thing I want to make sure is super clear.
I'm putting on the names of our key generation functions right here.
But the actual keys that we're going to try to access are going to be something like items account and
then the ID.
The note names I'm putting right here are just reminders to myself that when I eventually go to call
Evil Sha.
And put in my ID.
I'm going to need to provide a number three right here to indicate that I'm about to list out different
special keys that we're going to access as our script is is evaluated.
And then the first key that I'm going to provide would probably be the actual string value of whatever
items view keys that I'm trying to access.
The second value will be the actual items key that I'm trying to access.
So something looks like that.
And then items by use keys will be the third one.
Okay.
Next up, we're going to take a look at all this code again and try to figure out what arguments my
Louis script is going to need to accept for this thing to work correctly.
The arguments that are Lewis script is going to need to accept are going to be exactly the same as the
arguments to this function itself.
Y need to know which item id was just viewed and I need to know the idea of the user who just did the
view.
I'm going to put down here.
Arguments I need to accept are going to be first the item ID.
And second, the user ID.
Okay.
That looks good.
Now in step number two, we're going to go and start to write out our Lewis scripts.
So the actual script itself, inside the script, at the very top of it, we are going to take all the
values that get passed in as arguments to that RGV array and all the keys that get passed in to the
keys array.
And rather than making use of the values inside those two arrays directly, as we did in the script
we wrote out just a moment ago.
So for example, right here, I just accessed keys at one directly.
Instead of doing that, we're going to instead assign those keys and those arguments.
So the individual elements, very well labeled variables at the top of the script.
So in short, rather than just accessing keys at one, as we are doing right here, I want to instead
do something like.
Here to assign value?
Or how about incremented number two?
And that's going to be.
Add one.
And then I want to use that variable name instead of keys one directly.
This is not a necessity.
The only reason I want to do this is that later on I'm going to need to be able to read the script and
understand what the purpose is of each of the keys in the keys array by taking all the keys out and
assign them to variables and taking all the arguments out and assign them to variables makes it a lot
easier to understand the purpose of each key that you're passing in and the purpose of each value you
are passing it.
Because now I can look at this argument or this variable name right here, read it and say, okay,
it's called you to assign incremented number two.
And immediately I can read that and understand.
Oh, okay.
The first key that I provide to this script is supposed to be the key where I want to assign the incremented
number to.
Again, this is not a necessity.
It's just to help us understand the purpose of each of the keys and each of the arguments that we're
going to provide to our scripts, help us understand their purpose at some point in the future.
All right.
After that, we're going to write our logic.
And then we're also, of course, not going to forget the return of value in our script if we need to.
Now that we've gone through a little bit of this process and undo these changes.
Let's start to actually write the script itself.
So inside of client?
Yes.
Under this script section.
I'm going to add in a new you right here.
Of increment view.
This will be defined scripts.
We're going to put in a number of ease of three this time, because as we just looked at, we went through
this little design phase right here.
We recognize that there are three keys that we are going to need to access.
That's why we are putting three.
Right.
Then we're going to list out our script.
As a multi-line string.
Now our script this time around, a little bit more complicated, but you'll be able to understand what
is going on.
So inside the script, the first thing I'm going to do, as I showed right here for step number two,
we're going to take all the keys are the keys array and we're going to assign them to very well labeled.
Variable names.
So I'm going to say my first key is supposed to be my items for use key.
That's going to come from key.
Is it one?
Then items key.
That's going to use it to.
Items by view's key.
That's going to be keys three.
Now once again, just repeat by looking at the script, it's now very clear to me what the first three
keys are supposed to be.
Whenever I want to run the scripts.
I now understand by just looking at this.
Okay.
The first key is supposed to be a reference to the items of use key.
Then the item key hash.
And then are items by view's sorted.
Set.
Then after that up, that should be local right there.
That's better.
I'm going to repeat that same process for all the different arguments that we're going to receive.
So my first argument that I'm going to receive into my script is going to be the item ID and then the
user ID.
That's RGV at one.
At two.
I just I know I've said this several times now, but just to repeat now, whenever I look at my script,
I very clearly understand that the first argument I provide is supposed to be an item, is supposed
to be a user ID.
Now that we've done all of this work right here, we can write out the actual script now.
The actual script, what we're trying to actually do inside this thing is exactly the same logic we
have right here.
So we want to do a fad.
Remember, that is how we try to add an element to a hyper log log.
We're going to add in the hyper log log stored at whatever key this is.
And we're trying to add the value of the user ID.
We're then going to take a look at whether or not the hyper log log had an element added to it inserted.
If you will recall, back to hyper log logs.
If we actually inserted this user ID, this is the first time this person has looked at this item.
We're going to get back a one.
Otherwise, we're going to get back a zero.
So we need to look at that value.
And say, okay, is it one or is it zero?
And then based upon that, we're going to do an H anchor by and a Z anchor by.
So we need to translate exactly the same logic we have right here into plain Lua.
So that's going to end up looking like local inserted is the reddest skull you have at.
And then the arguments to RPF, that is going to be the key where our hyper log log is stored.
It is stored at items.
We use key.
And the value that we are trying to add is the user ID.
Well then take a look at whatever got returns.
So the value of inserted, remember, inserted is going to be either a one or it's going to be a zero.
And also recall something I told you about in Lua a little bit ago.
In Lua, the value zero is truth.
So if we just do the equivalent, the JavaScript code that we have right now, if we just say if inserted,
then this is always going to evaluate to be true.
Because if inserted is one, we're going to enter the if statement and if zero is inserted is zero.
We are also going to enter the statement because inlet zero is considered to be tricky.
We instead have to do a very specific check here.
We have to say if inserted is specifically equal to one, then that means that we just added in this
user ID.
You are hyper log log.
And if that's the case, then we want to do the H in Kirby and the Z anchor by.
That would be the Red Skull.
H inker by.
We want to increment a value on our items cash.
We specifically want to think about the views property there.
We want to incremented by one.
And we also wanted you a anchor by.
We want to increment a value stored at items by use key.
Or at least that's where the sorted set is.
We want to change the score of a member there by one.
And we want to change the score of the member.
Item ID.
And that's it.
That's our script.
Now in this case, there's not really anything we need to return, no value that we want to get back,
but we don't really need to return anything in this particular case.
But we obviously could if we wanted to.
That's the script.
Now we're going to define those two other options transform arguments and transform reply.
So after the closing little quotes of my scripts, I'm going to add and transform arguments.
And remember, the arguments to this thing are going to be whatever arguments we want to pass through
or we want to pass to our actual function.
Or is it?
Right here.
So it's going to be the arguments are going to be provided through the function that is tied to our
client library.
So for us, we want to provide arguments.
Of our.
What's going to be the itemized.
And the user ID those are both can be strengths.
So then we have to return.
All the different arguments that we want to provide to the evolution commands number.
This array right here is going to be taken.
And no Dennis is going to do a evaluation of the script ID then three because that is what we provided
to a number of GIs right here.
And then it will take this entire array, all the strings inside there, they all have to be strings.
And it's going to be pretty much put each element in there.
Right after that three.
So after the three we want to have first.
Our items views key agenda items key than the items five use key than the item D and then the user ID.
We need to put the true values that we want for each of those keys and arguments into this array right
here.
Now for the three different keys.
Remember, we have our key generating functions, so we're going to use those to produce the three different
keys.
Get those key generating functions.
I'm going to go back a bit of use that.
Yes.
We're going to copy our import statement up here at the top and services keys.
Well, then go back over to client.
Yes.
I'm going to paste the import at the top.
Now we can put in our three different keys.
And if you need a reminder on how we use these three different functions items views key, which is
the first one we have to provide.
Is going to be called with the item ID.
And the second one is going to be our items key.
Which needs an item ID.
Then our items by these key.
And that doesn't take in an ID.
Then we have to put in the item ID itself and then the user ID.
Now I know this step right here is confusing.
So once again, let's just kind of reiterate what's going on.
Each of these key generating functions is going to generate a string.
This first one is going to give us a string of something like whatever this key generating function
produced, I don't know, is something like items the use pounds and then the item is.
The next one will give us a string of something like items lb and then the ID.
And then this one is something like items.
Use the sorted sets, whatever key that is actually at.
And then the item idea is going to be the of course, the ID.
There'll be a string like SDF.
And then we get whatever our user ideas we want you.
One, two, three.
So those are the actual strings that are going to be generated whenever transform arguments gets called.
So this array right here is going to be taken and again, each element is going to be appended onto
shore.
We'll end up with.
You've all saw the script idea three and then the first key.
Then the second key.
Then the third key.
Then our item ID and then the user ID.
And that's it.
Now onto our last up here.
Last up is we have to define.
The Transform reply function.
Now in this case, transform reply.
We are not, actually.
Returning any value from our Lewis scripts.
So in this case, there's no value to receive.
Nothing to pass in response.
Nothing for us to return.
So we can just leave it entirely empty.
Okay.
Once again, I know this has been tedious.
I know this is really confusing stuff.
There's just a lot of different moving parts.
And I know probably in particular this transform arguments function is pretty nasty.
So having said all that, let's save this.
The last thing we have to do is go back to which of these sorts.
And now that we've got this super fancy script put together, we no longer have to write out all this
JavaScript code.
Instead, we can just use.
The brand new function that we have tied to our clients.
And that new function is client dot increment view.
And any time we call this thing, we have to pass in the item ID and the user ID.
So we will put in item ID and user ID.
And that's it.
We no longer need the imports in here anymore, so I'll delete those as well.
And I don't really need the notes at the bottom so I can delete those too.
Well, this file definitely looks much more compact than what it looked like before.
But remember, all we've really done here is hidden the logic somewhere else in our application.
We're still going through all the different logic, all the different commands.
We are just writing them out in Lua.
So even though this file looks much more clean, did we actually have a net benefit or net gain?
I don't know.
It's really up to your opinion to decide whether or not hiding away complexity in Lua scripts is worth
it.
All right.
Having said all that time to test this thing.
So going to save all these different files.
I'm going to make sure my server is not throwing any errors.
I'm going to go back over to my application.
I'm going to go down to the bottom and down here.
I should be able to click on one of these items and have a view still be added to it.
Remember, we are still checking for uniqueness.
So to really make sure that everything is working as expected, I would recommend logging out and signing
up for a.
New account.
It has not viewed any of those items before.
I just created a new account in if I now go and look at newest chair and then come back to this page,
it should go up to 31 views.
I'll click.
I'm going to go back.
Hey.
31 views.
Now, if I go there again.
And then back.
It's still at 31, which is what I want.
I'll try this on popular tour as well as the popular chair.
It was eight.
Now it's nine.
I go there again.
It does not get incremented again.
A long process, but we did it.
Now, at this point, if you have any heirs or if it looks like the views are not being incremented,
I would recommend you come back over to your terminal and take a look at any errors that you might see
over here.
You will probably see an error that looks like the one that I currently have here that is being thrown
by the dashboard page.
This one right here.
That's why we're seeing I am seeing that error.
So if you see something it says cannot do structure property of items of undefined only expected.
If you see any other error, that's the issue.
And if you see any other error, I can just about guarantee you that you have a typo somewhere in this
Lewis script right here.
So as a first point of debugging, I really, really recommend you take a look at every line in here
very closely.
My editor, of course, is not applying any.
Syntax highlighting or anything, any validation to the Lewis script because it's all being stored inside
of a string.
So again, really recommend you triple check this thing to make sure all the syntax is correct.
Well, we have gotten through scripts and we've seen a pretty basic use of them and a little bit more
complex use them as well.
We are not done with scripts.
However, we are going to eventually use them to implement a little bit of better concurrency handling
inside of our application.
So don't forget anything about scripts.
We're going to need to use them again very shortly.