In this video, we're going to get a brief overview on the Lua programming language.
As I mentioned just a moment ago, if you don't know anything about Lua, totally fine.
If you already have experience with it, feel free to skip over this video and understand Lula.
We're just going to run a little bit of Lula code.
There are just a couple of topics I want you to be aware of.
You are already familiar with Python or JavaScript, or to be honest with you, just about any language
you're going to pick up Lula in a handful of minutes, or at least as much as you need to know to work
with Redis that to run some Lua.
I'm going to do a Google search or online Lua.
On all the different search results right here.
You're going to see a variety of different websites that allow you to write out some Lua and execute
it and then see the results.
I'm going to use the first one on this list at tutorials points, but you can use any of these different
execution tools that you want to.
Okay.
So I'm at tutorials point.
I'm going to write out some amount of Lua code on the left hand side.
We're then going to click on the X key button and see the result on the right.
The first thing we're going to take a look at is just printing out values.
We can do something equivalent to a JavaScript console.log.
With a print statement I can print one, two, three.
And I'll see the results over here.
We can create strings.
With single quotes or double quotes.
We can create variables by using the local keyword.
So if I ever want to make a new variable, I would write out local some and then assign it some value.
In this case, one plus one.
And then I can make use of that variable as any other kind of variable in any other language.
If you ever forget to put on the local keyboard right here, this code is still going to work, but
it's going to create a global variable instead.
In Lua, we want to avoid global variables as much as possible, and in particular in Redis.
If you ever tried to create a global variable, your script will throw in air.
So in short, whenever you create a new variable for the very first time, you will use the local keyword.
After the variable has been declared, you can then assign that a new value without using local.
It's just for the initial declaration.
All right.
Next up.
We've finished the execution here.
It's taking a while.
Come on, you thing.
There we go.
Next up, simple if statements.
But a right out in a statement.
Give me a simple if we do not have to use parentheses, but you can if you want to, then we can do
something like say if some is greater than zero then and then terminate it with an end.
So in JavaScript we would have really braces right there and right there in Lua we instead have a them
and an end.
Inside of the if statement, we can then do whatever we wish.
I might put in something like some is greater than zero.
Very good.
If you want to check to see if the value is not equal to something we can use.
Still day equals like so.
So if not equal to zero.
Then do something.
Is not.
Oh, come on.
Thumb is not equal to zero.
There we go.
Again today equals is any time we want to see if a value is not equal to something in JavaScript.
That would of course be something like not equals.
Like so.
All right.
One last little simple comparison here.
If you want to see if a value is equal to something, we use double equals.
So if some is equal to zero and.
Whatever.
Let's move on.
Okay.
Now, here's where things get a little bit more interesting.
Something to just be aware of.
You might recall that in JavaScript, in some other languages, the value of zero is treated as false.
So in JavaScript, if we did something like if zero.
Then something in JavaScript.
We would never get into the body of this if statement.
But Lua is very different in Lua.
Zero is treated as each worthy value.
Same thing for empty string as well.
So if I did something like if zero print euro is true thi.
I will see euro is truly again, little bit unexpected if you're coming from the JavaScript world.
We can do the same thing with a empty string.
I'll do if zero and empty string.
Notice how to do an and we do not make use of the JavaScript ampersand.
Instead it's just the p word.
And.
And so I still see at zero is trippy.
Finally, last little variation I want to look at right now, actually, two more very quickly.
We ever want to specifically mention the values, false or true?
It's just the false or true keywords.
So I could say if false or not true.
In this case, false is a false boolean value.
True is tricky.
I'm using an operator here and we use not instead of the JavaScript exclamation.
Any time we want to flip a boolean value, this would evaluate to false or false for that part right
there.
All right.
Now, here's the last one for this video.
In Lua, we do not have null or undefined.
Instead we have nil.
But nil is very similar to null or undefined as we are used to it in JavaScript.
Nil is treated as a false value.
If we did something like if nil.
Then we will never reach the print statement right here.
I will not see.
Won't run.
Okay.
So that's just a little bit around the basics of Lua.
So printing numbers, strings, variable declaration.
We then seen if statements which are going to use if then and we've seen a couple of different comparison
operators.
There's just one or two more topics I want to take a look at and then that's pretty much it for Lua.
Like I said, our use of Lua in Redis is always going to be a very, very simple.