The next topic we're going to look at is arrays.
In Lua, we can create an array that's very similar to a JavaScript array with one very important difference.
First, I'm going to write out a array literal right here on the very first line.
Let's say local colors is curly braces.
Red, green.
I blew.
The difference here is not the fact that we're using curly braces.
The difference is how we access elements inside the array.
So in JavaScript, if you're white writing JavaScript right now, we would do colors at zero to get
the very first elements.
But Lua things are different.
The very first element has an index of one completely different.
So please pay attention to that.
Please keep that in mind as you are trying to access elements in an array in Lua, first element is
one and therefore the second is two, three, four and so on.
Lua arrays are one indexed JavaScript arrays are zero indexed.
If I do a print on colors at one.
I will see Red.
Yep.
There we go.
Right there.
Next up, we can print out the number of elements inside of an array with pounds and then the name of
the array.
That will show me three.
And then if we ever want to add in an element to the end of an array, we can use a built in function
called insert.
I'm going to run table, not inserts and put in colors and orange.
This will add in a brand new element to the very end of colors.
But now, if I do a print on colors at four, I should see that new element I just added, which is
orange and yup.
There it is right there.
Next up, very common operation we do around arrays is iterate through all the elements and work with
the elements in some way.
Write out a or loop in Lua we're going to write for.
An I and a B.
In I pears.
Others.
Well, then put in the key word do and end like so.
And inside the for loop.
I'm going to print out I and be.
Pairs is used to iterate through all the different keys and values inside of an array.
Really the indexes and the values the indexes are going to be assigned to this variable AI and each
element will be assigned to the.
If I now run this, we'll see index one, two, three and four with values of red, green, blue and
orange.
Okay.
So that's pretty much it.
That's all we need to know around a raise for right now.
Naturally, there is a lot more around arrays to understand the loop, but for what we are going to
be doing, this is pretty much good enough.
Lastly, I want to mention just one more time.
Please don't forget that arrays are one index as opposed to JavaScript in many other languages where
they are zero indexed instead.