Just one or two more.
Very quickly, hot topics.
First, we saw a for loop in the last video where we can iterate through all the different elements
in an array.
In some cases, we might want to write out a for loop where we are not iterating through an array.
We might instead want to have some generic balance, maybe iterate from, say, one up to five or ten
up to 20 or something like that.
Right now, if we're like that in Lua, we can do four I equals and we're going to put in a start value
and an end value.
If I put in, I am a RN.
And print out the value of I.
I will start off at five and then go all the way up to and including ten.
If I run that I will see a print up of I six, seven, eight, nine, ten any second now.
There we go.
We'll use this every now and then any time we want to iterate through just some number of very specific
elements or I should say numbers.
All right.
Last topic we're going to go over right now is how we create something very similar to an object in
Lua.
Now, objects are not referred to as objects in the but instead we refer to them as tables or associative
arrays.
The syntax around them is very, very similar to arrays, which we looked at just a moment ago.
And as a matter of fact, an array can function as a table.
It is a little bit confusing, but at the end of the day, what we want to keep in mind is that a Lua
table is like a US object, roughly similar.
All right, so I'm going to make a new local variable called user.
I'm going to declare a associative array or a table by putting in curly braces, and then I will list
out some number of key value pairs inside of here.
I will say that my user has an ID of a one.
And a name.
Samantha.
Oki of id value of A1 of name value of Samantha noticed that you separate the keys and the values.
We do not use a colon as we do in JavaScript.
Instead we use an equal sign.
Now, if I ever want to access a element inside of here, we can do a user at ID.
And I get a one right there.
Another very common operation that we're going to want to do all the time is iterate through all the
keys and values inside of a table.
We can use a very similar for loop to what we used a little bit to go around an array with one important
difference.
I'm going to write out 4kb in and then pairs user.
I'll print out K and B.
So the big difference here is the fact that we're using a slightly different function called pairs.
So if we were working with an array and we're going to use our pairs, if we are working with something
that has e value pairs inside of it, we'll use simply pairs instead.
A good pneumonic or way to remember this is think of the AI in here as representing integer and arrays
are integer index.
I'm going to use pairs here.
I'm going to run this.
And we should see the ID and the value name.
And Samantha.
There are more similarities around tables and arrays than at what I'm going into here.
But again, not super relevant for what we are doing with Redis at this point, believe it or not.
We pretty much know enough to write out some interesting scripts with Lua inside of Redis.
We're going to kind of pause the Lua discussion here as far as the basics of Lua goes, and we're going
to move on to the world of how we use Lua in it.
Reddit's very last thing I want to mention really quickly is naturally, if you ever get stuck writing
any Lua code, just use Google.
There are a tremendous number of technologies that use Lua as a scripting language.
Just about every single simple operation you can imagine, like iterating through all the elements of
an array or stuff like that.
There will be a ton of blog posts and questions and whatnot asked you can very easily search for on
Google.
So just keep that in mind if you ever get stuck.