I think we now understand the basics of Lua.
So in this video, we're going to focus on how we actually write out a script and execute it with Redis.
I've gone back over to our book Cloud and I've made a new notebook called Lua Scripts.
Let's take a look at a couple of diagrams to understand how we run a script.
Well, then come back over here and get started.
Okay.
So the script running process is broken up into two separate steps.
In step one, we're going to write our script and send it off to Redis.
So on our server, we'll write our scripts, then load the script by using a command called Script Load.
When we send the script over to read us, it's going to store that scripts so that we can run it at
some point in time in the future.
And it's going to send us an idea for the script that we just sent.
The script idea is going to come back on to us on the server and we're going to hold onto that ID that
we can tell us at some point in time in the future.
Go find the script with this ID and try to run it.
We only have to do this one single time for any given script.
You only have to load it up once.
Once we have loaded that script, we can execute it as many times as we wish.
Once the script has been loaded, at some point in time, the future, we're going to want to, of course,
execute it, to run the scripts.
We're going to run another command called Evil Shaw, and we're going to put in the idea or our script
that we got back during that previous step.
Once we send the e-mail shore command readies is going to find the script we had previously sent is
going to execute it.
It's going to find whatever value we return from the script.
Take that value and then send it back to our server.
We can take that return value and use it for whatever we want.
We are allowed to return numbers, strings, people's arrays.
Just about every kind of data structure from Lua can be returned and sent back over to our server.
Okay.
So at this point in time, let's try to actually go through these two steps.
Let's try to write a script.
We're going to load it and then execute it using eval shop.
Back over Ann Arbor, Xcloud.
I'm going to load a script with script load, and then I'm going to write out my entire Lewis script
inside of single quotes.
Right now, I'm going to have my script be very simply, return one plus one.
A couple of things to note here.
First, notice that I am wrapping the entire script with quotes.
If for some reason my Lua code asked to include a string on its own, I can use double quotes inside
there.
So this would return a string of one plus one.
Second notice.
So I'm actually using the return keyword.
When you are executing a script, if you want to actually return a value, you must use the return keyword.
If you don't have a return anywhere inside of your Lua code, no value will be sent back over to your
server.
All right, I'm going to run this.
And then there is my ID for that script right there.
Now I would save this idea and use it any time I want to execute the script of one plus one.
Let's try running it right now.
I'm going to add in a brand new code cell.
And inside here, I'll do an evil.
Oh, that's just one word.
I then put in my ID so I'm going to copy it from up here and paste it in.
And then before you run this, one very important step right after this is right here, I'm going to
put in a space and then add a zero.
Notice the zero right there.
Don't forget that.
Zero.
I'll then run this.
And there we go.
That's the results.
You which is, of course, the results of doing return one plus one.
If I wanted to update my script in some way, I could change it to say return and.
Plus ten.
And if I wanted to run this, I would now have to do another load.
I'll do that right now.
I'm going to get back a completely different ID.
So if I wanted to run the new script, I would have to copy that ID.
Put it down here at the e-mail shop.
Make sure I still have a zero.
Right after it.
And I can run that and I get 20.
All right.
So in essence, not too bad, right?
Like, it's pretty straightforward to load a script and run it.
But as it turns out, there are a couple of things in here that start to get really, really nasty little
pieces of trivia that you need to be aware of.
Let's start to focus on some little odds and ends in the next video.