We've now got an example of defining and executing a script.
Now we're going to go into a little bit more detail.
And I first want to begin by giving you a very quick example.
I want you to imagine a scenario that would be a little bit challenging to deal with, using only the
techniques we have learned so far around scripts.
Okay.
So here's the example, and this is not something we would do in a normal application.
I want to show you why this is a problem and then we'll figure out how we can use some more features
around scripts to solve it.
We're going to imagine that in our application.
It's really important that we have the ability to add one to a number in Redis.
And it's really important to us for some reason you define this inside of a script.
So in our app, we might decide to have one script defined where we do one plus one and then another
script to find for one, plus do another for one plus three, one plus for one plus five, one plus
six, and so on.
These are each defined as separate scripts that we have to load up and then execute.
Now, of course, this would be really, really tedious.
One separate script for just each different variation of this little number right here.
Surely there's a better way to do that.
And of course there is.
So we could use a technique around scripts referred to as providing arguments.
And this is very similar nature to providing arguments to a function.
The only difference is that the arguments are loose scripts.
So let's look at an example.
So here's what we would do.
We would change up our script a little bit to be return one plus and then something called a RGV.
A RGV is a global variable defined inside of our lowest script.
It's short for arguments.
It is an array, it's a reference, or it contains all the different arguments that we provide to our
script when we execute it.
So every single time we execute our script, we can provide a different number, the different quantity
or different arguments altogether.
To provide arguments.
We're going to run our email short commands with the idea of our scripts.
We're still going to put in zero, and I'll tell you why that is and a little bit, and then we'll provide
all the arguments after that zero.
If we have to provide multiple different arguments, we'll just list them all out one by one.
We might do one, two, three, four, and so on.
Each argument will be provided as a string, even if it is supposed to represent a number.
So in our case, these are definitely supposed to be numbers, but we must provide them as strings.
Otherwise, we'll get an error when we try to run our script.
Then to access these arguments inside of our scripts, we'll take a look at the RGV array.
So if we do RGV at one, that means get the very first argument that is provided to our script when
it gets executed.
So in this case, we can imagine that our first argument is the string one.
So we would replace this with the string one.
If we did a rugby to.
We'd be looking for the second element.
That'd be a string of two.
We can imagine a behind the scenes.
That's kind of what's happening.
Now the V variable right here, as I mentioned, it is a global variable.
So we don't have to define it.
We don't have to initialize it.
You can kind of imagine that what's going on by the scenes is Redis is taking this list of arguments
right here and defining an array for us.
Like so putting in one, two, three, four and so on.
All right, so arguments around scripts are extremely useful.
We can use them all the time, any time we want to customize our script in some way, not actually play
with these things.
Let's go back over to our book and write out a very fast example.
We're going to do exactly this thing right here.
I want to add one to some argument that we're going to provide to our scripts.
The back over here.
I'm going to go to our return statement and I'm going to change the second one with a RGV one.
Now remember, when we provide our arguments to the execute command or even offshore, they must be
provided as strings and they show up in our script as strings as well.
So if we ran our command, as it stands right now or ran the script, this would pretty much be one
plus one as a string.
And that's probably not what we want.
We want to actually add one to the number one.
So we need to take that argument.
And pass it into a number.
You pass a string into a number in Lua?
I use the two number function.
Notice that number here is lowercase.
So two number, all lowercase.
All right, I'm going to execute the load script.
Well, then take the ID, we get back.
I'm going to paste it down here at the evil shore.
And then still going to leave in the zero right here.
And again, we'll discuss what that zero is all about in a little bit.
And then right after that, I'm going to provide my argument to the script.
So this will be the value put in for RGV at one right there.
And once again, I'm going to provide it as a string.
So I going to put in a string of 100.
If I run that, I get back return value of 1 to 1.
As a guess and ends up looking something like that right there.
As one more very quick example, I want to try expanding our script here just a little bit.
In addition to adding in the first argument, I want to try adding the second argument as well.
So I'm going to put in another plus two number and then RGV and this time the second element.
I'm going to load that script.
But the ID down here.
And then add in a second argument, this time of 201.
That's when I get back.
301 Perfect.
Okay.
So that's how we provide arguments and we're going to provide arguments any time we want to customize
a script's execution in some way.
Now onto a little bit related topic related to the zero right here.
We're going to figure out what that is all about.
And we're going to see one major limitation that's extremely important to understand around scripts,
all that in the next video.