A couple of videos ago I told you that we use Lewis scripts to run, read us commands.
So inside of a Lewis script, we can do a git or a set or an H, get all we could do an L range and
so on.
All the range commands we've learned about so far can be executed from within a script.
And the nice thing about this is that there is no delay in the script execution and the words we don't
run the command and then like pause execution of the script or anything like that.
We run the command at the result back immediately and we can work with that data before anything else
occurs in Redis.
And that's a key aspect of how we're going to fix a couple of concurrency issues later on.
Okay.
So let's take a look at how we actually run a command.
But to run a red light command, we're going to use a built in object called Redis.
We're going to run the call method on it as the first arguments we're going to put in the name of the
command we want to run.
Now we can provide any arguments we want to give to the command right after that.
In this case, I'd be trying to get the key of color.
And before I say another word, I got to tell you something extremely important.
This is going to be the entire focus of this video.
As short as this script is right here, it has a very big issue.
So you're not going to want to run a script like this in production.
Tell you what the issue is in just 1/2.
But first, let's try running this thing as is.
Okay.
So back over here.
Right before I do my script load, I'm going to set color to be red.
So we definitely have a value there.
Then on my load statement, I'm going to change this to return.
Write a stock call.
I want to provide a string here.
So going to use double quotes so I don't conflict with the single quotes outside the entire script.
I'm going to do a get on color.
I'm going to load that.
There's my ID.
I'm going to pass the I.D. down here.
And then, as usual, once again, put in that zero.
I run this and I get back a string of red.
Okay, well, that definitely works.
We can use Lola to run his commands.
Now, let me tell you what the issue is right here.
And again, this is the entire point of this particular video.
Any time that we are trying to access any value inside of Redis.
In other words, any time we try to run a command and access or set the value of any key whatsoever,
those keys need to be provided ahead of time.
The short commands.
So the issue with this script right here is that I ran you belshaw without telling Redis exactly what
keys I plan to access inside the script.
I just went ahead and accessed the key of color without telling you all about it.
And that's the issue.
That's what we don't want to do.
So anytime we want to access any key whatsoever inside of radius from inside of a script, we're going
to use a technique very similar to what we just saw a moment ago around arguments.
So in this case, if we want to do a reticent call on gifts, you have to provide a key right there
rather than writing in the key as a simple string.
I'm going to access another built in global array called Keys.
I'm going to access keys at one.
And then when I run my e-mail shore command, I'm going to still put in the ID.
I'm going to put in the number one right here to tell you belshaw that I'm about to give it one key
that I am going to want to access.
In this case, the key is color.
You can imagine that when the script runs red, this is going to define a global array for us.
That has a single element inside of its.
With a string of color.
You might be kind of curious about the one right here.
Again, that's going to be the number of keys we're about to list in this command.
So if I wanted to access both the keys of color and maybe items, I would put in a two right there.
The entire purpose of that number is to just make it clear which the strings right here are supposed
to be keys we want to access and therefore should be listed inside this keys array versus arguments
that we might want to access.
If I put in, say, a four and a six later on as arguments.
So in this case, these two elements would be added into the keys array or in six would be added into
the array, which we learned about in the last video.
Now, I got to just tell you this one more time, because it's so important, so critical.
Any time you want to access any key, so get data or set data, you must provide the key as an arguments.
And the effect of that is it means that you can't.
And this is a really important restriction around scripts.
We cannot, unfortunately.
Have a script, generate some keys dynamically that we want to work with.
So there will never be a point in time where you might say store some keys inside of a red list and
then inside of a script, try to access that list, get out all those keys, and then look those keys
up inside the script.
We're not going to do that because that would require us to dynamically generate some keys.
In other words, the Keys store inside the list while we are running the scripts.
Every key we want to access must be provided as an argument to show.
The reason I'm making such a big deal about this is that, as we just saw, you can run a script where
you access a key that you don't mention inside of email, so you're not going to see an error.
It's behind the scenes.
That stuff is going to start to get a little bit buggy and eventually cause issues down the line.
Okay.
So let's see some examples of defining a key ahead of time and providing it to evaluate your.
So let's in a replicator fix up this example right here.
I want to provide a key of color to al-Qaeda because I'm now providing a key.
I need to change that zero to a one to say on about to provide one key right here and then inside my
script, rather than directly accessing color, I would do keys at one.
Now I will once again load the scripts.
But in the new ID business and I still get red.
All right.
So we've now learned about the array and the keys array.
Those are the two tricky topics around scripts.
So from here on out, it's pretty much, hey, we just need to figure out what we might want to do with
scripts and how we actually write Lua code effectively.
So now we get to kind of get to the interesting things around scripts in just a moment.