But when do we want to use a Lewis script?
I think there are a couple of different scenarios where you might want to use a Louis script to enhance
your application.
The first is any time you want to limit the amount of data exchanged between your server and Redis,
and we saw a little small example of that back over here with this example.
So we had a sorted set.
We wanted to run a query on the set that was not supported out of the box by Redis.
We could easily do something like this by using a Lewis script instead.
We could make sure that we are only returning the elements inside the sorted set that we actually care
about.
Another example of where we might want to use a script is solving some different concurrency issues.
I'm going to give you a good example on this in just a little bit.
Third, any time we want to minimize the number of roundtrips between our server and readies, you might
imagine that in some scenario we might want to get a couple of keys and then depending upon their value,
we might want to fetch a couple more.
And depending upon those values, we might want to fetch more keys every single time we reach out and
get some data from Reddit.
It takes some amount of time to process that request and get the data back over to our server.
So if we ever have a scenario where we are making many round trips over treaties as a part of one single
operation, we could put all that code inside of a Lewis script instead and run all that code on Redis
as opposed to shipping data back over to our server.
And then be on that.
Well, scripts are really flexible, and you could definitely think of your own uses as well.
All right.
Now, a couple scenarios where you might not want to use scripts or just some downsides to be aware
of.
The first and biggest downside, absolutely, is the fact that we need to know all of our keys ahead
of time for when we run that evolution command.
So we cannot dynamically generate a key inside of our scripts.
We must provide every key that we ever planned to access to evolution.
That's a big downside.
And it really cuts down on the number of useful or really use cases around scripts.
Second, it's really tough to test scripts.
You might have an automated testing framework that you use for your server, but chances are it's only
meant to run code related to your server's language.
In the case of a Lewis script, well, we would have to add in some additional tooling to test our scripts.
Related to number two is the fact that with Lua we're working with a dynamic, weakly typed language
on our server.
For our e-commerce application, we're using TypeScript.
And a big benefit to that is that we get typed checking, which definitely enhances productivity and
helps us catch errors.
As soon as we start adding in Lewis scripts, we're losing out on that typing for some logic that might
be really critical to our application.
Definitely a downside.
And then related to number two and number three.
Well, we just have to learn and understand another language which has its own burden as well.
I gave you a very quick overview on Lua and it is easy to learn, but once again, it's just another
thing to learn.
Another thing to worry about.
Definitely have to keep that in mind.
All right, so where are we going to use scripts on our E commerce application?
Well, I think that there is a very small example of case number three right here.
Where we are doing a round trip to our server that we might be able to minimize just one single script.
And that means that we only have to do one single request to Redis us as opposed to two inside of our
application.
The back inside my code editor.
I'm going to find our SC services.
Mary's used to.
Yes.
File.
Right here is our increment view function.
You might recall that inside of here we ran one command dpf at.
That's going to make a request off to us.
We then have to wait for the response from that before we then possibly do a follow up right here.
That means that to increment of you, which is going to be happening potentially thousands and thousands
of times per second inside of application, depending upon how many people are accessing our app.
At any given time, we have to do one round trip over to Redis no matter what.
And then if the user has not visited that page before, we're doing an additional round trip.
So we might be able to use a loose script to condense all this down to one single request off to Redis
as opposed to potentially the two that is right now.
Let's take a look at replacing all this logic with the script in just a moment.