Just a moment ago, I mentioned that we were going to replace the contents of increment view with a
custom Lewis script.
We are going to do that.
But first we're going to do a very quick aside.
I want to show you how we typically make use of Lewis scripts inside of a real project.
We're going to write a script.
We're going to integrate it into the node.
Read a client that we are using.
This is going to be a script unrelated to increment view.
Once we understand, the entire process will then come back to increment view and replace this logic
with a script.
A couple of diagrams to understand how we implement custom scripts with a node Redis library that we
are using to connect to Redis.
The first thing I want to point out is that making use of script load and email shore is just a little
bit tedious, only because we have to first call a script, load it back that ID and then hold onto
it until we eventually want to use it with email shore.
So implementing that inside of our code base.
Well, of course, it's not the worst thing in the world, but it's just an extra little step for us
to go through it, rather than forcing us to make use of script, load and email evolution directly.
A lot of different reticent client libraries such as Node Redis is the one we are using as some advanced
features for automating the process of doing script, load and evaluation.
So what we're going to focus on in this video is what that process looks like.
They help you understand this process?
We are going to do this little side topic, as I mentioned just a moment ago.
But here's our goal for right now.
I want to use our Rita's clients.
I want to somehow add on a custom function to it called Add one and store.
This function does not yet exist.
It doesn't exist at all.
We are going to implement this custom function and tie it to our client by using a Lewis script.
This add one and store function is going to behave very simply.
We're going to pass in a key and a number.
Whatever number we pass in, right here is the second argument.
We're going to add one to it's inside of a Lua script.
So inside of Redis, we're going to add one to that number.
We're then going to store the results at a key of books.
Colon counts in this case or any other key that we choose to pass in right there.
There could be items count or whatever else.
And of course, the five is not hard coded.
If we put in something like this, then I would want to add one to the value of six and store it at
books count.
Let's take a look at how we go through this process.
We're going to break it down into five separate steps.
So step one, we have to decide on a name for the function.
This is not a name that is going to be used inside of us at all scripts in red.
There is no concept of names or anything like that.
We invoke them only by using those identifiers.
We get back whenever we run the emotion command.
The name of the function is just specifically how are we going to run this thing in our JavaScript code?
In this first example we are going through the name of our function is going to be add one and store.
Then the next thing we need to do is write out the script itself.
We then need to figure out how many keys we are going to be providing whenever we run the script.
This is going to be a value that gets passed on to the email shore commands.
In our case, we are only going to be providing one single key.
This one right here.
That's the key where we want to store our computed value.
Then we're going to have one function that's going to take in some different arguments and instruct
no treatise on exactly how to take those arguments that we're providing to our function, one called
Add one and store.
So in other words, how do we take these two arguments right here and pass them on to the email shore
commands?
And then another function that's going to tell Node Redis how to get the result of our script and pass
it or really serialize it into a value that can be used in the rest of our application.
Now I know probably everything I'm showing you so far in particular, these steps right here, and in
particular these last three items.
I know this sounds like confusing stuff only could be using the first time you go through it.
As soon as you have written out a custom script with note readings, everything is going to get a lot
more clear very quickly.
So let's going to end the lecturing at this point.
We're going to take a quick pause, come back, go over to our code editor.
We're going to implement this, add one and store method.