In this video.
We're going to get some more experience with sets by implanting a unique user name system inside of
our e-commerce application.
We're going to do exactly what you see inside this diagram right here.
Whenever a user makes a request to sign up to our application, we're going to check to see if that
username is already in use by taking a look at a set of usernames that we are going to store.
If the username is already present inside the set.
That means that the username is taken and we're going to tell the user sorry but you can't use this
username, but if you want to you can sign up with a different one.
All right.
So let's get started on the implementation.
Back over inside my code editor, I'm going to first find SIRC.
Services.
Various users reports that you will recall that inside of here we did some work on the create user function.
Right before we create a user record here, I think that this would be a reasonable spot for us to do
a little check.
We're going to see.
If the username is already in the set of usernames.
If so, row and error.
Otherwise continue.
So simple.
If statements all we really have to do here.
And when I say see if it's already in the set of usernames I'm talking about, of course, this set
right here which you and I need to create.
In addition, don't forget, after we actually create a user account on that step right there, we then
need to take the username that we just created the account for and add it into the set as well.
So we need to keep on updating that set over time as more and more people sign up to our application.
All right.
So now we understand what we're going to do.
Step one, we need to create a new key function.
But one of those functions that's going to generate this key right here.
We are creating all those different key functions inside of our services.
You start to.
Yes, file the year, you start to yes.
Inside of your I'm going to add in and export a new function called usernames unique key.
Now you'll notice that the key name here is rather long.
I'm doing that because we're actually going to add in another set later on.
Also called Users Your Usernames.
So we got a little bit of a conflict in naming here.
I'll go into more detail why that is later on.
Just right now, just understand that there is a reason that I'm using this kind of really long key
for right now.
All right.
Now that we've got that key function put together, I'm going to go back over to users dots.
I'm going to go to the top.
And import the key function.
Next up inside of creat user.
Will implement every step of this little flaw right here.
But a see if a username is already inside that set of usernames, we can use that as is member command.
I'll do a.
Await client dot s is member.
We're going to look at usernames, unique key and then the value that we want to check where for existence
inside there is adders dot username.
Remember that Atta's object has a username that the user is trying to sign up with no adders but username.
Whenever we call ESAs member, we get back a number either zero or one.
One means that this element already exists inside the set.
Zero means it does not.
I'm going to assign the result of this operation to a variable called exists.
Well then check to see if exists is equal to one in a JavaScript or typescript.
We can do that very simply by just saying if exists.
So if the element already exists inside the set, that means the username is taken.
So we want to throw an error and say something like username is taken.
And otherwise we can just go ahead and continue and create the user account.
After creating the account.
Once again, let's not forget we need to take the username that the user just signed up with an add
it into the set so that nobody else can use it in the future.
So to add an element into the set, we can use the s add command.
So await Poulenc's ad.
User.
Usernames unique.
He.
And I want to add in Adam Scott is her name.
I'm going to clean up the comments.
And that's it.
So now we are enforcing unique usernames inside our application.
Now, the last thing I want to add in here is that there is a very small bug inside of some of the code
we have in this function now.
This is not a bug that you and I are going to run into any time soon, but it is a bug that would start
to arise if our application got to be really popular.
We had a lot of people signing up for usernames or creating new accounts at the same time.
We're going to go into exactly what this bug is in great, great detail in a later section as we start
to talk more about concurrency.
Right now, again, there's a small issue, but we will solve it later on.
Okay.
Let's save this.
We're going to go back over to the browser and test it out to test it in the browser.
Let's first go to our terminal.
We're going to make sure that our server is still running.
If it is not running, remember you can execute npm run dev inside of your project directory at the
terminal.
Well, then go to your local house.
3000.
I'm going to sign up for new accounts.
And the first time I sign up, it should work as long as I'm using a new username that I've never used
before.
I do of course.
Still get a 500 right year.
That's totally fine.
It's a bug we're going to fix up later.
If I now log out and then attempt to sign up again, not sign in, but sign up.
If I try to sign up with the same username, I should now get an error message that says username is
taken.
Perfect.
That means that our set is definitely tracking that unique usernames.
So this definitely looks good.
All right.
Now we've got our first feature out of the way.
Let's move on to our next feature using sets in just a moment.