You get some more experience with SATs, we're going to add in a like system to our application.
To get started, I first want to show you where this a like system really appears inside of our app.
Back over here at our app, I'm at the sign up page.
Remember, only sign up works right now.
I'm going to create a brand new account.
Once I've created the accounts, I'm going to create a new item by going to new at the top right inside.
I'm going to click Submit immediately and I'll see the product that was just created.
So on this page, on the top right hand side, there is a like button.
The number right here is supposed to represent the number of likes that this item has.
And if I click on the like button, that means that I want to like the item.
If I then click it a second time.
I want to.
Unlike the item, that's the first place where we really start to see it.
Likes appear will also see likes appear.
If I click on the see the seller link right here at the very center.
When I click on that link, I'm taken to a seller's profile page.
So on the screen I want to list out all the items that I like, and this person likes the items that
we both like together.
That would be an intersection of these two sets.
And then at the bottom, I want to see a list of all the items that just this person likes, not an
intersection, just the items that this person likes.
All right.
So again, a couple of locations where we are going to see this like system.
To implement this like stuff we're going to do again, exactly what we see in this diagram.
So every single user is going to have their own separate sets.
We might eventually have many, many, many sets, one for every single user.
And that's totally fine and right.
So we can have as many separate sets as we want to have.
Our keys for each individual set will be something like users colon likes out and then the ID of that
particular user.
And then inside assets, we're going to record the item ID that this person likes.
And we spoke about some the different commands we can run.
Yep.
Pretty simple stuff.
All right.
So to get started on the implementation.
Back inside my code editor, I'm going to find the queries like Scott's file.
So we've got a variety of different functions in here.
The two that we're going to focus on in this video are like item and unlike item.
So if we like an item, we want to take that user's ID, we want to find the like sets associated with
them and add the item ID to it.
And for unlike item, we want to take that same user ID on the likes that associated with it and remove
that item ID from the set.
Now to actually access these sets associated with each user ID.
We of course need to create a key function, a function that's going to generate that key right there.
As usual, let's create that key first.
Back inside the services directory, often the key sorts file at the very bottom of this list.
I'll make a new function called user likes e.
This is going to be called with some user ID that will be a string.
And I'm going to return a brand new string of users Berlin likes pound and then dollar sign.
Really?
Braces user ID.
Let's save this.
Go back to what you like, Scott.
Yes.
I'm going to zoom in very quickly and then at the top will add in a couple of different imports.
The first thing we definitely need is our right as clients by will import that from services readies.
You will also need that key function we just put together.
The user likes key.
From Services.
He's.
Now we can start working on like item and unlike item.
In the case of like item, all we have to do once again find the set associated with that user ID and
add an item ID to it.
So I will await.
Wyandotte is sad because we're trying to add an element into a set.
I want to find the set stored at the key user like key and put in the user ID.
And then I want to add the element item ID.
We'll type of their user.
Likes he.
Okay.
So that's it for like item.
And now we're going to do unlike item.
So it's just the exact opposite behavior.
We're going to remove an element instead of adding it over, unlike item.
I will await client SRM.
User likes key user ID and item ID.
Now.
Let's save this file.
I'm going to go back over.
Now, if I refresh the page, I should be able to click on the like button right here.
And unfortunately, it's going to initially appear like nothing is really happening whatsoever, even
though in theory we are definitely maintaining that set now and we are definitely say adding an item
ID into it.
There's still a couple of other elements that have to it put together inside of our application to actually
see a result right here.
So let's take a quick pause.
We'll come back in just a moment and I'll tell you what those other little parts are.