We have started our like system and although we got two functions put together, it still appears like
our like system isn't quite behaving as expected.
So two separate issues in this video.
We're going to solve one and then discuss how to solve the second issue.
The first issue is that if I click on this button, it might change color.
But as soon as I refresh, it goes back to just saying, like when I click on like, I want this item
to stay light.
And when I refresh, it should still say light.
So that's the first problem we need to fix.
Let's tackle that problem right away because that is a pretty easy one.
Back inside my editor.
I'm still inside the livestock file.
There's a function inside if you're called user likes item.
This is the function that determines whether or not that button is going to appear as green or not.
Whenever we refresh the page.
This function needs to return.
True if this user likes that item id.
And false if they don't.
So we can implement this pretty easily.
All we have to do is look at this user user's set of likes and see if this item ID is in its.
For that we can use the s is member command.
So inside this function I will return client.
S is member.
But the user likes he putting in user ID and then item I.D..
All right, let's save that.
Now, if I look back over and I refresh the page, if I click on this button and set this item to be
liked, now it truly is light.
I can refresh and whenever I refresh it stays green.
If I unlike it by clicking the button again and refresh, the item stays unliked.
So this is expected behavior.
This is what we want.
That's good.
That is one problem solved.
Now we're going to move on to the second problem.
The second problem is, as you guessed, if I like this, I want to see that zero right there turn into
a one.
You indicate that at least one person likes this item.
Now fixing up that number and making sure in increments every time someone likes this thing is going
to be a little bit more challenging.
Let me tell you why.
One pinnacle of our like system that we discussed several times is that every separate user is going
to have their own set of liked items.
Here's the set for user 45.
Here's a set for user 32 or 17 for 82 and so on.
If we have a million different users, that means we have a million different sets.
And here's the unfortunate thing.
In Redis, we don't really have a very good built in way to take a look at all these different sets
of which there might be millions or many more and run a query over all them together.
We don't really have a good way of doing that.
Let's imagine that.
I'm trying to see if the item or the number of people who like the item with ID 1195 BE That's the idea
of my chair right here that I'm trying to sell.
It might be that this person down here likes it, so they have that ID inside their set.
But I don't have a way to easily go from this set to this set, this set, the set and so on, and figure
out which out of all these or how many out of all these actually contain that ID That's the issue that
we need to think of a more clever way of figuring out how many users like a very particular item.
And for that, we're going to do a little bit of a head computation.
So let me show you another diagram, help you understand what I mean.
Our solution is going to be very simple, rather than trying to figure out how many people like an item
as someone comes to our landing page or the page for that particular item.
We're going to figure out how many people like an item ahead of time.
Whenever someone likes an item.
So a request comes in saying that user ID 32 wants to like ID 45 as usual.
So exactly what we're doing right now, we're going to add that items ID, that user's set to be 32
right there.
So we add in 45.
That's exactly.
We're currently doing.
But in addition to that, we're going to say if we truly just added this item to the set, if that item
was not liked by this person before, because who knows, we could have accidental duplicate like we
actually added in that ID to the set.
Then let's go and find the items cache and we're going to store the total number of likes as a plain
number on that item's hash.
So I would increment likes from 0 to 1.
And that's it.
This means that whenever someone likes a item, we do have to update the item itself.
In addition to adding this record to the like set, it means a little bit of extra work.
But on the flip side, every time someone wants to take a look at an item, they want to see that item's
profile page.
All we have to do is get this item hash.
We know the number of likes right there so we don't have to do any follow up query and we don't have
to walk over a list of all of our different sets or anything like that, even though it's a little bit
more work up front to update this value.
Reading the data will be significantly, significantly faster, which of course is our primary goal
with Redis.
We're all about performance.
We are all about speed.
Okay.
Now we understand the solution.
Rick, pause right here and come back in just a moment.
We're going to make sure that whenever we like an item or unlike it, we're going to go in.
Also find this item's hash as well.
And we're going to increment or decrement its number of likes.