I'm back inside of our likes not to yes file.
We're going to add in some additional implementation around like item and unlike item.
There's just one little detail here that I want to repeat one more time.
Whenever we get a request for a user to like an item, there's always the possibility we always have
to be aware of this, that a user might click the like button twice in very, very quick succession.
So we might accidentally get two requests in a row where the same user is trying to like the same item.
In this scenario, we would not want to increment likes by two.
We would still want to make sure that we only incremented.
By one way, we're going to handle that is by a little bit of behavior around the s add function.
So remember we are using that right here whenever a user likes an item.
When we call Asad, we're going to get back a number, either zero or one.
I'm going to take the return value of Asad right here and assign it to a variable called inserted.
Inserted is going to be equal to one.
If we truly did just add a new value into our sets, it will be equal to zero if we did not add anything.
That's how we are going to account for two requests coming in in quick succession.
We only want to increment this Lykes value right here inside of the items hash.
When we attempt to add an item into the set and we get back a value of one.
Okay.
So right after inserted, we'll say if inserted.
That's that's pretty much it.
That's going to take care of accidental duplicate requests.
Then inside of here, we want to take a look at this particular item and we want to make sure that's
clear that this thing just got another, like all the items that we are currently storing inside of
bread is already have a like value that starts off at zero that already belongs to all the items and
all the hashes that we have stored inside of lettuce.
All we have to do is take a look at that likes property and increment it by one.
That's pretty much it.
To increment a number stored inside the hash by one.
We can make use of a command that we discussed a while ago.
So backyard Arbuckle out.
Just a quick reminder, there's the H anchor by command.
And this allows us to adjust a value stored inside of a hash very easily.
We can use h anchor by the key for the house we want to look up.
The key inside the house.
So in our case, it would be likes right there.
And then we want to increment by one.
That's how we can make sure that we add one to that.
Like about.
And to actually use that h anchor bike means we are going to have to look up the hash or really the
key where the hash is stored inside of Redis for this particular item ID, that means that we need our
items key function inside of here as well.
Let's go up to the top.
Import.
Items key.
Then down side of our statement, we can do a return.
Client H inker by.
We're going to look at the hash stored at items key.
Item ID.
I want to look at the field inside there of likes and I want to increment it by one.
And that's it.
Now we're going to do the exact, exact opposite operation for unlike item.
We are going to.
On SE run right here.
SRM does a very similar return value as s add.
So it's going to return one if we actually removed this given value.
So if we actually removed that item ID from the users like set.
We'll get back one.
Otherwise we'll get zero if removed and we will return.
Client H.
Anchor by.
Item ski with item ID likes, and this time we are going to increment by negative one to subtract one.
All right, let's save this.
We now flip back over.
Go to our item.
I'm going to refresh really quickly.
I'm then going to click on this thing to unlock it.
And now unfortunately, because I just added in all this code when I was in a like state, when I deselect
it, I'm now subtracting one and I'm going into the negatives now.
So our code does work correctly.
It's just because I implemented this change at a not awkward time.
So I'll tell you what.
Very quickly, just to make sure this thing works, I'm going to sign out.
I'm going to sign back up with a brand new account.
I will make a new item very quickly.
And now if I click on like that should go up to one perfect.
And if I click it again, I go back to zero.
Awesome.
All right, so now we can like and unlike her, as much as we wish.
Well, this looks pretty good.
Now we've got this little bit of a like system put together, really everything related to this main
landing page for an item.
Last thing, if do is take care of the seller profile page as well.
So on this page we need to show items that I like and this person likes.
Same thing down here, except we're going to show just the items that this person likes.
Let's take care of these last two sections in just a moment.