Let's get started on some queries that are going to fill in the data for these two sections.
We're going to first focus on running items in this second section.
So this should show all the items that just this person likes to implement that query.
Back inside of our editor, we will find the liked items function.
This function needs to do two separate things.
You separate steps.
Step number one, we're going to fetch all the item.
IDs from this users liked sets.
And when I say this user, I'm talking about the person with that user ID.
So it's number one or it's going to get all the ideas out of their like sets.
Then in step number two, we're going to fetch all the item hashes with those IDs.
And we're going to return as a ray.
Now, step number two might sound a little bit challenging, but recall that we've actually already
put that entire step together in an earlier video.
You might recall that back inside the queries items folder, there's the items dots file.
We spent a little bit of time talking about this get items function inside of here.
We put together some code that would take an array of IDs and then fetch all those different hashes
and return them as an array.
And most importantly, we implemented this step using a pipeline which is an efficient way to send multiple
queries off to read us at the exact same time.
We don't really have to re-implement.
Step number two, we can just reuse that git items function that we had already created.
All we really have to do is get all the elements inside of our set, pass them off to get items, and
that's it.
With that in mind, let's get started right away.
At the very top, I'm going to first import.
Yet items.
From items.
Then to find all the item IDs inside this user's like set we'll do a concert IDs is await client dot
and then as a very quick reminder here, one of the commands we have available to us to work with hashes.
Going back over to my set's notebook and the first command we looked at was s members.
We can use S members to get an array of all the elements inside that set.
While the U.S. members.
With user like key user ID.
Now if I mouse over it is right there.
We are told that yup.
This is definitely going to be an array of strings that we can take that.
And return.
Get items.
IDs.
And that's it.
I'm going to save this.
I'm going to flip back over very quickly.
Refresh.
And now, sure enough, I see the one item that I like right here.
It's the chair.
As a very quick test if I go to that item and unlike it.
And then click on See the seller again.
Remember, that's my profile because I listed this item.
So if I go back to my own profile, it no longer shows up in the section, which means it's definitely
working as expected.
I like it again.
See that item.
Once again right there.
All right.
That looks good.
Let's take a quick pause and we're going to take care of the other section like here, items you both
like, which will be pretty easy now that we've got that get items function put together.