Onto the last big feature, our end, our like system.
So I want to show items that I like and this person likes.
In this case, this is my own profile, so I'm really just going to expect to see this chair listed
in there.
But eventually, once we start to load in more data, we'll come back and make sure that this section
is working correctly.
All right.
Back inside of our likes knockouts file.
We're going to implement the common like items function.
So we need to do an intersection between this person's, like, set of item IDs and that person's.
That's going to be the entire command.
All right.
So I'm going to expand this.
I'm going to get a new variable called IDs and this will be the result of a wait find dot s enter.
Now the arguments to the center function, unfortunately, is not just a plain row in this list of ideas.
It has to be an array of them.
So we're going to put in an array.
We want to want to find the intersection between that user and that user.
So it will be user likes.
E with user one id user likes key with user to ID.
After getting that list of ideas, we will once again return.
Get items and put in the list of ideas that we found.
And that's it.
But once again, back over here, I refresh the page.
I will see items you both like.
And sure enough, there is the chair there.
Again, this is my own profile, so it's not super proof that everything is working as expected.
But yeah, it's probably working and we can test it out in greater detail later on.
Okay.
That is, it's around our like system.
Now, in my opinion, it's my opinion.
This is an awfully small amount of code to implement a like system.
So this is really the power of sets in action right here.
We're seeing how easy it is to set up relations between different items or different records by using
a set.
And we even get this awesome functionality in getting common items or common things between different
records by using intersections as well.