In this section, we're going to start to get some hands on experience with Redis.
The first thing we're going to focus on is the idea of commands.
Commands are simple strings that we send to our database that we use to save or retrieve some information
better understand commands.
Let's go back over to our books Cloud.
So this tool right here, I've made a new notebook called Basic Strings and created one code cell inside
of here.
We're going to write out a couple of basic commands and just understand how Read receives and retrieves
data.
So here's our very first command.
We're going to write out a command that's going to save a simple string inside of our database.
I'm going to put in a set message and as a string of.
Hi there.
After that, I'll click on the play button and I get a response right here of, Okay, if I then want
to retrieve this information that I have stored, I can add in another code cell right here and I will
put in a slightly different command.
One called yet.
And then message.
I click on play, I get back the string I had just saved.
All right.
So very simple commands.
Well, let's take a look at a diagram or two and just understand what is going on behind the scenes
here.
So when you click on that play button, that string that you entered into, the code editor is taken
as it stands like a plain string and it's sent off to your running.
Read a server.
The first command that we executed is the set command and it's used to store a very simple string inside
of Redis.
Internally, Redis looks at the first word right after the set command.
In this case, it is message red.
Interpret this as being like a key or a variable name.
We are essentially creating a variable of sorts inside of red.
Red is called message.
It then assigns that a value of hi there.
So internally this is kind of what's going on.
We've got a key of message and if we ever refer to that variable or that key name in the future, we're
going to get back a string of.
Hi there.
After saving that data reticence back in response to us of OC, which simply means okay, the data has
been saved successfully.
The second command that we made use of was the get command.
You get command is used to retrieve simple strings.
Once again, Reddit is going to look at whatever word you put right after get in.
It's going to interpret that as being like a variable name or really a key threat.
This is going to take a look at all the different keys it has stored.
It's going to try to find one specifically called message.
In this case, it finds it right here, but retrieves whatever value is associated with that key and
sends it back in response to us.
And that's why we saw.
Hi there up here on the screen.
Now the jet and set commands that we just made use of are two very simple commands that are intended
only for storing plane strings and plane numbers.
As I mentioned in an earlier video, there are many other types of data that we can store inside of
Redis.
Some other very common data types are lists, hashes, sets, sorted sets and so on.
Each of these different types of data have different sets of command, so we make use of them with.
So for example with string we just used set and get.
Those are commands that are only made for working with plain strings.
If we ever want to work with a list of elements or a hash, there are completely different commands
that we're going to make use of the.
For example, to add an element into a list, we might use inserts to add an element into a hash.
We might make use of each set.
Each of these different commands work only on the respective data types.
So in other words, I cannot use set and get to work with the list that and get only works with strings.
Throughout this course, we're going to focus on all these different data types one at a time.
We're going to learn many of the different commands that are associated with each of them in general
in every section of this course.
We're going to focus on one data type, learn about the different commands associated with it, and
when we would use each of those different commands.
The first type that we're going to be working with is the most simple and straightforward, just plain
strings.
Let's pause right here and start to dive deeper into strings in the next video.