Let's take a look at how we store and work with numbers inside of Redis.
And we can make use of numbers in very much the same way that we made use of strings.
As a matter of fact, we can use just about all the same commands for setting a number and retrieving
a number.
We can use the same set yet in get inset and so on and all the same options around these set commands
and so on apply.
So we can do a set x, a set x, x, and so on.
We start working with numbers.
However, we can also start looking at an additional set of commands designed specifically to work with
numbers.
So commands like decrease, decrease by increase by increase and so on.
Now, one thing I want you to understand right away is that we can very easily accidentally apply some
of these number specific commands to keys that reference strings.
And if we do so, if we try to say add some value to a string, we're going to end up getting an error
message back from Redis.
We'll see an example that very quickly.
There is one other very strange behavior around numbers I want you to be aware of as well.
Let's imagine for a second that we run the command like set age 22, presumably store a number inside
of our database.
That true.
Looks like a number right there to me.
Well, here's the weird part.
Internally, Redis is going to store that number as a string of 20.
That's a string right there inside of Redis.
It is understood to be a string.
When we try to retrieve that value.
So if we do a get age registers going to send back to us a string containing the number 20.
And so inside of our app server, we have to take that string.
We have to pass it to turn it into a plane number.
You can kind of view this entire idea of storing numbers inside of Redis as almost an afterthought.
It's like the authors of Reddit said, Hey, let's make everything work really well for strings.
And then later on they realized, Oh, we should probably also support numbers.
That's pretty much what happened here.
Now, this extra little step of parsing the number is, at the end of the day, pretty small.
It's not a big deal.
We'll see some examples of it in real code later on inside the course.
Okay.
So with all that in mind, we're going to very quickly go over some of these commands.
It's going to be very fast because they're all pretty simple and basic in nature.
No.
First off, increment and decrements, very simple.
We can add a single number to a existing key.
When I say a single number, I mean adds one, or we can decrease that subtracts one from some number
stored at a key.
Let's test both these commands out very quickly back inside of our book.
So back over here.
I'm going to set.
Age to 20.
All right.
Looks good.
Well, then do a increase of age.
And we get back.
Yep.
Sure enough.
21.
If I then do on another code cell down here, a decrease of age.
Yep.
We go back down to 20.
All right.
Simple enough.
There are two very small variations on these commands.
So increase by and decrease by.
These are identical commands in nature.
The only difference is they allow us to specify how much we want to increase number by or how much we
want to subtract by.
We can put in a number after the key to say we want to add ten.
We're at 15 or 250 or whatever else to an existing value.
So again, as a very quick example.
I can do a increase by the age and add to it.
And now up to 40.
And then the very last command we're going to take a look at around numbers right now is increased by
float.
So the number or the commands we've looked at so far, increase, increase by decrease, decrease by
our all around working with integers.
Those are numbers that do not have decimal points on them.
If we specifically want to work with floats or numbers that have a decimal, we're going to use increase
by floats.
We can call it increase by floats, reference some key and then put in a number with a decimal.
And if you want to decrease, well that's fine.
You just put in a negative number like so.
Let's test that out very quickly as well.
We'll do an increase by float to age with how about a -3.3?
And I get back a float value.
And that's pretty much it around numbers.
Now, once again, the question here very quickly becomes who cares?
What good are numbers?
When would we ever want to store a number one of these commands going to be useful?
Well, in this case, I don't really have anything to say.
Hey, here's like a crazy use case that you can come up with.
But there is something very interesting around these commands.
There is something really interesting where if you really think about them and you think about the fact
that they even exist.
Starts to get a little bit interesting.
We'll come back the next video.
We're going to do a little bit deeper, dive on these commands and understand why they exist at all.
And it kind of is going to lead you to a better understanding of some particular use cases of reticence.