All right, my friends, once again, we've got a set of commands and we kind of look at them and say,
why do these commands exist?
When are we really going to use them?
Well, this time around, I'm not going to try to give you some contrived use case for them, per se.
I'm not going to try to imagine some kind of some kind of sample application.
But instead, we're going to take a look at what these commands really do and start to notice something
really interesting about their sheer existence.
Just the fact that they exist is kind of interesting.
Let me tell you what I mean by that.
I want to consider the increase command.
So remember, increase is going to look at a number that is already stored in the database.
It's going to look up that value and increase it by one.
Now, the very important part about that entire operation is that it is really doing two things simultaneously.
It is looking up a value.
It is changing the value and then saving the value back.
So I kind of listed three things there, but essentially it's doing a lookup operation and a modification
at the same time.
And you start to think about that.
You might start to get the sense that we could re-implement the increased command by using these two
more basic commands of sets and git.
Let's take a look at what that might look like.
So again, rather than making use of increase, we could break this up into two separate operations.
So over here on the left hand side, we've got a first command that we might issue.
This might be to get some value out of this.
You'll notice I've now changed the name of our key to upvotes.
So we're going to imagine that you're trying to upvote a blog post or an image or comment, whatever
it might be.
Inside of our database, we've got an existing key value pair where upvotes is 20.
So we could get the current value of upvotes, get it back inside of our API server as a string, parse
it into a number, add one to it manually, which is what increase usually does for us.
We'd end up with 21.
Then to save that back to our database, we can issue a set command where we say set up votes to 21.
Sure enough, we would save 21 and that would be it.
Effectively, this two step process does the same thing as increase.
So again, why does increase exist with this in mind?
Well, there are two reasons that this is not a very good approach.
The first reason that this is not a good approach is probably going to be kind of obvious and a little
bit clear.
That is, we are making two roundtrips to our reddest database.
That means two different requests from our API server over to Metis.
That means at a very fundamental level it might take up to twice as long to increment increment a number
compared to us just using the increment command.
But just by sheer fact, of breaking this up into two separate commands instead of one.
Well, it's not quite ideal, but there's a much more fundamental issue here.
A much more and a challenging thing to solve.
Let's take a look at what the second big issue is.
Okay.
Let's imagine that we have a very, very popular website.
So something like Reddit dot com or something similar to it.
And on the very front page of our website, we always list out a couple of different posts with some
top comments.
The chances are these very popular posts are getting upvoted all the time, though just constantly.
In 1/2 we might receive a tremendous number of requests to upvote a given post.
Let's imagine that we received two requests at exactly the same time to our API server asking to upload
a particular post.
If the post already had a upvote value of 20, then after receiving these two requests and processing
them, our expectation is that we should have 22 upvotes.
That's what we want.
We want to see the number 22 after we process both these requests.
Now, just to simplify these diagrams a little bit more, or I guess make them a little bit more confusing
but more realistic, we're going to imagine that we were running two copies of our API server and they're
both connecting to the same instance of Redis.
So we're working with the same underlying data.
We have two completely different servers that are trying to tell us at the same time that we need to
increment that value.
So let's try to imagine what goes on behind the scenes as we process these two requests.
Assuming that we're doing this to round trip kind of affair, we're doing a jet and then a set.
All right.
Here we go.
This is a crazy diagram.
Don't sweat it.
We'll go through it step by step.
So the entire idea here is that we've got API server number one up here and API server number two down
here.
We've only got one copy of Red.
It's in the middle.
I've just split it out into two separate boxes just for clarity.
Now along this horizontal axis from left to right, we can kind of imagine is time passing.
So we received these two requests at exactly the same time, and they're both trying to upvote the exact
same post.
The both of our copies of the API server are going to simultaneously issue two separate commands to
get the current value of upvotes.
And Redis is of course when to send back response to both copies of our API server of 20.
Now at the exact same time, both copies of our API server are going to parse that number, add one
to it and come up with 21, and then simultaneously at the exact same time, they're both going to say
to Redis, okay, let's update the value of upvotes.
So set it to 21.
So they both send a command of 21.
At the exact same time after red is red, this is going to update the value of upwards to 21.
And that's it.
That's the entire flow.
And I bet you can see what the issue is here.
Our intention was to end up with 22 upvotes, but because we read out this value of 20, updated it
simultaneously in two different locations, we ended up with 21 instead.
Now, this might seem like a uncommon problem.
You might think, Oh, Stephen, how often is this really going to happen?
Well, if you're receiving a tremendous number of requests, say thousands per second, without a doubt,
a scenario like this will eventually happen.
It is absolutely, positively going to happen at some point in time.
And this is a very basic scenario where we are trying to increment a single small number.
You can imagine that we've got if we had some more complicated business logic running behind the scenes,
we might end up with a similar bug.
It would be much more challenging to handle.
So how would we solve this?
Well, to solve this problem, there are three different possible solutions.
The first solution?
We need to use a register transaction with a very special command called Watch.
This is something we're going to take a look at later on inside the course.
We could also make use of something called a lock.
So another thing we're going to take a look at later on, stayed the course as well.
So essentially these first two options are options.
And I just want you to know that there are very good ways of solving solving this problem.
We're going to look at them later on because they are much more complicated and not really needed in
this scenario.
So the third possible solution, which is definitely the easiest, the simplest to understand, no two
ways about it is to just use the increment command.
Though if we use the incorrect command instead, here's what you'd end up up with.
We would get our two separate quests at the same time.
The API server would send off the increment upvotes commands to Redis.
And then the key thing to understand here, this is something that I'm going to tell you about non-stop.
Throughout this course.
Redis is synchronous and single threaded in nature.
That means that even if a tremendous number of commands are coming in at exactly the same time, like
the same microsecond, it doesn't make a difference to Redis.
Redis only processes one command at a time in the order that they are received.
So even if we get both these increment upvotes commands at exactly the same time, it doesn't matter.
Register is going to first process this one perhaps and end up with 21.
And then process this one and end up with 22.
So the first response after running that increment upvotes would send back 21 to the first API server
and then 22 to the second, which would be the intended behavior.
Just to be clear.
We successfully processed both requests to upvote, which came in at in theory just about the exact
same time.
And we ended up with 22 upvotes in total.
Okay.
So, like I said.
The fact that these commands exist, you know, who cares?
We're just changing the value of numbers.
But what is really interesting and what we're kind of getting a sense of right now and again, we're
going to see this throughout the course is that this these commands, just their sheer existence, start
to tell us about the synchronous nature of radius and how we kind of have to worry about concurrency
in some scenarios when we are processing many different requests at the same time.
And just I want to repeat it for a third time.
This is a topic we're going to touch on again and again throughout the course.
We're always going to be thinking about concurrency and handling data from different APIs at the same
time.
Okay.
So enough about numbers right now.
Let's move on.