Throughout this course, we're going to be using this Arbor tool a pretty good amount.
As a reminder, you do not have to use this tool if you don't want to.
I'm going to show you how you can use red ac alai instead and also, of course, what Red Acela is in
just a couple videos.
I do, however, recommend you use Arbor because it gives you a nice little kind of notebook where you
can put together some documentation and refer to this stuff in the future.
I made this tool for you, but just to be clear, I don't get anything from you using it.
As a matter of fact, I pay to keep this tool running.
So when I say I recommend you use it, it's not because it's in my interest per se.
To do so is because I really think that you would be well-served to have some documentation on what
we're doing here.
Now in this video, what I want to do at the end of every single section, I'm going to give you a single
file.
That contains all of the completed notes from our the like basically the previous section.
And I will have put in a lot of extra documentation and whatnot as well.
So you can see in this case I went back to our basic strings notebook and I put in some quick notes
around all these different commands we wrote out.
And so I got just about every single one of them documented.
You can find the completed notebook attached to the previous lecture.
The one right before this one was a text lecture.
You should have found a file called Basic Strings Complete a dot JSON.
So if you want to use this kind of completed version I put together, just go back to the main page
of Object Cloud, click on upload notebook and then you can just do a drag and drop like so.
And then here is the notebook that was just created.
And you could see all the notes.
I'm going to attach these completed notebooks at the end of every section or really wherever is appropriate,
really wherever we have a good set of notes that warrants some documentation.
So again, totally optional.
You don't have to upload these things if you don't want to.
But again, I kind of recommend it.
Lastly, want to mention all the notebooks that are getting uploaded here are tied to your browser session.
So in other words, if you ever change browsers, change computers, or reset your cookies in your browser,
you will lose your notebooks.
So if holding on to these things is really important to you, I would recommend that you export your
notebooks every now and then.
It just downloads a simple JSON file.
You can then very easily re-upload using the upload tool very simply.
Okay.
That's it.
So let's continue on.