Attached to the lecture right before this one is a JSON file called String Exercises.
Inside there there are just a couple of exercises around strings I'd like to go over really quickly,
so make sure you download that file once you have downloaded it.
Go over to our object cloud.
Go to the main landing page.
We're going to click on Upload Notebook.
Then I'm going to do a simple drag and drop.
Of that Jason file.
And then I should see strings exercises right there.
Inside of here are three just very simple, very straightforward exercises.
There's going to make sure that some of the topics we just went over are super clear.
I would like you to give these exercises a shot.
We're then going to go over the solutions to them together in just a moment.
So go and give it a try.
And we will watch together everything in the next video.