Hopefully you had some success with these exercises.
So there are three in total.
Each one is just asking you to write out a very simple command.
Let's go over the solutions together.
So for the first exercise, we need to store a value of Toyota at the key car.
Well, it sounds like we would use a very simple set operation.
I'm going to do set car Toyota, and that's pretty much it.
If I run that, I get back responsive.
Okay.
Once again, meaning everything was stored successfully.
Let's go on to exercise number two.
On this one.
We're going to store the value triangle at the key shape, but we're only going to store that value
if the key shape is not already defined.
If I do a get of shape right now, I get back.
No.
That means that the key is not currently defined in any way.
So I'm going to do a set shape triangle and then to make sure that we only attempt to store this if
nothing is already stored at shape.
I'm going to add on the arguments and X.
I'm going to run that.
And the first time I run this, I'll get back.
Okay.
Which means that the value has been stored.
But if I run it a second time, I'll get back null because a value has now been stored at actually just
to confirm everything worked.
I'll also do a get on shape and I should get back a responsive triangle.
Okay.
Not bad.
Let's move on to the third exercise.
Now, this one's just a little bit tricky.
We're going to write a command that's going to store the value of today's headlines and notice that
there is a space inside that string as well.
Space right there between those two words.
We want to store that at the key news.
We also want to automatically expire this value after 3 seconds.
Well, to approach this, let's first make sure that we can store the string correctly and not worry
about any expiration just yet.
So I will do a set news.
And then you might have noticed if you try to do something like today's headlines, you're going to
end up getting an error because we've got a string here that has a space in it.
If there is no space, we do not have to wrap this with quotes.
But because there are quotes or something, because there is a space in there, we do have to wrap it
with quotes.
In addition, we cannot very easily use a single quotes on either side because I've got an apostrophe
in here.
We can use single quotes.
If we escape that apostrophe, that will work.
Or alternatively, we could just use double quotes around the outside, and then we wouldn't have to
worry about the single quote on the inside.
All right.
Well, that definitely stores the string, but we want to make sure that this value expires after 3
seconds.
So to put in the automatic expiration, we could either do an X of three, remember, accepts a number
that is interpreted as seconds.
Or alternatively, we could do apex, which takes in a millisecond value.
So either one would be totally fine.
I'll run that.
And now if I comment out that line.
And do a get on news.
After 3 seconds later, I should see no in response because now the value has expired.
Okay.
So that's pretty much it.
Well, hopefully you got through these three exercises.
Still a lot more to learn.
So let's move on to our next topic.