We are going to write out a couple more commands in just a moment.
But first, I want to give you a few more high level notes on commands and show you some documentation
around them as well.
I went through the official Rita's documentation and I found a list of all the different commands that
are relevant for dealing with strings in just about any way.
And I came up with a list that you see right here.
Now, this might look like many different commands where you have to understand and really figure out
what they're all used for.
But I want to immediately help you understand that you really don't have to memorize every single one
of these commands to use this effectively out of all these different commands.
Just about half of them are used to retrieve data out of Redis.
Those specifically retrieve strings.
Just about the other half are used to store strings in red.
Now, even when I start to divide it down like this, it still looks like there's a lot of stuff to
memorize.
But here's the thing to understand about Red is it turns out that many commands kind of duplicate functionality.
In other words, something like get and get really have at the end of the day very similar behavior.
Making use of the Git X Command is very similar to get, except it kind of implies that you're also
going to add in this additional option.
In other words, you're kind of like very small variations on otherwise simple commands.
But of all this, I kind of did a little bit of grouping together.
On the guitar side.
These are all commands that are used to retrieve data.
It turns out that gets get Del and get x duvall.
Do something vaguely similar.
So you don't really have to memorize each and every one of these three commands.
You can really just start to study, get by itself.
And if you ever decide that you're in a special scenario or special case where maybe get Del would be
a little bit more convenient for you to use.
You can very quickly look at the documentation and understand how to use it very quickly.
Very similar on Seders as well.
It turns out that set set an X and set x all kind of vaguely do the same thing.
So we're going to spend a lot of time understanding sets and we're going to have a quick word about
set an X and set x, but we're not going to obsess over them or anything like that.
In addition, there are also some commands where it's really not immediately obvious where you would
ever use these things, any practical application, unless you have some kind of very special circumstance.
Some examples of that would be substring get range LCS and for setters the append and set range.
That's not to say that you're never going to use these commands, but if you're going to use them,
it's probably in a very special use case and I'll mention what some possible use cases would be.
And the last thing I want to do is show you the official documentation you are going to be making use
of the official docs around commands very, very often.
Even if you are using a library in your code to work with Redis.
I'll tell you why that is.
A little bit later on inside the course.
I want to very quickly show you this documentation and help you understand how to read it.
Because even in this course, we are going to refer back to the documentation very often.
Go inside your browser, open up a new tab.
We're going to go to register IO, slash commands, and I've got the page open myself right here.
Now up at the top, I am going to find this dropdown that says Filter by group.
Remember what I told you in the last video?
There are many different commands and each of these different commands are usually used to modify or
work with a very specific type of data.
So if I use this dropdown, I'll see that I can look up all the different commands related to strings.
And now we're going to see some the commands we just saw in that diagram just a moment ago.
So things like append, get set, get delegate X and so on.
You'll notice that there are some other commands inside here that didn't list inside the diagram that
you were just looking at, because they are related specifically to working with numbers.
We're going to cover numbers separately in just a moment.
Ah, this entire list.
I'm going to scroll down and find the command called set.
Here it is right here.
Now all I want to show you is really this big lock of text up here at the top because you're going to
see in the documentation for just about every command blocks of text that look like this.
And if you don't know what you're looking at, it's going to get really confusing really quickly.
So let me just help you understand what this text is trying to tell us.
I took all the text of that heading and broke it up part by parts.
The first thing I want to point out is that any time you see a capitalized word, that is a keyword.
In other words, we're going to write out exactly that keyword for a command whenever we execute it.
So set is capitalized.
That means if we ever want to run the set command, we must write in SBT.
Any time you see a lowercase value, that is where you and I, as developers are supposed to put in
some particular value of our own.
So we're not supposed to write in here.
Right here.
We're supposed to put in some value or key.
So something like color or message or something similar.
Any time you see square brackets, that means everything inside there is optional.
So down here at the very bottom we have get inside of square brackets.
That means this is an optional argument that we are not required to put in to understand what these
optional arguments do for us.
You can scroll down in the documentation a little bit and find right your options.
Find git and that will tell you what's going to happen if you add in that get keyword.
Finally you'll see all of these hype symbols.
They kind of look like capital I's that can be interpreted as meaning or everything inside of this big
square bracket block right here means you can add in an argument or apex or an exact or apex out and
so on.
Now, like I said, we're going to come back to this documentation very often because it really is truly
the source of understanding how this works.
In addition, many of the documentation on these different commands will give you more insight into
what the command is doing behind the scenes and how we might use it effectively in a real application.