Let's do a deep dive on the set command.
And the set command is very basic in terms of the data that it stores.
It's really only four simple strings.
But by taking a look at the different arguments that this command accepts, you start to get a better
sense of what's going on with Redis and some of its common use cases, as we just saw in the documentation
to run the set command we first put in Capital City.
We are then always going to list out the name of the key that we want to set and the actual value that
we want to store.
We saw an example of that back over on our book just a moment ago where we set the key of message with
the value of Hi there.
After that, there are three distinct groups of options that we can provide.
The first group of options tell us when this value should expire.
In other words, when this value will be automatically removed from the database.
Now, that might sound really bizarre.
Why would we ever want to automatically remove data from the database?
Turns out there are some use cases for this, which we'll discuss in just a moment.
The second set of optional arguments.
Provide some conditions on when to set this key, though only set the key if it has not been set before.
Or alternatively, only set the key if it does already exist.
Again, we'll look at some possible use cases for this.
And then finally the last optional group of options here get.
If we put in get, then whenever we set a key, we're going to get back in response.
The previous value that was stored there.
Now, of course, you can see all these different options and the documentation around them in the official
Docs page that we were looking at just a moment ago, rather than have me just lecture a whole bunch.
Let's go back over to our book and test out some different variations of a set command to better understand
what it's all about over in our book.
I've created a new code cell.
The first thing I want to do is try out that get option and just see how it works.
I'm going to set.
A key of color to red.
And then run it after they get back.
Okay.
And then going to put in a second command in here of set color green.
I think he sort of get at the very end.
This means first set color to red, then set color to green and give us back whatever the previous value
of color was.
If I now run this, we get back red.
Red is stored in color.
After this command is executed.
And then when we set color equal to green, we get back red.
Just you know, our book is only ever going to show you the outputs of the last command that gets executed
in a single cell.
If you want to see the output of all the different commands, you can click on the little dot, dot,
dot right here and we'll show you the output of both commands.
I can see that first I did the set color of red and then set color green.
Next up, we're going to take a look at the annex and x x options.
Describing what these things do in plain English is a little bit confusing.
So instead, let's look at a very simple diagram.
Okay.
So first, we'll take a look at the x x option.
If we add in x x to the very end of our command, then the set is only going to run if the key already
exists inside of Redis.
Let's imagine for a second that we run set SDF with x x on the very end.
We're trying to set a key of a SDF.
Well further, imagine that our register database is completely empty right now, so no data in there
whatsoever because the SDF key does not exist inside retest.
No data would be actually set and we would get back a response of no.
Let's try that out inside of our bucket very quickly.
Back over.
I'm going to add in a new code section.
I'm going to do a set SDF AI there with x x.
Now once again, I do not yet have anything set with that key right there and will put in some real
gibberish just to make sure it's very plain.
I probably don't have a key with that name.
Now, if I run this, I get back.
No.
Is that key?
Does not yet exist.
I'm going to change the set.
Use color instead.
And I definitely have a color he already defined as I had made use of it back up here just a moment
ago.
Now, if I run this, I get okay, because the color key already exists.
Very similar option.
It kind of works in reverse is the next option.
So an X is only going to run the set if the key does not exist.
Of colour already exists inside of our database for making use of the anex flag.
Then the set operation will not run.
Let's try out that variation as well.
Down here.
I'll put in a set color.
You have a blue with an X.
I run.
That color already exists, but the operation does not run.
I get back a null, but if I tried to set a key that definitely has not been set before.
So something like color SDF, then it's going to work successfully and I will get back the OC.
All right.
So a couple of simple variations around the set commands.
We kind of skipped over it.
The middle one right here.
The option for when this value should expire.
And like I said, this might seem a little bit strange, but let's start to dive into the world of expiring
values in the next video and understand why we would ever want to have some of our data and readies
expire automatically.