The last variation on set that we're going to take a look at are these specs and so on.
Optional arguments.
All these optional arguments are all about when Redis should automatically expire or delete the data
that we are storing inside of our database, for example.
If we run sets color red with an X of two, that means that we want to automatically delete this color
key value pair after 2 seconds have passed.
I'm going to tell you why we might do this in just a moment.
But first, let's go back over to our book and just test this out very quickly.
All right, so back over here.
I've created two editor cells.
I'm going to first put in a set color red with an X of two.
And then immediately do a jet color right after or then do another jet color down here as a separate
query.
That when we run the top one, we're going to immediately set color.
We then attempt to get color and we should get back a response immediately that says Red.
But if we then wait for 2 seconds and then run the second query down here, red should have automatically
deleted color.
And so we should get back a response of no or something similar.
Okay, so here we go.
The first one, I get red and then if I wait 2 seconds, I get.
No.
Alternatively, if I run the first one and then the second one immediately after, very quickly, I
should see Red come up on the second one.
So I'll do that that I see red down here.
I could do red or the second one again.
Now I get back.
No.
So again, that second optional argument group is when read is going to automatically delete your data
at this particular key value pair.
We just made use of the option Yext allows you to designate how long to wait in milliseconds sat and
sat allowed to specify a date time.
So like an actual particular time at some point in time in the future and keep total.
Essentially means keep any expiration that has already been applied to this key.
Most common uses, however, are going to be NPCs.
Now the real question here and what all this stuff around set really gets down to is why would we ever
want to use this expiration option?
Where would we ever want to have a data store where our data gets automatically deleted after some period
of time?
Well, there's one very simple answer to this, and it kind of goes back to one of the original purposes
of Redis.
Rattus was originally designed as a caching server.
That means that it's going to keep around some amount of data for some period of time and then eventually
just plain get rid of it when it's not needed anymore.
We walk you through a common use case of this exploration field.
Let's imagine that we are building some kind of news API.
So our API server right here is going to be receiving requests for some headlines of news from around
the world to make sure that our API is very fast.
We might have two different databases for servicing our application.
One might be a traditional database like PostgreSQL, MySchool or something similar, and we might also
have a reticent database running as well.
Now remember Redis in general is a very, very fast let's make our API very quick.
We could use Redis as a caching server.
Let's walk through what the typical flow of our app might be.
Well, assume that we get some request in for news headlines and we want to respond to this request
as fast as we possibly can.
So our API might decide to first see if the latest headlines are stored inside of Redis at this point.
Nope.
No data inside of your whatsoever.
As soon as the API sees that no data is available inside of Rita's, it might fall back as a second
choice to trying to get some data out of our traditional database, which in general is probably going
to be much slower than using Redis.
Inside of our traditional database, we might have our latest headlines stored right here.
The API is going to get a copy of those latest headlines and send them back in response to whoever made
that original request.
Simultaneously.
It might also store a copy of the latest headlines inside of Reddy's.
Now let's think about what happens if another request comes in shortly after.
When another request comes in for news headlines, the AP might again check to see if the data is available
in readies.
And sure enough, now it is.
The API can take the data right here very, very quickly as it did not have to access the traditional
database and immediately sent back a response right away.
Now, without a doubt, this would make for a very fast application because we don't have to go reach
out to the traditional database.
But the downside here is that we might not have anything available for any other part of our application
to automatically update the headlines inside of Redis.
There's a very simple reason for this.
Remember, Redis, all of its data has to be stored in memory.
So we can't always just put all of our headlines in Redis because we might eventually run out of memory.
But to get around that problem, we might decide to automatically delete this particular headline after
it has not been accessed in any way in some number of seconds or milliseconds, maybe after 10 seconds
passed.
Since we put in this cash value inside of here, we might delete it automatically just to save space
inside of our Redis database.
Naturally, the next time another request comes in, the API would reach out to us again.
No data is available.
And so again, back to that original first step, the flow might get some data out of the traditional
database, send it back in response, and then also cache it temporarily inside of Redis.
Again, this kind of automatic expiration time really goes back to registers original purpose as a caching
server and we want to inspire data to make sure that our cash is not serving old out of date data and
also make sure that we are not going to run out of memory.
We're going to see eventually.
There are some other use cases around these exploration flags.
There's some really clever use cases that we can use to solve a couple of common problems around retest.
But the most common use case of exploration really is around caching.
Okay.
Now, one thing I want to note here.
We're not going to go too deep into the other explanation options such as you expect that and so on.
As I showed you just a moment ago, you can always take a look at the documentation to understand what
those do for us in this course.
I don't want to be just me reading through the documentation for all the different commands we go over.
I'm not going to cover every last little option because I really, truly believe you can probably read
the documentation and figure out what's going on much faster than I can explain it in long winded diagrams
and so on.
Of course, if you do have any questions about these additional options, feel free to post them on
the course and I'll do my best to answer them for you.
All right.
So at this point, I think we've got a reasonable idea of what's going on with set.
So let's move on to our next command in the next video.