We've gone through set in pretty good detail in this video.
We're going to very quickly rip through sets and x, x, m sets and M set an x, as I mentioned, set
an x and set x are very similar in nature to set, which is why we're going to spend just a very brief
amount of time in the near future as we come across very similar commands.
I'm probably not going to mention them at all or just mention them in passing, because once again,
I am really going to assume you can take a look at documentation much more quickly than I can iterate
through the stuff in.
Of course.
Okay.
So very fast.
What's up with set an x and x?
Okay.
So set.
Yes.
Does the exact same thing as set when you include the x option.
Remember we just spoke about Yext a moment ago.
It means set the value of color to red, but then unset or delete this key value pair after 2 seconds.
If we use set with an x of two that is completely identical to set x e number of seconds value completely
identical.
Same thing.
If you even look at the documentation around sets, you will see a note that eventually a set yes might
be deprecated and removed because set can do exactly what set X does.
On to set next.
I bet you can sense a theme here.
I bet you can guess what's going on here.
Remember, the next flag on set is only going to update or set a key value pair if it does not already
exist.
So if we already have a key pair of color, then this set right here would do nothing that an x does
the same thing.
The only difference is you are making use of set and x as opposed to set with the next as the last argument.
Once again that X and set next just about the same as using set with just one particular argument.
Okay.
So those are pretty boring in nature.
And again, as we come across nearly identical commands, I'm not really going to cover these extra
ones, might mention them in passing, just, you know, that they exist.
But we're not going to spend a ton of time discussing them.
Now.
Let's move on.
Very quickly, two sets begin in.
This case stands for multiple.
So we can use insets to set multiple key value pairs at the exact same time.
Round diagram.
There we go.
For example, I might do an inset with a key value.
A key value, and I could repeat more key value pairs inside the same command if I want.
I could do colour sets red and also simultaneously set car to Toyota.
Those are the same as calling set multiple times in a row.
All right.
So all these commands, like I mentioned, pretty basic.
Let's go back over to our book very quickly and just test them out.
All right.
So back over here.
I'm going to add in a new code cell.
And first, let's try doing a set X.
With a colour of red once again.
And in between the key and the value right there, we're going to put the number of seconds.
We want to keep this key value pair around.
Again, I'll just do 2 seconds.
I'm going to run this.
I'm going to wait 2 seconds and I'll run that cell right above again.
Okay.
And count one, two, and run this up here and I get null.
If I run this one and then immediately click on the one above, I will see red and then eventually it
goes back to null again.
Simple enough.
Now, if you want to go ahead and give a test with such an X, we have to you if you want to give that
a shot.
Otherwise, I'm just going to skip ahead to m set very quickly.
Inset allows us to set multiple key value pairs at the same time so we could do color red and model
Toyota.
And then if I do a jet color and a jet model and run this.
And then remember, this preview window over here on the right hand side is only going to show the output
of the most recent command unless you click on that dot, dot, dot.
Now I can see that I set successfully both color and model, and I get back red and Toyota.
One more variation on inset is inset and x again, just about identical in nature just means if any
of these guys already exist, then do not do any setting whatsoever.
If I do im set an x and the key color or car are already defined, then I will not set any values at
all.
All right.
So that's it.
Just a couple of very fast variations on these commands.
Again, I just I know I mentioned this twice already.
I mentioned just one more time in general, in the future, I will not really go out of my way to cover
that next that.
Yes, you said next at all, we're just going to really look at these more basic commands because those
are the ones that you are always going to use.
You're just going to add in the additional arguments because the more specialized forms of these commands
might eventually be removed at some point in time in the future.