That's for completion sake.
Let's go over to the other side of this diagram.
We're going to take a look at and get and get very quickly.
We've already used get a couple of times, so I bet you can guess how that one's going to work.
We just put in get and the name of some key that we want to retrieve.
Very small variation.
This is in Get, which works very similar to M set.
It allows us to retrieve multiple different keys with one single command, so an in get of color in
model would give us whatever value is associated with both color and model.
Again, very quick demonstration here.
So I have previously set the keys, color and model and if I now add in another cell here and do an
m gets of color and model.
I should get back both Red and Toyota and sure enough, I do.