We just had two long videos on a couple of different commands, and I know just going over commands
is pretty boring.
We're going to do one last very quick video on a few commands and then I'm really excited because in
the next video we're going to go over a lot of these different commands together and see how they all
fit together to make a pretty interesting system.
We're going to start to see where Reddit starts to come to life.
Very quickly, one last set of commands.
In this video we're going to cover get range, that range in Del.
Very quickly.
All right.
So first off, Del, this deletes an existing key out of your database and all the data stored at that
key.
This can use not only with strings, it can be used with any kind of data type.
For example, it called Del with a string of color.
It's going to delete the key color and any data associated with that key.
As a very quick example, I can do a jet color and I've got red stored there still.
I then do a del of color.
And then finally.
Another jet of color.
And now I can see plainly that no data is stored there at all.
All right.
Simple enough.
Next up, get range.
Now this command and the next one we're going to look at, which is set range, are both going to look
not super useful.
But like I said, we're going to see how all these commands kind of come together to really make this
very interesting.
The get range allows us to look at an existing string inside of our database and we can pull a range
of characters out of that string.
So we might Ron get range.
Look at the string stored at color and try to retrieve just the characters at index zero of that string
all the way through index three.
Let me show you an example that very quickly.
As a reminder, I have a key already set up of model here, and Toyota is stored at it.
So if I do a get range on model and then a zero and two, that means starting at index zero.
That would be a tie.
Go all the way up to and including index two.
So a012.
That would give me back toi.
Arun.
That's Antonoff.
I get to play again.
Doesn't look super useful, but we'll see how it can be very useful in just a moment.
Only got set range.
Kind of like the opposite of get rings.
This allows us to update a portion of an existing string, so we'll look up a string stored at color.
We're going to go to some index inside that string, maybe index two.
And starting at index two, we're going to replace the characters in that string with whatever string
we provide right after that number.
Again, very quick example.
I'll do a set range on model.
I'll say starting at index you.
I want to overwrite all the existing characters with Lou.
Now we'll get back six.
That is the total length of the string that was created.
Well, then it's actually if I run this again, I'm going to do a further insertion.
So let me instead make a new cell down here and I will get model.
Now we can see that I have to loop because I started at index two of Toyota and started overwriting
existing characters.
All right.
So three more commands now.
We're going to take a quick pause, come back and see how all these different commands kind of come
together to make a pretty performant system.