All right, my friends, I'm really excited for this video because this is where we're going to see
Rita start to get really, really useful.
So as I mentioned in the last video, why would we ever really want to replace part of a string?
How often is there truly some kind of practical application of that?
And it seems like not always the most useful thing in the world.
Well, just keep in mind, one of the big reasons that we use Redis at all is its incredible performance.
It is a very, very fast database.
But it turns out that a lot of the commands that we're going to look at, although at face value, they
might appear to not be very useful.
And I think get range and set range are very good examples of that.
At face value, these commands don't really do a lot for us, but we can kind of twist these commands
a little bit.
We can use them in very creative ways.
And in doing so, we can make systems that are extremely fast in nature, just absolutely incredibly
fast.
And you're going to see exactly why they are fast and get some kind of sense of why they are fast at
all in just a little bit.
Don't worry.
I'm going to make sure it's very clear why these commands are fast at all.
Okay.
So I'm going to lay out a little bit of an example here, a little bit of a story.
We're going to imagine that you and I are employees at some really large product company.
So we make and sell furniture products.
And we have as a part of our company a big database.
It's a traditional SQL based database.
Inside, there is a list of all of our different furniture products.
For every single product, we record the products, ID, the type.
So is it a couch, a table or a chair?
The color and the material.
And that's it.
That's the only information we record.
And the kicker here is that we have many, many, many products in this database.
Just an absolutely unbelievable number.
It turns out that our company has employees all over the globe who are trying to access and write information
into this database all the time.
It turns out that with this incredible number of products and the number of people who are trying to
make use of this data, our application is running extremely slowly.
We're going to imagine that our job is to use Redis to make accessing this data and updating this data
as fast as possible at all costs.
The absolute.
Complete goal here is speed.
And that's it.
That's what we're going for.
All right.
So now we set out the kind of baseline what we're doing here and what the issue is.
It's going to walk through a possible solution using these otherwise apparently useless looking commands.
It was a part of solving this process.
Your first job, as you know, would absolutely be to figure out how people are accessing the data,
how are they actually accessing it?
What updates are they making and how are they actually working with this list of products at all?
And in your research, you come up with these four different ways in which people interact with this
data.
The first way is they fetch one, two, three properties of a single item.
So a user might try to look up the item with an idea of two and then maybe access just the type that
would be table.
Or maybe they try to access just the material, which would be wood.
Or maybe they tried to get access to all three properties.
Second, the user might want to update 123 properties of a single item again.
Maybe a user wants to take a look at the ID the product with I.D. two.
An update.
Just the color or just the material?
Another way in which users might make use of this is to fetch all the properties related to several
items.
The user might say, I want to get all the properties for items one, two and three.
And then finally, user might try to create several items at once, maybe create 20 or 30 or 40 different
items each with a type color and material.
All right.
Now that we understand these use cases, let's try to come up with some way of getting this data intérets
and then figure out how we can use these otherwise useless looking commands to make this entire process
very fast.
But here's the trick.
As a part of our research, let's imagine that we found that there's a very limited number of types
of furniture.
Very limited number of colors and a very limited number of materials as well.
Maybe in total, there's only five materials that exist for making furniture.
Maybe there's only ten or so colors.
There's only ten or so types.
So it turns out that a lot of this data inside this table is very repetitive in nature, and it doesn't
really very, very often.
We'll say that our possible values of color, maybe red, green, blue, blah, blah, blah, all the
way down to ten.
All right.
Like I said.
Here is the trick.
Because this data is so repetitive we could decide to encode these values rather than storing an entire
string of red inside of our database for every possible red furniture item or the entire string green.
We might decide to encode these values inside of our Redis database rather than storing the entire string
of red, the entire string of green, the entire string of blue, and so on.
We might decide to just put in the character.
A So if we ever find a product with a color of A, that means it is red.
If we ever find a product with a color of B, that means it is green.
We refined product with a value C blue.
You get the idea, then we can repeat that process for types in materials as well.
So eventually we take that entire existing list of French products and come up with a encoded dataset
rather than storing these really long strings.
We now have just these simple characters, each of which have a very special meaning for that particular
attribute.
So a type of a might be a couch, a color of E might be brown, and a material of O might be leather
or something like that.
Almost lost out.
Now that we've got these encoded values, we can start to store them as plain strings inside of red
as.
So we might take every single item, every single product and assign them.
He's like, item all in one.
And that is meant to indicate that this is some product or item with idea one.
And then the value for that would be just taking these different attributes right here that are string
encoded.
Joining them all together and then storing them as a plane string.
I would end up with a u.
G.
So I'd.
One has a.
For tight you for color g.
From material.
An item to.
B.
G.
O.
An item three.
E.
C.
All right.
So we've now got all this data stored inside of Redis.
Now we can start to think about how we can make use of all those different commands that we just discussed
in the last couple of videos.
If you implement those for different operations.
So in order to fetch one, two, three properties of a single item, we could write out something like
yet range of item at one from 0 to 2.
That would go and find item one.
It would give me back all the characters inside of you're from zero one up to two.
So I get back AQ.
That would give me all three of the properties of that first item.
So I would know its type, its color and its material.
If I only cared about the type, I could do a get range of 020, which would give me just the right
there.
It would tell me the type of this item.
If I want to update one, two, three properties, well, I could do a set range.
Of item at one.
I would then maybe if I want to update all three different properties starting at index zero.
Insert B, c, d.
So I would update item one right here to BCD.
And so now maybe I'd have one is meant to represent a table that is brown made of plastic.
If I want to fetch all properties related to several items I could do a AM gets an item.
One item to an item three.
Now.
If I wanted to create several items simultaneously, I could do it in set item four and then put in
its encoded attributes of who knows, maybe TR Q and item five, maybe DNSSEC or something like that.
So now.
The net result here is that I have all my data stored in Redis.
It is just about as compact as possible.
It has been encoded with these very small single characters, and I can make use of these operations
that are built into Redis to make changes, updates, bulk updates, bulk inserts and so on to all these
different items.
And for reasons that, like I said, we're going to explore, explore very shortly.
All these different operations are going to run extremely, extremely quickly in general, far more
quickly than inside of our traditional database, especially considering the incredible number of items
we had stored inside the original database.
Oh.
Okay, so that's it.
That's why these seemingly useless commands actually can be very useful.
Sometimes you can't take these commands at face value.
You have to kind of think of very original uses for them.
And once you start to use them in these very interesting ways, that's when you start to get a lot of
very interesting power, inefficiency, efficiency out of Redis.
This is just our first take of this kind of interesting system where we kind of take these basic commands
and twist them a little bit.
We're going to see many other examples of this in the future as well.