Let's go back over to our e-commerce application and start to integrate search into it.
As you probably guess, we're going to wire up the search bar up here at the very top.
So if a user types in something like chair, I want to find all the different items that have chair
in the name or its description.
And I want to show those items and a little box right underneath it.
Now, just to clarify, we're going to show some search results right underneath it.
These are going to be the results of a full tech search, specifically of the items, names and the
descriptions.
That's it.
They're not going to do any querying here around, say, the items, VUSE or its bid price or anything
like that.
We are just concerned with the items, name and description.
So to get started on this, I've put together a little bit of a process that we're going to go through.
This is focused solely on just the index creation.
So whenever we need to make a new index inside of an application, these are the steps are going to
go through.
First thing we're going to do is figure out what prefix the index will use.
Remember that whenever we call FTE that creates, we have to provide a prefix to it.
And that means go and find all the different keys inside of radius that start with some particular string
and try to index those hashes.
For us, our prefects is going to try to look at all the different items that we've stored inside of
us.
All of our different items start with the prefix of items.
LB So items LB is probably going to be our prefix.
The next thing we have to do is look at all the different fields and the types of those fields inside
of our different hashes.
We're going to specifically add those to the index that is being created.
Remember that we only have to add fields to the index if we actually intend to use them inside of a
search.
We are only going to be doing searching on a item's name and description.
So we don't need any of the other fields inside of an item to be added to the index.
We only need the name and the description.
Given that we want to do a full tech search on both these fields, they're probably going to be of type
text instead of tag or numeric or any other type.
Once you've got those first few steps done, and we pretty much do at this point, those steps are pretty
easy and straightforward.
We're then going to actually write our function to create the index.
And then the last step here and this is where things are going to get a little bit challenging.
We have to decide when to create the index.
We can have a separate discussion on that because there's a couple of interesting little challenges
that we're going to run into around deciding when the index will be created.
But let's move on to step number three right here.
We need to make a function to create the index.
To do that, I'm going to go back over to my code editor.
And inside of my SIRC service's reticence.
Directory.
I'll find the file called Create Indexes.
Here it is right here.
You'll notice that I've already defined a function for us called create indexes.
The inside of here is where we are going to add in some code to actually, of course, create the index
to create an index using the Node Redis library, which is what we're using right now.
We're going to call a function of client dot dot creates.
This is how we create an index using node redis.
This function is going to take three different arguments.
The first will be where we want to store the key or where we want to store the index inside of Redis.
So we have to basically just provide a key.
The second argument is going to be a big object describing all the different fields that we want to
index and the types of those fields.
So we're going to say that we want to index the name and the description of every item and that they
are both of type text.
And then the third argument is going to describe the kind of structure we are trying to index.
So that is a hash.
And we'll that's where we will also provide our prefix as well.
And one thing to note here is that we are going to have to specify exactly where we want to store the
items index.
So we need to make another key generating function and we'll call it something like items index key.
Let's get started there.
So back inside, my editor, I'm going to find that key sorts file.
And then at the very bottom, I'm going to add on a new key generating function called items next key.
Now I'm going to follow the same naming convention I've told you about a couple of times.
So I'd colon items.
Well, then go back over to Crete indexes.
Yes.
And I'm going to import that function at the top.
Okay.
Now, rather than continue on and having this video get really, really long, let's take a pause right
here and then continue with the implementation in just a moment.