The other command.
I want you to understand around debugging, any search operation is for profile.
This allows you to run a query and register is going to internally at time how long it takes to execute
that query.
By using this command, you can try to play around with the syntax of your command of your query a little
bit.
Get a better understanding of what happens when you say put on a wildcard prefix or put on those percent
signs to allow for fuzzy search.
Let's try running this over in orbit really quickly.
I'm going to do a 40 knots profile by the items.
Search, Mary.
Like where he's going to be chairs and then I'm going to add on a limit zero zero, which just means
don't actually send me any results back.
And then if I run that, we're going to get some information here.
There's a lot of stuff going on.
But what it really comes down to are the first two numbers you see.
The first number is how many search results actually came back.
So by searching for chairs, I got 206 results.
And then the second number right after that is how long it actually took to run the query in milliseconds.
This is not seconds.
It is milliseconds.
In this case, it took one point about seven milliseconds to execute this query.
So at that point we run it a couple of times.
We can just make sure is at 1.6 and like a good average.
As I'm running this, I can see very easily that it goes from about 1.3 all the way up to the 1.6.
Now that we've got that kind of average, we can try to play around with the query a little bit.
For example, what happens if we start to do a fuzzy search?
If I do two sets of percent signs, how does that really impact our search runtime?
As I start to run this, we can see okay.
Yeah, a little bit.
I start to go from the 1.3 to 1.7 to a range of around 1.7 to 2.2.
There definitely is a little bit of an impact by adding on a fuzzy search to this thing.
We can also try to limit down the fuzziness, see what that does.
Now I'm at 1.2 up to about 1.7, so it appears that doing a little bit of a fuzzy search doesn't really
have the biggest impact on performance.
It's that's really all we're going to cover around profile.
I really just want you to know that this command exists and you can use it to get a better understanding
of how adjusting your query and start to affect the performance of your query.