If you log into the application and then click on the dashboard link at the top right hand side, you're
going to get a big area that looks like this.
So we've always had a big error on the dashboard page.
We're going to try to fix that in this video.
First one, begin by helping you understand what information the dashboard page is going to show.
I'm going to go back over to my code editor.
I'm going to find the queries items I use.
Hertz file.
And then inside of here, we've got a items by user function.
I'm going to expand on that function and return an empty array from it.
If I then save this and go back over to the dashboard, I'll now see a little table on here.
So that is what this page is supposed to display.
We're going to show the user all the items that they are trying to sell on our platform.
We're going to show the name, the price, the time left on the auction, the number of bids, number
of views and number of likes.
And each of these different fields are going to be sortable as well.
So we are really doing kind of a search and a sort operation.
We are searching for all the different items that have been created by the user.
And then we are sorting by these different values.
We need to understand a little bit more about sorting with ready search before we start to put any of
this stuff together.
So couple of notes on ready search and sorting.
The ready search itself can sort search results.
We don't have to do a search and then use that sort of command we learned about a long time ago.
Not an easy command at all here.
Instead, we're just going to do a normal search.
And as a part of our query, we're also going to say, please sort the results by some field.
In order to use sorting, we have to update our index.
So we have to specifically say which fields we want to be able to sort by.
By default, we can't just do arbitrary sorting.
We have to say ahead of time how we expect to do our sort.
And then a little limitation here.
We can only sort by one field at a time, so we can't try to say sort by dates or something like that
and find all the items that were created on one day and then within that day apply further sorting by
maybe doing sorting by the items name or something like that.
But only at one sort yield at a time.
Now as we start to create our index, we want to do sorting.
We have to say out of all of our different fields, whether we want them to be sortable or not.
At present, as we've created our index, we have only the name and the description.
And because we did not specifically say that we wanted these to be sortable, they were automatically
marked as non sortable for us.
We definitely want to build a sorts on the items names.
So I'm going to move it over to this sortable column.
So I want to be able to do a search on our items index and be able to search sort by the item name.
And then let's go through all these other properties that are stored inside of an item house as well
and figure out if they should be included inside of our index and whether or not they should be sortable.
Remember we are now talking about using this items index.
Or this entire table right here.
So we definitely need to do an update to the index and we need to mark some of these different fields
as being sortable.
Let's just go down list one by one.
Next up is owner ID.
We do want this to be in our index now because we want to find all the items that have been created
by a very specific person.
But once we find those items, we don't really need to sort by that in any way.
So we're going to add owner ID to our index, but it's going to be non searchable.
Image URL doesn't need to be in our index at all because we are not searching by image URLs.
We're also not sorting by its.
We don't really need to read it out because we're not doing any sorting or searching based on it.
But we are going to be doing some sorting based on ending apps as we got the time left column right
here.
So I'm going to start to include that in my index as a sortable field.
And then views like price and bids are all going to be added into our index as sortable yields because
those are columns that I want people to click on right here and sort my search results.
Okay.
So that's it.
We're going to recreate our index.
We're going to add a bunch of additional fields to the index, and some of those fields will be marked
as sortable.
Let's take a pause right here.
We'll come back in just a moment and we're going to update our index.