Let's go and find where we create our index.
We're going to update our schema definition inside there.
We're going to add on a bunch of additional fields and some of them are going to be marked as sortable.
Back inside my editor.
I'm going to find our Redis create indexes.
Yes.
File.
So here's where our index gets created.
We're going to expand the schema definition of object right here.
I'm going to first begin with that.
So I'm going to add in all our additional properties.
We're going to have everything you see on this list right here.
So let's just add them in one by one.
I'll just put in the keys first, so I'll put in owner ID.
And then ending at.
It's.
Use.
Rice.
And I think that's it.
I think I'm missing one, actually.
We got name, description and Nat views, likes price bids, views, likes that sort of missing.
We get likes on there as well.
They will then go through all these different fields and we're going to mark their type and whether
or not we want to sort by that field as well.
The first off name.
Name is already marked as text.
I want to leave it as that, but now I want to build a sort by it as well.
So I'm going to add on another option here of sort of all true.
Fair description.
I don't ever expect to have to sort by the description.
So add on a sortable.
A false.
And then I want to pause right here really quickly.
You'll notice we're getting a ton of errors from inside this file.
That is because of a small bug inside the typescript definitions around Node Redis.
So we're seeing this here not because of any actual error, it's because of an issue with TypeScript
and how it's interacting with Node Redis.
So to just make this error go away because our code is valid right now, I'm going to go to the end
of the object.
We're working on the schema definition object and put it in as any.
Now the error goes away.
Let's continue on.
Now that the ugly air is out of here with owner I.D., we have to put in a tape and whether or not we
want people to sort by it's the type year is not going to be a pure text field because we never really
expect to do a full text search operation on owner ID.
Instead, we're going to market as TAG is.
We're only ever going to look up items with an owner ID exactly equal to some value.
And remember that is a perfect candidate for a tag field.
We're going to put in a type of schema field types tag.
I do not expect to need to sort by this field.
So I'll put in a sort of bowl of balls.
And then all the remaining values inside of here are going to be identical.
So I'm going to put in the type and sortable for one and then I'll copy paste it down for ending output.
Remember, this is stored as a number inside of Redis, so I'm going to put in a type of schema you'll
type, sort, numeric.
And then sortable here is going to be true because I want to be able to sort by items ending at time.
And then, as I mentioned, we're going to reuse the same type and sortable for all the remaining fields
as well.
So it's going to copy that and paste it on down.
Okay.
So that's it.
Now we've updated our index definition here, but there's just one problem.
Remember how Create Indexes works.
This function gets called whenever our application restarts and whenever it restarts.
We're going to take a look at all the indexes that exist.
And if this index, if items index already exists, we're going to return early from this function.
Even though we just updated our create statement, it's never going to actually run.
How do we try to update a index that already exists?
Well, I got some kind of bad news here.
It turns out that whenever we want to make a change to an index, we can only add fields to it.
We cannot remove fields and we cannot change existing ones.
In this case, because we wanted to take two existing properties, really, one, I should say a religious
name right here.
And market is searchable.
We were trying to make a change to an existing field and that's just not allowed with the current implementation
of indexes.
So in our case, we unfortunately have to manually delete this index and then restart our application
and allow the index to be recreated.
We're going to go and manually delete our index over in our book really quickly.
The back or inside of our book.
I'm going to do a.
After that drop index.
Of IDC's items.
Then I'll go back over to my terminal.
And I'm going to restart my server.
Now if I refresh my browser page here.
I should have recreated the index just to make sure it actually did get recreated correctly.
I'll do a search up here at the top, search for chair, and I should still see some items appear.
I definitely do.
That means that the index was recreated.
All right.
So we've got our updated index.
There are some additional fields in the index and we can sort by them.
Now, we just need to put together some implementation for this table and we'll be all set.