We have updated our index.
So now I'm going to go back to my queries items by user.
Yes, file.
This is a function that's going to be called whenever a user goes to that dashboard page.
So we need to return some items from this function right here that are going to be displayed on that
table.
When this function is called, we're going to be told the user idea, the person who is currently visiting
their dashboard.
So we need to find all the items that were created by that person.
As a second arguments, we'll be given some options.
The options object right here is going to have all the different properties you see inside this interface
up here.
So it will have a page, upper page, a sorts by field, the which attribute or which field you want
to start by and the direction of our sorting as well.
When we return results here.
We're not actually going to return a plane array.
We're going to return an object that has a total pages property.
I'm going to put in a zero for right now and a list of serialized items.
So that's what we are trying to return.
I have dummy values inside of here right now, but we're going to replace those with actual search results
in just a little bit.
Back over inside the browser.
Just make sure everything is really clear.
Whenever a user clicks on a name, that means we want to do a search for all the items created by the
user who is currently signed in.
And we want to sort by the name of the item and we want to do it in a descending behavior.
So we want to start from the list, go up to the most.
Now that's ascending.
We want to go from the most and least descending order.
Anything with price.
If I click price again, I want to sort by ascending order.
And then same thing for time left.
Number of bids.
Number of views and number of likes.
That's worth trying to go for here.
So with all that in mind, let's work on some more implementation.
Okay.
Inside of items by user.
We're definitely going to have to do a search over our items index.
We're going to get back a bunch of item hashes.
So we're going to have to DC realize all those hashes and total.
I think we need to import three things into this file at the very top.
We need to import.
Our read his clients.
From services this.
We need to get our items.
Index key.
From Services Keys.
And then our DC realized function from the same directory DC relies.
Next up.
Inside of our function, we can first begin by creating the query that we want to search with.
So our query here is going to be very, very simple.
We are trying to find all of the item hashes where the owner ID field is equal to what the user ID that
is being passed into this function.
That's it.
So to write out a query that does that.
We'll say query is going to be a template string.
We're going to look at the owner ID field of every hash.
Remember that owner ID inside of our index is a tag.
And to do a query with a tag, we use curly braces instead of parentheses.
Inside of those curly braces.
I'll do a dollar sign.
Curly brace user ID.
That's a query.
That's all it takes.
Next up, we're going to do our source criteria.
Right now, we're going to write out the code for this and then we'll explain what it means in just
a moment.
We'll say sort criteria.
Is going to be options or ops sought sort by.
And Scott's direction.
And.
I'll put in an object right here.
I.
What's not sought by.
And direction.
It's not direction.
Notice that by indirection or in all the capitals.
What's going on with this line.
It's just saying that if we were provided with a source field, so which field to sort by and a direction
that we want to assign this object to sort criteria.
That's all we're saying there.
Otherwise, if we were not given both a sort by and a direction, don't try to assign anything to sort
criteria.
Sort criteria is either going to be this object or undefined.
And it's time for us to do our actual search and our source and the pagination as well.
Because remember, we only want to get back a certain page of results.
We'll say contest total and documents.
Is going to be a wait line for search.
Our first argument will be our items index key.
Then the query.
That's the easy stuff.
We know what those arguments are.
I'll put in another object here.
We're going to specify some of these different options.
But once again, we want to do a search on some hashes.
So I'll put in an on hash.
We want to do a sorts by.
Of sorts.
Criteria.
And then a limit's.
With from offstage times OP starts for page.
And size of object per.
H.
And once again, we're running into a little issue with the typescript definitions here.
So going to mark this entire object with as any just to get that air to go away.
Now I know I'm kind of speeding over this sort by thing.
And the limit thing, the supply is just to say, here's what we are trying to well, sort by.
So we are trying to sort by whatever field was passed into our function as sort by and our direction
is going to be either descending or ascending.
And then the limit is how we are implementing pagination.
We've seen many examples of limits throughout this course already.
We're using limit here just to constrain the number of results we get back.
Just to make sure that everything is working as expected.
Let's try to console.log out total and documents the right.
After I do my search, I'll do a console.log of total.
And documents.
And then going to go over to my browser.
I'm going to make sure I'm signed in and I'm going to create a brand new item to make sure that there's
actually an item to return.
I'm going to put in an item with the name of new chair the duration of one day.
And then go back to my dashboard.
Dashboard still will be empty, but I should have a console.log.
If I go over to my terminal.
Hey, how about that?
I actually see a result here.
So I can see a new chair, which I just created.
I will also see some other items I created in the past couple of videos.
And my total number of results is three.
That's how many items I have created.
The three.
These should all be items I made.
They should not be any items that are made by anyone else.
Let's say this looks good.
We're definitely on the right path here.
Now, the last thing we have to do.
Is take it all in documents and use those two values to return our total number of pages and this items
array as well.
Let's take care of those last steps in just a moment.