When we execute our search, we get back total, which is the total number of results and documents,
which is an array of all the different item hashes we found.
But documents is just a little bit more complicated than that.
I want to point out very quickly, we take a look at that console.log very closely.
You'll notice that documents is actually an array of objects for every object has the ID, which is
actually the key at which our item hash was stored.
And then the value is the item hash itself.
So just keep that in mind for a moment.
We need to take total and documents and use it to return those two properties.
Let's take care of total pages.
First of all is the total number of records we found.
Total pages is the total number of pages.
Assuming that we are using this many items per page.
So to calculate total pages, it will be math dot ceiling.
Of total divided by ops dots per page.
And then four items.
We'll take a look at documents.
We're going to map over all them.
I'm going to structure out the ID and a value.
Now remember, I'm right here is not the actual items ID, it is the key at which the item was stored.
We're going to do a.
These are your lives inside of your.
And then the first argument to this is supposed to be the idea of this item house, this idea right
here.
Not actually the item is it is the key.
So we're going to take that key and we're going to remove the items, pound part of it, and that will
leave us with just the items.
True.
ID in shorts will do an item, not replace.
Items lb with empty string.
And then the second argument to DC lies will be the actual item hash, which is value.
We do get an air here once again, just some funny stuff around TypeScript.
We're going to cheat and just do a value as any.
And that should be it.
I will remove the console.log.
And I think we're ready for a test.
Okay.
Looking pretty good, though.
Now, as I start to look around here, I should be able to click on these things and do some sorting.
I can sort my time left.
I can sort by pretty much nothing else because we don't actually have any other values inside of here.
So I'm going to go and look at how about new chair really quickly and place a bid on this.
If I go back to Dashboard now, I see a price of 50 right there.
So I should be able to sort on that as well.
Yup, definitely can.
If you want to totally optional, you can go and create a whole bunch of additional items and you can
verify that the pagination is working correctly as well.
I'm going to leave that up to you.
Okay.
So let's say this works right now.
Doesn't look that great because we only have a couple of items.
But surely if we actually made a few and put in some more realistic data here, probably look a little
bit better.
But I'm happy with this as is.