Let's continue on inside of Crete indexes.
Yes.
In addition to that key function we just imported, we're going to add in two other imports.
The first is going to be for something called schema field types from the Node Redis library.
We'll also get our retest client from dot slash client as well.
Schema field types is how we are going to designate the types of the different fields that we want to
index.
So in our case, the name and the description fields.
I'll show you how to use this object in just a moment.
So then inside of our function we will return client dot FTE that creates and will pass in the three
arguments I mentioned just a moment ago.
The first will be the key where we are going to store this index and the schema object and then the
options object.
The first will be.
Items index key.
The second will be our schema object.
So to display or to tell node redis what fields we want to index and their types, we're going to put
in the keys of the fields we want to index.
So that's going to be name.
And description.
We're going to set those keys to an object and the object is going to have a type property that describes
what type name is.
How do we want to treat this in our index?
As we mentioned several times, you want to treat the name and the description as text fields and to
indicate that we will add schema fields types that text and notice that text is in all capitals.
We're going to add that to both these objects.
Okay.
And then finally, our third argument.
Is going to be the options object.
So it will designate what kind of object we are trying to add to this index.
So it's going to be a bunch of different hashes as opposed to JSON.
And then our prefix here.
It's going to be items out.
A little note here on the prefix.
Remember we've been using a key generation functions and the entire point there as I have repeated so
many times throughout this course, so that we avoid making any typos around our keys by adding on a
prefix here that is a plain string.
We're kind of breaking that rule.
So one thing we could do to make this prefix a little bit safer here is by importing our key generation
function for a plain item hash.
So you might recall that the function for that is called items key.
That's a function where we can put in an item ID and we'll get back a string of items around and then
whatever item ID we put in.
Back go inside of Crete indexes.
I'm going to impart that really quickly.
And to make sure that we don't make any typos on this prefix whatsoever.
We can make use of the items key function and just put in an empty string.
So that will give us back.
Exactly items found.
Once again, as usual, as I repeated so many times, this is just going to make sure that we avoid
making any typos.
Okay.
So that's pretty much it.
We've now got our index in theory ready to be created.
This part wasn't so bad, but now we're going to start to get to a little bit more advanced topic,
which is when do we create our index?
So we've got a function that can be used to create an index, but when are we going to actually call
it?
This is a little bit more challenging than you might think, for one simple reason.
If we have an index that has already been created, I'm going to go back over to our book really quickly.
Back over here.
We have an index that has already been created in here called idea cars.
If I try to call, create again and recreate that index, I end up getting an error.
So right now, if we just call our create indexes function that we just put together, if we just call
that say every single time that our application starts up, we would end up getting errors all over
the place.
So we might want to have a little bit more intelligent way of deciding when we need to actually call
our index creation function.
Let's go into some more details on this in the next video.