As we just saw a moment ago, trying to create the same index twice is going to lead to an error.
So before we try to create our index, we should probably actually check and make sure that it needs
to be created.
We should probably do this whenever our application starts up.
So here's the general idea.
Here's what we're going to try to implement.
We're going to say that whenever our application starts up and we first connect to Redis, we're going
to look into Redis and get a list of all the different indexes that already exist.
We're then going to see if the index that we're trying to make has already been created.
If it does, then we're not going to do anything otherwise.
If our index has not yet been created, go ahead and create it.
So in theory, pretty simple and straightforward.
The first thing we need to figure out, however, is how do we get a list of all the different indexes
that already exist?
There's another command we can use to get a list of all these different indexes.
Let me show you how to use it back inside of our book really quickly.
The back over here at the very bottom, I'm going to add in a new code cell and do a FC dot underscore
list.
That's a.
If we run that command, we'll get back an array of strings.
These are the keys of all the different indexes that exist.
You'll notice that in my application I've already gone and created the items index.
So you're probably only going to see index cars right now, which is totally fine, totally to be expected.
I just kind of jumped ahead a little bit and made the index already.
So before we make our index, we're going to run underscore list.
We're going to see if the index we're trying to create has already been created.
If it has returned early.
Otherwise make the index.
That's it.
Let's get to it.
I can send my editor.
I'm going to find Crete indexes.
Inside of here.
I'm going to two fine indexes as a weight client to underscore list.
That's going to give us back an array of strengths.
We're going to iterate through that and try to find the index we are trying to create.
So I'm going to do exists is indexes not find.
And for each index I'm going to return.
True.
If index is equal to.
The key where our index is going to be stored at, which is items index key.
So items index key.
If we are able to find a match.
So if exists, then return early.
Otherwise go on and create the index.
All right.
So that's going to take care of making sure we don't try to what creepy index when it's already been
made.
So now we just need to make sure that we actually call this create indexes function when our app first
connects to Redis.
To do so we can go back over to our Reddit's clients file.
Your ID is right here.
After we create our clients, we can add on a callback function and say once we successfully connect
threads, try to call that create indexes function.
At the top of this file I'm going to import creates indexes.
From create indexes.
And then down at the very bottom of the file.
Right after the connect statement or right before, it doesn't make a big difference.
I'm going to add in a client dot on connect.
So this will be called as soon as we connect to Redis.
And inside of here I want to do and await.
Creates indexes.
And I need to mark the enclosing function as async.
We should also add in just a little bit of air handling around us just to capture the scenario in which
the index fails for some reason.
Who knows, maybe we accidentally try to create some index with invalid syntax or any variety of different
issues.
So I'm going to wrap this with a try.
And if anything goes wrong, I'll do a console.
Air of the air.
Okay.
So that should be it.
So now if I save the application and go back over to my browser and refresh the app as soon as I refresh
the app, that will ensure that I am issuing a or creating a connection over to Redis.
So now, in theory, our index should have been created.
If I go to my terminal, I shouldn't see any errors over here.
I don't.
So that means everything looks good.
So now, in theory, the index has been created to verify that we can go back to our book, which is
connected to the same instance for me as our e-commerce application.
As long as you are connected to the same instance, we should be able to now do an FTA dot underscore
list and see the items index has been created.
Okay.
So that's pretty good.
Now, one thing that we have not really touched on is how we can update this index.
So if we decide to add additional fields to the index at some point in time, how would we take care
of that?
Don't worry.
We're going to touch on that a little bit later on.
As soon as we finish up this search operation.
So let's pause here when we come back in the next video.
Make sure that a user can type into that text input right here and actually see some search results
come back.