Our index has been created.
So now we need to make sure that whenever a user enters in some text right here, we take that text
and use it to conduct an actual search.
I've already created a function that will be called with a user's text, so let's go and find where
that function is defined, and we're going to put all of our searching logic inside there.
Back inside my editor, I'm going to find queries, items and then search thoughts.
So this function will be called automatically.
Any time a user types into that text input, it's going to receive two different arguments.
The first is the raw search term, so that is exactly whatever text the user entered.
And then the second argument will be how many search results we want to get back by default, it is
five, so at most five results.
But if we only get back one or two, that's totally fine as well.
We're not going to worry about capping the number of search results just yet.
We'll take care of that in just a moment.
So inside of here, we're going to go through two different operations.
We're going to first take whatever search term the user just entered, and we're going to clean it up
a little bit.
Remember, we don't really want to just take the user's text and just throw it directly into the search
command.
Instead, we probably want to do some processing on it.
Right now we are trying to implement Fuzzy Search.
We're not doing a prefix or doing fuzzy search over all of our different items, names and descriptions.
So we need to take the string that the user entered.
We're going to do some preprocessing by stripping out some symbols and stuff like that.
We might want to wrap all the different search terms with parentheses, parentheses, so we get some
fuzzy searching.
And then we need to decide if we want to do an end to operation for the search or an or operation.
A couple of different decisions have to be made here.
Let's first focus on just taking the user search term and cleaning it up a little bit.
All right.
So back inside of search items.
I'll make a new variable.
I'm going to call it cleaned.
This is going to be the user's search term and they going to change on a couple of different methods
just to pass it and clean it up a little bit.
The first thing I'm going to do is replace all of the non alphanumeric characters or spaces.
So if a user enters in any symbols here or something like that, I'm going to remove all those extra
symbols.
We can do so by adding in a regular expression.
I'm going to put in.
Q Four flashes and then a g an inside of the Ford slashes all add in square brackets inside those.
I'll put in a carrot and I'll put in lowercase a2 z.
Uppercase A to Z.
0 to 9 and then a space.
And then after the entire regular expression, I'll put in an empty string.
That means find all the characters that are not alphanumeric or a space and just take them out of the
string entirely.
Then after that, I'm going to do a trim operation.
So if a user enters in any extra spaces at the end of the string.
Or the start of the string.
I just want to take those extra spaces out.
So I will do a dot trim.
Then following exactly what we have in this diagram right here.
I'm going to do a split operation on that string on any space we have.
We're going to split that entire string into separate individual words.
So we'll do a dot split.
On a string with a space in it.
That's going to give us our array of strings and then going to map through all these different strings
and wrap each individual word with percent, the search term percent.
We can do that with a.
And for each word.
I'm going to return.
Word inside of a template string.
I'm going to put in a percent dollar sign.
Curly brace.
Closing curly brace percent.
Just to handle the case in which we might have a couple of extra spaces in between words.
So something like this right here, I'm going to add in one little check here.
I'm going to make sure that if there is a word that I want to return that wrap version.
Otherwise, just return empty string, if that doesn't make sense right there.
Don't sweat it.
All this is doing is removing a couple of additional empty spaces that were not captured during the
initial trim.
And then finally we're going to take all these cleaned up turns, all the individual words that have
been wrapped by these parentheses.
We're going to join it all together into a string.
In this first version, I'm going to do an end search operation.
So it's going to look something like this.
We can then come back later on and try putting in a pipe to symbolize in or search.
We'll see how it affects our search results.
So to join this all back together.
All do join.
With a space.
Okay.
So we've now got our cleaned up term.
Now that we've got the cleaned up term or ready to do a query, we're going to have to import a couple
of things at the top.
So we need to get our read his client.
We need to get our items index key.
We're also going to get our serialize function as well.
When we actually do our search, we're going to get back an array of item objects and we need to make
sure we serialize those so we can actually be used by the rest of our application.
So at the very top, I'm going to import client.
From services this.
These serialized from dot slash these serialized.
And then items index key.
From Services Keys.
All right.
Now, once again, I don't want this video to go on too long.
So let's take a quick pause right here and then wrap up search items in just a moment.