We've got our import statements.
We've got our cleaned up search term.
And we're going to add in the actual searching operation.
We're going to break this up into a couple of separate steps.
Number one, I'm going to look at cleaned.
And make sure it is valid.
I'll show you what that means in just a moment.
Well, then use the client to do.
An actual search.
And then I'm going to serialize and return these search results.
That's our three big steps.
First off, step number one.
We just went through some parsing operation right here.
We potentially removed a lot of different characters.
Now we need to make sure that the user actually gave us a valid string to search with.
So imagine if a user gave us a string like a bunch of symbols right there.
Our first operation inside of that clean up syntax, that clean up step we have, is going to remove
all these different symbols.
And so if a user gave us this string, we would end up with empty string.
And I don't really want to do a search with an empty string because that would probably just return
all the different items we have inside of our database.
I want our user to actually give us some valid search.
So I'm going to look at cleaned right here.
And if cleaned.
Is an empty string and I'm going to return an empty array, which kind of indicates we were not able
to find any search results.
Then on step number two, we're going to use our red as client to do the actual search.
This is where we are going to call the search command and pass in a couple of arguments to the search
operation.
So I'm going to get results from a wait client for that search.
The arguments to this are going to be the key where are indexes stored?
So that is items index key.
And then the second argument is going to be our actual query.
Now remember, a lot of our queries look like, say at name oil and blah, blah, blah.
But in our case, right now we are doing a full text search so we can utilize a little bit of a shortcut.
If we put in a query that is just a plain, simple string without any special syntax in it whatsoever,
and Redis is going to take that entire string and use it to automatically search all the different fields
that are marked as type text inside of our index.
So you and I don't have to put in that fancy at name stuff here because we are trying to do a full tech
search over all the available text fields inside of our index.
So we're going to put in our cleaned up search term and that's it.
And one other thing we're going to take care of very quickly.
Remember that one of the arguments to our function is the number of results that we expect to get back.
So we want to limit how many results we get, just in case our search has, say, 500 results.
I don't want to send those all back over to my server.
I just want to get the first five and that's it.
To limit the number of results that we gets.
I'm going to add on a third argument here of an object that has a limit key.
And then limit is going to be from zero.
And size of size.
From is like an offset.
If we had a frame of ten, that means set the first ten search results and then take however many sizes
after that.
So size is five.
That means skip the first ten, take the next five.
In our case, we're just always trying to get the first five.
So we're going to have a hardcoded from a zero and then our size is going to be whatever the size argument
is.
Because the key and the value here are identical.
We can condense it down like so.
Now at this point, who knows what results actually is?
So I think we should just do a console log of results and see what we actually get back from the search
operation.
After we understand what kind of data we are working with, we can actually implement the DC realized
step.
I'm going to do a console.log of results right there.
Okay.
Let's go back over to the browser and test this out.
So going to refresh the page.
I'll then do a search for chair.
Once I enter that, I'll go back over to my terminal and take a look at what console.log we got.
Okay.
So we've got a big object here.
It has a documents property, which is an array.
So we want to take a look at that documents property.
That's going to give us back this array of search results and this value right here even though it looks
like hey scary console.log that is actually our serialized item hash so we really want to map over the
documents array look at all the individual value properties and serialize whatever we got provide right
there as a value.
Okay.
So back inside of our editor.
For step number three, i'm going to return results that daqing documents.
I'm going to map over that.
I'm going to take.
The ID and the value by using a little bit of structuring.
So notice the curly braces right there.
And then call serialize and then remember really quickly serialize.
The first argument is the ID and the second is going to be the serialized item.
So that's why ID structured out both the ID property and the value, so I can pass in first the ID and
then the value.
We are going to get a little bit of a tip air right here on the D.C. release function trying to pass
in value.
That is a little bit of an issue with how the types are set up around the Node Regis library itself.
So we're just going to kind of cheat around this little bit and put in as any just to make this code
work.
Okay.
So let's save this now.
And then one more test.
So back inside the browser all to refresh and then search for chair.
And sure enough it actually works.
Now I see some different chair results.
Chair Great.
Chair I do.
Table I have a table here.
So it's that table right there.
I do.
Table.
Yep.
There's table.
I should be able to your chair as well.
Let's see what else I have.
I've got a desk as well.
I put in desk?
Yep.
There we go.
Desk.
All right.
So it looks like the search operation is definitely working.
Now, I would like to add in a lot more data to our application.
So I want to throw in a ton of different items with a bunch of kind of randomized item names and descriptions.
And then we're going to play around with how we form up our search query and really understand the impact
of how we can mess around with that query that we're passing in to get some kind of different results.