We could do a much better job of trying to optimize our searching operation if we had a lot more data
inside of our app.
So if we just had a lot more items with somewhat realistic item names and descriptions.
Luckily I put together a little script for us.
It's inside of our project directory in the Seeds folder.
Inside here is a seed file.
This generates a whole bunch of fake data and then puts it into our Red Hat database.
It's going to create a bunch of items and users.
It has somewhat realistic item names and descriptions.
If you run the seed script, it's going to insert a lot of data into Redis, but it's also going to
delete all the data that already exists inside there.
So if you run the seed script, make sure you are not connected to any important.
Read a database that has any information that you want to keep around.
Okay.
Let me show you how to run the scripts.
Well, just make sure it works.
Back over at my terminal.
I'm going to stop my running server and then execute NPM run seed.
And that's it.
Once I've executed that script well, then start my server back up with NPM.
Run Dev.
Then back inside my browser, I can see a huge list of brand new items they've all got.
Again, pretty reasonable titles, I guess, and their descriptions are also pretty long as well.
So notice that there's a lot of text inside of here, and the text generally follows a trend of sorts,
though in particular, this one has a name of a kind of wood.
This is beech in this case.
A bunch of bids have also been created and tied to the item.
Now, any data you already had inside of Rita's has been deleted.
So if you want to add a bid or anything like that, you do have to create a brand new account and sign
into it.
I'm going to take care of that right now.
Plug it to sign up and create new accounts.
You can run that seat command as often as you want.
All the items in there have runtimes that are based upon the current time.
When you run the speed command.
So in other words, if I wait, say a week right now to finish up the rest of the course, all these
items are going to end up being expired.
So if you come back in a week just to rerun the seed command and a bunch of additional items will be
created that are going to end relative to the time when you run that command.
Okay.
So we've now got some more realistic data here.
So now we're going to start to play around with our search query and figure out what kind of options
are going to modify the results and make it a little bit more ideal.