Our searching is definitely working, but in some cases it's not working quite as well as I would hope.
Let me show you an example.
The very first item I see right here is generic wooden gloves.
So if I do a search for wooden, I definitely see many items that have the word wooden in the name that's
working as expected.
But if I do a search for, say, chair.
I don't see any items that have the word chair in the name.
If I click on any item.
Share does appear in the items description.
A one right there and one right there.
Remember, we are searching over all the text fields for every single item.
So seeing cheer up here in the description means that this is technically a valid search results.
But I would really like to favor items that have the word chair in the name of the item rather than
always showing items that have chair in the description only.
That's just going to make it appear that our search result results are a little bit more relevant.
Just be clear.
There are items with the word chair in the name.
So if I do a search for, say, button chair, I will see an item right there with chair in the name.
So we need to do some tweaks around our search.
We need to make sure that we kind of fever items that have a search term in the name as opposed to the
description.
To understand how to do this.
I want to do a overall deep dive on search just so we can understand how these searching algorithm works
behind the scenes.
That's going to give us a better idea of how we can tweak the searching behavior to better suit our
needs.
To better understand how research works.
We're going to imagine a very simple scenario.
We're going to imagine we have two strings that we are searching over.
So string one and string two.
It will imagine that we run some kind of query where the search term is simply fruit.
That's it.
Nothing else.
I really want to focus on how ready search decides whether is will give us back search results of first
string one and then string two or string two and then string one.
So in other words, how does Ready Search decide which of these two strings is more relevant to this
search term?
I want to walk through the algorithm that Reddit search internally uses.
We're going to figure out how it works.
And then once we understand how it works, we'll be able to better manipulate the searching mechanism.
All right, so ready search uses something called ATF, IDF algorithm.
This is a relatively simple and pretty easy to understand searching algorithm.
With this algorithm, we can take a look at a bunch of different strings and decide which one is most
relevant for any given search term.
The IDF works by taking in something called a term frequency and multiplying it by something called
an inverse document frequency.
This results in a score for each individual string.
A higher score means that that string is more relevant to some given search result.
The term frequency is calculated by looking at how many times a search term appears in a string, and
then we divide it by the total number of words in the string.
I'm going to show you that in action in just a moment.
And then the IDF or inverse document frequency is a little bit more involved calculation.
We'll go over that in a second as well.
All right, so let's try calculating the term frequency and inverse document frequency for both these
strings given a search term of fruit.
So here's the calculation.
But for each separate string we'll calculate taf times the IDF.
The term frequency is how many number of times our search term appears in a string.
This first string right here, the word fruit appears twice, once here and once here.
Do we get a two?
We then divide that by the number of words in the string.
There are one, two, three, four, five, six.
So we end up with a six.
We then multiply by that the logarithm of one, plus the total number of strings in our entire search
set divided by the total number of strings containing our search term.
So in our case, our entire search set has two strings inside of it.
Hence the two right there.
And they both contain our search term a fruit.
So we get a two right there.
And if we do this entire calculation, we end up with a score of point one.
That is a search score of the term roots on this particular string.
We then repeat that same process for our second string.
In this case, we end up with one divided by two and then the same logarithm.
Are same term for the same value for the logarithm term, and we end up with a final score of 0.15.
So in this case, we would say that good fruit is more relevant and we would rate that higher inside
of our search results.
So this would appear first and then we would see excellent fruit, good fantastic fruit right after
it.
And just to be clear.
This searching algorithm that I'm showing you right here, the actual the actual calculation done by
ready search is slightly, slightly different.
It takes into account some extra parameters as well.
So, for example, they're going to take into account how many words occur between search terms or the
word that we're searching for inside of a string.
So in the case of the first string right here, we have three words in between.
And so that will be accounted for inside of ready search.
But more or less, this is pretty much exactly what's going on inside of ready search.
Okay.
Now, a couple of variations on this I want to look at very quickly.
Let's imagine what would happen if we have two separate search terms.
So fruit and good, we would do the same calculation for each individual term.
So we would do one calculation right here for fruit and then a second calculation for the word good.
And then we would add those scores together and get .15.
We repeat the same process for the second string as well.
We have one calculation for fruit, another calculation for good, and there is our score.
So in this case, if we search for fruit and good, we would still end up with string two down here
ranking higher.
And so that would be shown first.
Now, last variation I want to show you is that we can add on additional weights to individual terms.
So we could do a query where we say find fruit and good.
But anytime we see the word good, give that twice as much importance as the word fruit.
So we would expect to see documents or strings that contain good.
Appear higher inside of our search results than those that don't contain the word gut or maybe the less
usages of the word good.
The two apply a weight.
We'll still do the exact same calculation for fruit right here, and then we'll do the same initial
calculation for good.
But then once we get the score right there, we just multiply it by two, but places more importance
on the word good.
We can make use of waits inside of ready search really easily, not only to weight specific search terms,
but we can also make sure that we try to weight specific fields as well.
And that's what we are really focused on.
Let me show you an example of that in the next video.