We just took a look at the ATF, ATF algorithm.
And at the very end of the last video I showed you that we could apply a weight to an individual term.
Now we want to do something like this, but we don't want to wait a term.
Instead, we want to wait a field.
Let me show you an example of what I mean for our particular application.
Okay.
So remember, all of our different items have names and descriptions.
Let's imagine we have two different items.
So item one over here has a name of chair, and then item two has a description of chair.
Chair, chair.
At present, our application is considering any search term that occurs inside the name to be equal
in importance to any occurrence of that search term inside that description.
So if we apply the TF RDF algorithm with a search term of chair to these two items right now, we would
definitely rank term or mean item number two over your higher.
Because it contains chair, chair cheer as the description.
But that's not what we really want.
We don't want to place great importance on item number two here.
We don't want to rank it higher.
We want to rank item number one higher, specifically because the name field contains chair.
So we want to apply a weight not to the search term but to the field.
We want to tell ready search that if our search term occurs inside the name, we should place a lot
of importance on that compared to if we see a search term inside the description.
Let's take a look at how we can wait a yield instead of a term.
Okay.
So to do so, we're going to update our query just a little bit.
It's going to look something like this.
This means look at the name field of each individual hash and look for chair.
And if we find here inside there, apply a five times weight to it.
So consider the word chair occurring inside the name field to be five times as important as the word
chair occurring inside of an item's description.
This will definitely force ready search to rank item number one higher, which is what we definitely
want.
Okay.
So this is probably going to be a better query for our purposes.
But there's one last week we need to do to it.
If we ever write out a query like this that looks at one field and then a second field, this is interpreted
as being an end to query by ready search.
So this means find only the items where we have a name containing chair and a description containing
chair.
In other words, only items that have chair in the name and the description.
So we ran this query on item one in item two.
We would not get any results back because neither of them contain chair inside the name and the description.
We need to do just a little bit of a tweak to this.
We need to say find all the items where either name occurs.
I chair occurs in the name and or chair occurs in the description.
We really want to turn it from an end to an end or.
Do an and or operation with multiple fields.
We're going to wrap each field with a set of parentheses and then put a pipe symbol in between them.
This means find all the items with care in the name and or chair in the description.
And if we find chair in the name, give it five times the importance.
Okay.
So let's go back over to our editor.
We're going to update our query and use something like this instead of the very plain query that we
have currently implemented.
The back over inside my editor.
Right above our actual search.
I'm going to add in a new string right here of Mary.
And it's going to be parentheses at name.
Well in parentheses and I'm going to insert cleaned in there.
And the author.
At Description.
Well in parentheses.
And putting cleans.
And then I'm going to apply a five times weight to the name field right after that parentheses right
there I'm going to put in equals greater than.
Really braces.
Dollar sign weights 5.0.
Now please double check your syntax and all your spelling inside of your.
If you make any error, you will be told that something is wrong with the query.
But it doesn't always point you exactly to where you need to go to fix it.
So it's a lot easier if you just write this out correctly right now.
Well, now take our query and we're going to use it inside of our search operation instead of the plain
cleaned string.
And that should be it.
So I'm going to save this and then go back over to the browser and do a quick test.
Back over here.
Now I'm going to search for Chair and I will, in fact, see items that have chair mentioned inside
them.
Very good.
Now we need to make sure that if we search for some term, that does not occur in any item's name.
We at least still show items that have that term inside the description.
So if I search for, say, natural, I can see that natural occurs in this item's description.
I'm not going to see any items where we have natural inside the items name just because there are no
items that have natural inside the name.
But if I click on any of these results, I should see natural.
Occur inside the description.
And sure enough, I do.
There it is right there.
All right.
So I'd say that this is a very good result.
We are prioritizing items that have a search term inside the name.
And if we don't have that term inside the name, we fall back to the description instead.