While we are discussing how search works, I want to show you two different commands you can use to
better understand the search process.
The first is explained.
Seelye We're going to run this with a name of an index and a query that we want to try to run explain.
Seelye is not going to actually execute the query.
Instead, it's going to take a look at your query and give you some information about how it understands
the query and how it thinks it should actually be executed.
We're going to use, explained Seelye, usually to make sure that our queries are being interpreted
correctly.
And I'm going to show you an example of when you think you might be writing out a query correctly,
but it turns out there's actually an issue with it.
Okay, so let's go over to our book and try out this command very quick.
So over in our book I'm going to do a PhD, explains Seelye.
I'd items and then my query is going to be simply chair.
Here's our results.
Now, the first thing I want to highlight here is the word that says plus chair expanded.
You might recall that a little bit ago I spoke about that concept of swimming inside of ready search.
That is where Ready Search might take a word like chairs, chaired or chairing or some other variations.
And it's going to assume that all those different variations really mean the same thing as the word
chair.
So stimming is where we can go from some of these more complex terms down to a more simple term.
And you see expanded right here.
We're kind of doing the opposite of stimming.
So Chair expanded means take the base word of chair and try to come up with some different variations
or some expanded forms of the word chair.
So when you do a query on share, that will be automatically expanded into searching not only chair
but also chairs chaired in chairing.
Then in addition to those extra searches, it is, of course, going to do a search on the original
search term and then across all of these different queries, all these different terms that are being
searched for.
We're going to take the union of all those.
That means do a search for chair, do a search for all the different expanded forms of chair in all
these different search results.
Get the scores for all them and then put them all together into one search results set sorted by all
the different search result rankings or the different scores.
Now, as we start to add in a more complex story here, we're going to see how this explain can really
start to get a little bit more complex.
I'm going to try to do chair minus desk.
So this query means find chair, find all the desks and don't show any results for desk inside the final
results.
If I do that.
Now we're still going to do the original union of chair and Chair expanded.
We're also going to do a separate search of find everything that does not contain a desk and then do
the intersection between these two groups of results to find what is common between the union and the
nuts operation.
Now this is definitely useful for just understanding.
Okay?
This is kind of what is going on behind the scenes are it's doing a union and not an intersection,
but at the end of the day, it's not really the most useful thing.
Let me show you what I mentioned a little bit ago, a real use case I've explained.
Seelye Just a little bit ago, we put together a command back inside of our editor.
So this one right here.
And you might recall, I mentioned in passing, we have to put the parentheses around each individual
field.
So what would happen if we didn't add in those parentheses?
Let's try it out really quickly with, explains Eli.
They're going to do that name.
Chair or at description.
Share.
If I run that.
You'll notice that the explain run successfully.
I get back results.
So as far as ready search is concerned, this is absolutely a valid query.
But if you look at the actual very plan right here, you're going to notice something really unexpected.
The entire description field, for some reason got converted to null.
So if we actually run this search right here, we run the query like this, we will probably have it
succeed, but we're probably not going to get what we really want because for some reason, even though
this is interpreted as being a valid query, the description field got turned into null instead.
If I then add on some parentheses around each term.
Like so.
And then rerun the explain.
Now it's definitely working as expected.
The do name.
You description and then join those two separate groups together.
Okay.
So that is explain, Seeley.
There's one other debug command we're going to look at in just a moment.