On to the get items function.
This function is going to be pretty interesting to put together.
It's going to require us to learn a new topic in Redis.
So let me give you a very quick side topic here, very quick side story to help you understand why this
is going to be an interesting function.
Okay.
Very quick example.
Let's imagine we are building a different application and we have an incoming request that says give
me the details about cars with the IDs by five, three, six, oh one and so on.
This is actually kind of challenging for us to do right now because you'll notice that all the different
commands we have learned about, such as each get all, each set each get and so on.
They all work on one single hash.
One of the words, one single key.
But we now are getting a request saying go and fetch a wide variety of different records.
So how do we somehow tell is that we don't want to fetch one single hash.
We want to get a variety of different hashes.
Let's first begin by taking a look at two different options.
The first option I want to show you, just because you will see some documentation, some blog posts
that show this as a possible way of implementing this, but it's definitely not ideal.
So this is an option, but probably you do not want to do this.
So notch.
Number one, very obvious solution.
We might take a look at all the IDs that the user has provided us, and we might loop over that list
of IDs and then do a separate each, get all one by one inside of a for loop or something similar.
This would definitely work.
We would definitely fetch all the data we're looking for, but there's a very clear downside.
We are making a wide variety of different separate requests off to Redis, and so that's just plain
going to take some amount of time if we are trying to fetch, say, 100 different records.
We're talking about making 100 different requests over to Redis, though probably not going to be very
ideal.
Let's take a look at option number two.
All right.
Option number two is going to use a feature in red is referred to as pipe lining.
Pipeline essentially means take a bunch of different commands and dump them all into one single command
and then throw that one single, big giant command off to Redis.
Though in this scenario we might still loop over all of our different IDs and tried to say, Hey, I
want to fetch the car with ID five, five, three and 67789, four, one, nine and so on.
But the big difference here is that we're essentially saying don't send the command off just yet.
So set all these commands up, but don't actually issue them.
Once we finish the for loop and creates or initialize these different commands, we can then say, All
right, take a look at all those commands that we had queued up.
And now in one big batch, send them off to lettuce.
So in one single connection, we can send off this big group of different Skittles, one for each individual
card that we're trying to fetch.
Reddest understands this idea of batching commands together.
So it's going to take the big pile of commands, break them all out into separate individual ones,
and execute each of them one by one.
The net result is that in response, we're going to get back a list.
Of sorts, containing the results of all the different commands that we just executed.
So we will get back a list of all these different cars in one single response.
Again, this is referred to as pipelines.
And before implementing pipelines inside of our application, I would like to do a quick little side,
a little bit of code back inside that sandbox folder that we worked on a little bit ago.
Just so you understand how to implement pipelines specifically with JavaScript and of course, TypeScript.
A quick pause right here, and we're going to work on a very small little side task with Pipeline.