Quick little side project just to understand how pipeline works.
So back inside, my editor.
I'm going to go to my root project directory.
Why not sandbox folder again and open up the index to yes file.
I've still got a little bit of code in here.
I'm going to find the run function.
I'm going to find the car that we did right there, and I'm going to delete everything from that line
down to the console log of car.
I'm just left with our single H set right here.
All right.
So to understand pipe lining, I want to try to create three separate hashes.
I then want to create a pipeline and fetch all three in one single request off to Redis.
The first, of course, we need to create three separate hashes.
I will duplicate the age sets we're doing right here twice, and then I'll change a little bit around
each age set.
On the first one, I'll change it to R one and car two and car three for the keys on each one.
I'll change the year on each as well.
Only the first one.
That's 1950.
This one I'll change to 1955 and 1960.
And why not?
I'll just change the colors as well.
Okay.
So now we've got our three different hashes created.
So now it's time for us to create a pipeline, send over three, separate each, get all but all them
together into really one single request.
So quick diagram on how we do that.
We are making use of a client library called Node Redis.
And unfortunately, the way pipeline is done in Node Redis is a little bit different than how pipe learning
is done with every other Rattus client library out there.
Not only for JavaScript, but for many other languages as well.
So if you are not going to use the node register library happening is going to be done.
Kind of like what you see right here.
This is an example written with Python.
So in the Python world to create a pipeline, you're going to take your register client, you're going
to call a method on it called pipeline.
You'll then attach or run a couple of different commands, attach that pipe object that you get back,
and then eventually call this execute function on it.
And as you guess, execute is going to run all the different commands you kind of batch together.
Unfortunately, we are not using Python, we're not using a different breed as client.
So setting up pipeline for us, like I said, a little bit different in the Node Redis world, which
is of course what we are using.
Setting up a pipeline doesn't really involve anything that specifically says, Hey, make a pipeline
for me with no threats.
We're going to instead run all of our different commands in an array that we're going to pass off to
a built in function called Promise Dot all.
So we might do a client talk, get another client talk.
Yet we can do each get all in each set a set, any different commands we want.
And in all these commands we're going to take them all, put them into an array and pass them off to
Promised Dot all.
Also very notably, we're not going to put a weight in front of any of the client commands.
By passing these all up to the promise.
Not all.
That's kind of a sign to Node Redis that we want to execute all these commands at the same time and
batch them all together to send off to Rita's.
All right, so let's give that a shot.
Back over inside of index.
Yes.
I'm going to do an await promised call and pass in an array.
And then inside this array we're going to put in as many different separate commands as we want.
And most notably, again, we're not going to use the a keyword.
So I'll do a client h get all of our one.
Our two.
And three.
After we do the await right here.
The result is an array of all the results from these different commands we're executing.
So the first element in this array will be the results of that command.
Second will be the results of that command.
Third will be the results of that command.
Now, if we do a console.log on results.
We should see all three separate cars get console.log.
All right, let's test this out very quickly.
So back in our terminal, remember to run that sandbox file.
You can open up a second terminal window and execute npm run sandbox.
And sure enough.
There we go.
I've got an array.
Couple objects inside of it.
One for each car we had created.
So that's pretty much it.
That's how we set up pipeline with Node Redis.
Now, one thing you might be curious about.
No, you do not have to write out all the separate commands like so you can create the commands inside
of a for loop or using a mapping statement.
So just as a very quick example.
I'm going to say Conte's commands.
I'm going to create an array with one, two and three.
And then going to map over that array.
This inner function will be called with first that number, then that number and then that number.
I refer to those as an argument called ID.
And then inside the mapping function I will return client h gets all.
With car less ID.
Now, instead of passing in an array of all the commands right there that I'm writing out in line,
I can pass in this commands array instead.
This is 100% equivalent to what we just had a moment ago.
Now if I save that and flick back over again, same exact results.
One other thing I want to mention.
When we are making use of pipeline, we do not have to only run one single kind of command.
We can mix in and get all and in each set and a get and a set, a delete.
As many different commands as we want, we can throw them all together into one single pipeline and
we're actually going to take advantage of that feature several times later on inside this course.
All right, so that's it.
That's the basics of pipeline.
We're going to use it any time we want to run a whole big batch of commands in one single group.
Now that we've got some knowledge around that, we'll take a pause right here.
We'll come back to our items doctor's file and we'll put together that JIT items function in just a
moment.