Now that we understand pipelines we can implement our git items function back inside that items.
Yes file.
So inside of here, we're going to use that same technique that we used that showed you at the end of
the last video.
We've got an array of IDs, so we're going to map over that array and create one command for every single
ID.
After we do that, mapping step will then use that promise dot all function to execute all those different
commands at the same time.
Okay.
So I'll do a commands.
Is ID's dot map.
And for every single ID we will return client h gets all.
We need to pass in the key, do the hash that we're trying to fetch.
Now, remember, anytime that we're trying to find a key or generate a key, we're going to use our
key function called items key.
Or put in items e at the ID.
So that gives us our commands.
And then to actually execute them, we have to pass that array of commands into a promised call.
So we will say Colin's results is await promised, not all.
We had commands.
So that's going to actually execute them.
And we get back an array of results.
The array of results are the results of running an H, get all commands and we get back a hash.
We still have to go through all those same operations that we do when we were matching an individual
item.
So for any individual item that we fetched, we got that hash and we have to make sure that we did not
get an empty object.
So we still have to do that when we're fetching a list of items.
And after we are sure that we did not get back and hit the object, we still have to go through the
serialization step as well.
So we've got to do the same thing down here for get items for every single result.
But for that we can do another mapping statement map over the list of results and handle empty objects
and realization all in one step.
To look at results, not map.
And for every single results, I'm going to first check to make sure that we do not have an empty object.
If object keys results dot length is equal to zero, then return null.
And then if we get past that.
Okay.
I guess we found something.
We found some data, so we need to serialize it.
We will call the serialize.
And then our first argument here is the idea of this record.
And the second will be the actual data that we want to serialize.
Just one problem.
We don't actually have access to the ID because right now we are mapping over the results array.
So we need to somehow figure out which result is tied to which ID we had fetched the handle.
That's the second argument to a mapping function I put in the parentheses right there is the index.
So I that's the index of the current result we are iterating over.
But figure out what the ID is of this result right here.
We can look up the index inside the IDS array.
Now we'll give us the ID of this results.
Long story short, all we have to do right here is IDs at I.
That's it.
All right.
So that results dot map is going to take care of handling the empty objects and you serialization it's
going to give us back an array of results or really an array of items in this case.
And that's what we're trying to return from this function so we can return.
Results dot map and that's pretty much it.
That's our entire IT items function.
All right, let's save that.
And that's pretty much it for get items.
Now this function we can't really easily test inside of our application just yet.
We can later, but not just yet, because we have to put together some other stuff first.
Though, we're not going to unfortunately be able to test this right away.
But we did get that example of Pipeline put together inside the sandbox.
And as I mentioned, we're going to use Pipeline in several other times.
So we will get a lot of practice around it.
Last I want to mention is that we are going to come back to this item Stotts file and specifically mess
around with this create item function quite a bit as we start to set up some other features inside of
our app.
Well, that's pretty much it for items right now, and that's pretty much it for pipelines, at least
right now and definitely hashes.
Let's continue on to our next major data type in Redis in just a moment.