We're all done implementing the bid history feature and in general, we're pretty much done with the
primary section on lists for right now.
So we're going to move on and finish up some implementation around bids in general.
So we're going to make sure that users can bid on items and eventually win them as well.
We're also going to add in some validation logic as well.
So you might notice that right now I'm looking at an item whose auction ended one day ago, but I'm
still very easily able to place new bids on this item.
And I'm told that I have the winning bid even though this thing has expired.
You also noticed that we are not being told what the current high bid is, the number of bids this item
has.
Clearly there's still some work to be done.
So this is all stuff we're going to start to take care of in this section.
And as we start to go through some of the stuff, we're going to notice that there are possibly some
other big issues inside of our application.
If a lot of people try to bid on the same item at the exact same time, that's going to lead into a
deeper discussion later on.
Okay.
So let's kind of go over what we need to do to make bids work in our app.
In this diagram, I have the bid list history for a item with an idea of A-1.
And then right here, I've got the item hash as well.
So as a quick reminder of some of the properties that an item house has got, a name owner ID, image,
URL, description, those are all being pretty much set for us by other parts of the application right
now.
But then more interestingly, we have created at ending at number of views, number of bids, the current
high bid price, which is stored simply as price.
And then the ID of the user who created or has right now the highest bid and I'm putting on here 40,
but let's make it look like a real ID.
That's better.
At present, whenever a bit is created, we are not doing a couple of updates that we should probably
do.
Notably, we're not increasing the number of bids that the item has.
We are not setting the current price of the item, and we are also not setting the idea of the user
who currently has the highest bid.
So that's all stuff we need to take care of.
In addition, we also do also have take care of some validation.
So whenever someone tries to create a bid, we have to go through three validation steps.
First, we need to make sure that the item they are bidding on actually exists.
We need to make sure that item is still open for bids.
And we need to make sure that the amount of money that is being bid is greater than the current highest
bid because that's how an auction works.
If someone else bids $100, I can't later on bid.
$1 doesn't make any sense.
So we have to do those validation steps.
And then if we pass through all that validation, here's a list of everything we need to do to make
all the data on our backend consistent.
So we need to add the bid it to the bid history.
We're already doing that.
So that's all done.
We need to update the number of bids the item has, the items price and that highest user bid field.
So those are the three properties in that hash right here that I mentioned just a moment ago.
Those three right there.
And then in addition, another very small thing we do need to take care of.
We need to update the item score in the item price sorted set.
We have not touched on this sorted set yet at all.
But as you might be able to guess, this sorted set is what is going to allow us to eventually be able
to put together.
The section back on the landing page right here that says Most Expensive.
So we're going to get the list of items to show in the section by maintaining a sorted set organized
by item prices in the same way that we've really done already for, say, ending soonest and most views.
So very similar in nature.
We have not yet created that sword set.
So I'm just saying right here, hey, that's something we need to be aware of that we have to do in
the future.
But right now, what we really have to do is just this validation stuff and then update the item hash
appropriately.
So not too bad.
All right.
So now that we understand what's going on, let's work on implementation around all this in just a moment.