I'm back inside my code editor looking at the services queries.
It's not its file, but inside of creep ID, we're going to fix the issue around creating multiple different
bids at the exact same time by implementing a transaction.
So inside of that function, because we are going to make use of a transaction, we're going to first
create a brand new connection to Redis for use just around the transaction and then immediately discard
it afterwards.
And after we create that connection, we're going to set up a transaction where we are watching a particular
key for changes.
If that key ever changes in any way, we're going to cancel the transaction.
Otherwise we'll go ahead and execute the transaction.
Okay.
So let's get to it.
A lot of the code we have to write here is going to more directly to the concepts we just learned.
So let's just write the code out and I think you'll have a reasonable idea of what's going on.
At the top of the function to get started, I'm going to return.
Client Dot executes isolated.
And then put in an arrow function.
It's going to be marked as async and it's going to take an argument that we're going to call isolated
clients.
So this step right here is where we are creating a brand new connection over charities.
We know that we want to run a transaction.
That means we need to create a new connection.
That isolated client thing is the new connection that we have that we're going to use just for the transaction
and nothing else.
So inside of execute isolated if we need to access Radisson any way rather than using the client as
we have done before, we're going to instead use isolated clients.
All right.
So then I'm going to take the rest of the entire function, everything from contact item, all the way
down to what?
Return promise.
Not all are going to cut all that.
And I'm going to place it in to execute isolated.
And then fix the indentation.
Next up at the very top of this arrow function, we need to set up our watch statement.
We're going to do our watch.
We're going to check to see if that item has ever changes.
And if it does, then we're going to cancel automatically the transaction.
Our watch statements will be a weight isolated.
Clients not watch.
Items.
Key Adam Scott Item I.D..
And that's it.
That's how we set up our watch.
Now we can.
That's our item.
We can do our validation on its.
We can then figure out how we want to update the item or update all of our data and then run that update
inside of a transaction.
So we need to take our current pipeline operation and replace it with a multi exec lock.
That's going to be a very easy refactor to turn this thing into an actual transaction.
I'm going to delete the promise dot.
All right there.
I will put in isolated clients.
Not multi.
And then I'm going to delete the word client right there.
And remove the comma at the end of the line.
All.
Then remove client right there.
And finally, I'm going to remove the closing square bracket and the parentheses right there.
And then very last step, I'm going to chain on an exec.
And that's it.
To take our brand new connection over charities run multi on it.
To tell right is that we're about to issue a transaction.
We're going to set up the R push.
So we're going to keep you up that command.
We're going to queue up the H sets and then execute all of it.
And of course, if our item has changes at any point in time along the way, then the exec is going
to fail silently.
So it's not going to throw an error or anything.
Instead, it's going to give us back a value of not.
Okay.
So let's save this now.
I'm going to go back over to my browser and we're going to test this out very quickly.
Back over here.
My item has probably expired at this point in time.
We had ended one hour ago.
So I'm going to create a brand new item.
The duration of 10 minutes.
And then we're going to go through that same process of trying to create multiple different bids for
this thing.
And very quick succession will enter in a bid of $10.
I will then inspect.
The Place bid button.
I'm going to make sure that I have a button highlighted right there.
I'll open up the.
I would console by pressing escape.
And then remember we're going to do a four.
Let's.
I equals zero i.
Less than 15 i.
Plus.
Plus signs.
Zero dot click.
And I'm going to just make sure I still have button highlighted.
Now if I run this.
I get back message of -- Low, which looks like an air, definitely.
But I also get a success message here.
And it turns out that if I look at history now, without a doubt, even though I issued 15 requests
in very quick succession, only one single bid actually succeeded.
And the fact that we see a bid to low right here is just a little air around the front end client that
I put together.
That's my fault at the end of the day.
What really happened was we executed the first request successfully.
We got the success message right here, and then all the other requests failed.
And that's where we start to see the bid to low message.
This definitely works.
We definitely solved our concurrency issue by making use of a transaction with that watch keyword.
All right.
Well, we've learned a pretty good amount about concurrency at this point in time and how to solve it
using a transaction with the watch command.
There are still two other ways that we're going to solve some of these concurrency issues, but we'll
take a look at those at a future point in time.
It's going to have to learn a lot more about some other topics on the way first.