Before we move on, there's one last thing I want to take care of around bids.
You might recall that on the main landing page, you've got a section showing the items that are ending
soonest.
The items with the most views and the items that are the most expensive or in other words, have had
the highest amount of money bid on them.
We have not put in any implementation, are showing the most expensive items.
We're going to take care of that very quickly.
The actual implementation of this is going to be identical to what we did for ending soonest and most
views.
The we're going to have a single sorted set called items.
Colin Rice This will store the ID of every individual item as a member and the score will be the price
of the item.
Whenever a user creates a brand new item, we're going to add the item ID to our sorted set.
With an initial score of zero because it has not yet had any money bid on it.
And then whenever someone creates a bid and attempts to bid some amount of money on an item will go
into that same sorted set and update the score with the amount of money that was just bid on it.
And to show the most expensive items here, we can just take the list of items like the top five or
something like that from the very end of our sorted sets, because those will have the most amount of
money bid on them, and that's pretty much it.
The implementation will first begin by creating this sorted sets key.
We need to make a key function of items price.
Let's take care of that right away.
Back inside my editor.
I'm going to find my services.
Easy.
Yes.
File.
Under the item section, I'll add in a new items I price key.
And then return a string of items.
Colin Price.
All right.
Next up, we'll make sure that whenever we create an item you take, the item is added to our sorted
set with a score of zero.
Our item creation goes on inside of our queries, items, items, stats, file.
Here it is right here.
At the very top.
I'm going to find where I import the other keys, those right there.
And I'm going to add in an additional import or items by price.
Key.
Well, then go down to where we greet each individual item.
Here it is right here.
That's where we make our ID, then got our pipeline for all these different item creation commands we
have to run.
We're going to add in yet another command to run as a part of this pipeline.
We'll do client dot z add items by price key.
And then inside of here our value, which is actually the member, remember, the member is going to
be the ID and the initial score will just be zero.
And that's it.
Okay.
Next up, we need to make sure that whenever we create a bid, we update the score in the sorted sets,
a bid creation we were just working on a little bit ago.
We can find the code related to that inside of queries.
It's not.
Yes.
Here's where we agreed a bid but the very top the file let's import that sorted set key as well by all
the other key imports will get items by price key.
Then down inside of our transaction, in addition to the R push and the H set, you can also do this
update to the sorted sets and we'll use the Z add command yet again.
We'll do a Z, add on items by price key.
And then our value is going to be the items it.
And the score is going to be the amount of money in the bid.
The amount of money in the bid is available as ATRs dot amounts.
So the score.
Write your score.
Colon matters, not amount.
And that's it.
But we are now maintaining our data inside of our sorted sets, which is very good.
Last thing you have to do is make sure that we eventually allow ourselves to pull this data out of Redis
and we're going to do that.
The very similar set up to what we had done in the past, you might recall inside of queries, items,
DOT or some of the items folder.
We have a couple of files at the very top year of by ending time AI views and then two other ones of
by price and by user.
We had previously discussed some different ways of loading up relational data by using these sort commands.
We saw an example of that with items by views.
We're going to do something very similar in loading up all of our different, most expensive items.
That's going to take a little bit of time, however.
So let's start to tackle the by price or items by price function in the next video.