Inside of the by price yes file.
The implementation of this function is going to be just about identical to what we previously did inside
the by views thoughts file.
We need to do a sort operation.
Then once we get the top couple records, we're going to iterate through all the strings.
We get back, rip them up into individual objects and serialize them and all the stuff is going to be
so similar.
As a matter of fact, we're just going to do a little bit of copy paste of code between these different
files.
So inside of BI views from inside the BI views file, right now, I'm going to go up to the top.
I'm going to copy the three imports and paste them over inside of my price.
Or then import instead of items by use keys.
I want to get items by price.
Key.
Then back inside of my views, I'm going to take the entire function body.
So all the way down to the bottom where I return the list of items.
Well, copy all of it.
And then paste all that into the body of items by price.
And the only thing we need to change in here is the key that we are using to look up the sordid sex
or change it to items by price.
He.
And that should be it.
I'm going to save this and then go back over and test out my application.
Right away.
I see a couple of records right here.
We do need to create a brand new couple of items to actually get everything to show up correctly.
Remember, at present, we have not actually added in any item IDs to our sorted sets, listing out
all the different prices.
So even though we have created a couple of different items, we have not added the IDs of those items
into these sorted sets.
We only just started adding in the code that a moment ago.
So in theory, we should only start to see new items from this point on.
Show up in the list right here.
I'm going to go to New.
I'm going to create a new item.
But how about chair by price as the name?
Well, then place a bid of 20.
And now back on the landing page, I will see my chair by price.
I can create another item as well just to test this out.
Make this one a table.
The duration of 10 minutes.
I'm going to place a bid of 25 on this one.
And then back on the landing page, I see 25 and then 20, which means these things are in fact, being
sorted correctly.
Very good.
Well, that's it for the most expensive section.
Now we've got all this bidding stuff put together.
Let's move on to another topic.