Let's take care of all these different validation steps.
If we fail any validation step, we're just going to throw an error and say, Hey, sorry, but the
item doesn't exist or this item is closed for bids or the bid is too low.
All these validation checks will be implemented inside of our create bid function that we had previously
worked on.
So once again, inside of services, queries, bids.
Yes, here is created right here.
So inside of your first thing you have to do is find the item that the user is trying to bid on.
If figure out which item the user is trying to bid on.
We can look at this adders object once again number.
The address object has an item ID property.
That is the item we are trying to bid on.
And to actually get that item out of Redis, we can reuse a function we had put together previously.
Inside the items items dot to yes file.
So you might recall working on get item right here that is going to find an item by its ID and then
do you realize it for us automatically?
The back and side of bids.
Yes.
At the very top I will import yet item.
From dot slash items.
Inside of Crete bid.
I'm going to attempt to fetch our chosen item.
Looking for adders dot item id.
And then right after that, right here, we're going to put in three different statements.
Each one is going to run a different validation check.
So first, if for any reason we were not able to find the item that we were looking for.
We will throw a new air and say item does not exist.
Next if the items price.
Is greater than or equal to.
At resort amounts.
That's the amount of money that we are trying to bid.
Well, that means that we put in a bid that is too low.
So it's an invalid bid.
We want to throw it in the air as well.
They'll throw a new ere with bid to low.
And then finally, we need to make sure that this item is still up for auction.
So if the ending at time is greater than the current time, once again, we need to throw it in the
air.
Remember that the item itself.
So the item that we dispatched.
Once we serialize it, it has an ending at property and the DC revised version of the ending property
is not just this plane number, it is an actual datetime object.
So we can take a look.
In an if statement at item.
Dot ending at so that's going to be a datetime object.
Then to figure out that this thing is in the past.
We're going to add in a little bit of code here that's going to be slightly mysterious.
It's basically just using this Lexan library to figure out if ending at is in the past or not.
So to figure out what this thing is in the past, we're going to put on a dot diff then date time dot
now.
And outside of those two parentheses, I'll add on A to Millie's.
And I'm going to check to see if that value is negative.
That's how we're going to see if the ending at time occurred in the past and if it did once again.
What?
Throw a new air.
And I'll say I am close to betting.
Let's test this out really quickly.
Now, just as a reminder, the bid to low air is not going to work just yet because we are currently
not storing any items prices on item hashes.
So right now, all item prices are always being set to zero and there's no way to update it just yet.
But we can figure out whether or not the ending time is being correctly checked.
Sorry, I'm going to go back over to the browser.
I'm going to find an item that ended in the past.
So this one clearly ended one day ago.
Well, then attempt to place a bid for it.
So here's ten.
I'm going to place a bid and I'm told item close to bidding.
Good.
That's what we want.
If I go and create a brand new item.
I'll make another thing called Chair.
I'll have it.
And in 10 minutes.
So this is still open, forbidding.
And if I put in ten.
Now it works.
All right.
That looks good.
And in theory, our other pieces of validation should work as well.
So the price check should work.
And the item check right here definitely should work as well.
Yes.
This looks good.
We've taken care of these validation steps.
So now all we have to do once we've accepted the bid is update a couple of different properties on the
item hash and then save it.