We've got the validation steps complete.
So now we need to update the item hash and save it back into Redis.
All right, so back over here inside of creep ID, we've already got one request.
Going off to Red is right here because we're trying to now issue a second command.
We should probably set up a pipeline so we can batch all these different commands together and send
them off to red us at the same time.
So I'm going to do a little bit of a refactor.
I'm going to delete the return right there and then going to wrap this inside of a promise.
Not all statements.
So here's promised.
Not all.
I've got an array right there.
I'm going to cut and paste the output in there.
And then I will add in my hash update as well.
So I want to do a client not age set.
I want to set my items key at item ID.
So that's the item house we're looking for.
We have not yet imported items key into this file just yet.
We'll take care of that in just a moment.
And then we want to update three different properties.
First, we want to make sure that our number of bids is going to be whatever the items current number
of bids is plus one.
So we'll put in item dot bids plus one.
Then our price is going to be the bid amount which is available inside this file or this function right
here as at or not amounts.
And then finally, the idea of the user who is placing the bid that is also available on the ATRs object.
So ATRs hears the argument, if I do a command, click on created it.
ATRs Right there.
There is user ID.
Well, I'll put in highest bid user ID.
That's going to be at her sort user ID.
Finally, I'm going to make sure that I return.
Promised not all.
Okay.
So the last thing we need to do is just make sure that we import items key.
So at the very top next to all my other item or my key imports, I'll put in items key.
I'm going to save this.
Let's go back over to the browser as usual.
Very quick test.
I've got an item that is still pending in the future.
I'm going to add in a bid of 15.
And now we can see the high bid.
Right?
There is $15 and it has one bid.
You'll also notice that the little input right here has now updated as well.
And I'm told that if I want to place another bid, I have to put in at least $15 and one cents.
So if I tried to do 15 again, I'll get an error.
But if I put in .01.
Yup.
Looks good.
And my high bid has updated number of bids has updated perfect.
Okay.
So this looks good and it appears that everything is functioning.
There is still one step we have to go through.
We have to create that sorted set to record which items have the highest bid at present.
And that sorted set, you will recall, is being used on the landing page in this section right here.
So we'll get around to that.
But in the meantime, there's some other very big issue that I want to point out.
This is something I mentioned a couple of videos ago.
It's a kind of big issue around creating bids right now.
And it's going to lead us into a much, much, much deeper discussion around a very important topic
to understand in is.