It appears that the bidding process is working fine right now, but unfortunately, there is a very
small issue.
In this video, we're going to start to take a look at what that issue is and then go into a long series
of videos to understand it and how to fix it.
Okay.
So let me show you what the problem is around bidding.
Right now, at present, I'm signed into the application.
I'm going to go and create a brand new item look like on new.
I'll set a duration of 10 minutes and then submit.
Then on this page, I'm going to do a very special little bit of setup.
You do not have to go through this setup.
As a matter of fact, it might be best if you just watch what I do on my screen.
I want to try to place several different bids at just about the exact same time to do so, rather than
typing in a number right here and then clicking on that button as fast as I can.
I'm going to use a little bit more fancy setup.
I'm going to open up my developer tools inside the browser where I can right click anywhere and click
on Inspect.
That will give me my developer tools.
On the Elements tab, I'm going to select this little arrow element picker right here and then click
on the place bid button.
I will then make sure that I see the button element highlighted right here, and I'll zoom in on that
panel just so it's super clear.
I definitely have the button element selected.
Well, then make sure that I've entered a bid right here.
I've got ten.
And then finally, I'm going to write out a very small script inside the console right here.
You don't see the console.
You can press escape on your keyboard.
I'm going to write out a very small script to click on that button several times in very, very quick
succession.
The script is going to be.
Or let's i.
Equals zero i.
Less than about 15.
I.
Plus.
Then put in my curly braces for the four loop and inside the curly braces I will enter dollar sign zero.
Not like.
The dollar signs zero is a reference to the element we have selected in the element picker up here,
so that's why we need to make sure a button is selected.
All right.
So now I'm going to go ahead and run the statements.
And at first glance it appears that everything pretty much worked as expected.
I see that I have a high bid of $10.
I see that there was one bid.
I see a success message right here.
Everything looks pretty reasonable.
I do see a couple of errors inside my console, which makes me think that, all right, perhaps we ran
into some issue as we tried to bid on the same item multiple times.
But let's do kind of a deeper look here and actually make sure that everything actually is working as
expected.
The first thing I'm going to do is scroll down on this page a little bit.
You'll notice in the bid history section, I now have many different entries in here.
The item started off at $10 or $0 and then went up to ten.
And that looks like we got another bid at ten and then ten, ten, ten and so on.
In addition, if I go to the network tab inside of my developer tools.
And then click on that patch x h r right here as a filter criteria.
I can then scroll up a little bit and I'll see that there are a variety of post requests that were successfully
issued.
So every request that has black text.
So this one, this one, this one, this one, this one, this one.
Those are all requests that were successfully processed by the server.
That means that a bid was successfully created.
Now.
Some bids failed.
These right here, they all fail due to validation issues.
Without a doubt, it looks like there were about five or six requests that successfully created a bit.
All these different bids have the exact same price of $10.
This is definitely some behavior we do not want in our application.
This means that if a bunch of people are trying to bid on the exact same item at the same time, some
number of people would see success messages.
Even if they all put in the exact same price, though, some people would get you some kind of success
message like this right here that says, Hey, congratulations, you have the winning bid, but due
to some bug inside of our application, they might not actually have the winning bid.
All right.
So now we've seen this error.
Let's take a pause here.
We're going to take a look at a couple diagrams and understand what's going on behind the scenes.