Let's take a look at a couple of diagrams and try to understand the bug that we just ran into.
Just to be clear, the issue here is that we are seeing that there was one bid, but it appears inside
of bid history right here that multiple different bids were actually processed behind the scenes.
So, again, let's try to figure this out.
Okay.
So here's what's going on right now on our server.
Whenever someone makes one single request to bid on an item, here's the request over here.
It might contain information like the idea, the item we want to bid on and the amount of money that
we want to bid.
Then on our server, this is what we are doing inside of our create bid function.
We are getting our item out of this.
We realize it and we run some validations.
These validations are those if statements we put into the crepe it function just a moment ago.
Here's create bid.
Here are the if statements.
Those are the validations.
If we get past all those validations, we then run some code to actually update our item inside of Redis.
That's where we do some update to the hash right there.
So we can kind of imagine that this is really broken into a two step process at the very first step
right here.
We try to fetch some data out of Redis.
This is our saved item that we are fetching.
So we get that hash.
We loaded onto our server, we serialize it, we run the validations and whatnot.
That'll take some amount of time, some number of milliseconds.
It takes some number of milliseconds to actually issue a command off to Redis and get a response back
from it.
It then takes a very, very, very few milliseconds, so it's just about instantaneous, serialize that
hash and runs the validations on it, but it does technically take a very small amount of time.
Then when we go to make our updates and save, we can imagine that we'll update the number of bids to
one and the price to ten.
And when we go to see this back, we are once again making requests off to Redis.
And again, that takes some number of milliseconds.
We then go and save the updated date up.
Back over here.
The thing I really want to focus on is the fact that as we run the first command to fetch some data
and then the second command to save some data, some amount of time is passing there.
Let's imagine what would happen if we tried to make two separate requests to bid on an item at the exact
same time.
Here's what would happen.
I've got two requests at the exact same time.
We're going to imagine that the server is going to handle the first requests on this line of execution
right here, and then the second request on this line of execution.
And again, we're processing these things at the exact same time.
As soon as the server sees these two income requests, it's going to run the read it function for both
them.
So we're going to just about simultaneously reach out to Regis and attempt to get our item hash, then
serialize it and run validations.
So we will reach over here, get a copy of the hash loaded onto the server.
D serialize it.
And then take a look at the data that we just loaded up nor validations are currently checking to make
sure that this item.
Has an amount or a price assigned to it that is less than the amount on the incoming request.
Both lines of execution right here.
Both are looking at a decent sized hash that says that the current price is zero.
So the validations on both lines of execution are going to pass just fine.
They're both going to say, oh, yeah, this is a valid bid.
We can absolutely bid $10 on this item.
The bottom lines of execution are going to update this hash in memory.
With a price of ten.
I think it's actually a mount that we call it.
They'll update the number of bids, two one on both.
And then as far as each line of execution is concerned, we have now made a valid update and it's time
to save this data.
Back over to treatise on both cases.
We're not going to take that update, hash serialize it and save it back over.
So the first house might be saved.
Now we have bits of one and amount of ten, and then simultaneously at just about the exact same time,
the second line of execution is also going to save.
We're going to serialize that hash and save it over a year as well.
So the data that actually gets saved inside of this deal says there's only one bid and the amount is
ten.
But we technically processed two separate and different requests to request to actually bid on an item.
And once again, if these requests came from different users, each user would probably be told the
bid has succeeded.
You are now the highest bidder on this item and you're going to win it and purchase this item pretty
soon.
When in reality, the person who is truly actually succeeding in the bid right now is whoever did the
last safe authorities.
Whoever did the most recent save is the one who is going to be currently purchasing or in control of
this item.
That's the issue.
The issue that we're running into right now and this very subtle bug that we have is any time we get
to request at exactly the same time are very closely at the same time we might attempt to match them
data.
Both lines of execution are looking at the same exact copy.
They might think that they are the only process that is currently looking at that piece of data and
then attempt to make an update.
In reality, there might be another line of execution that is also modifying that data at the exact
same time.
Okay.
So now we understand what the issue is in our particular case.
Let's now try to generalize the issue a little bit.
When is something like this going to be a problem?
Well, we're going to run into a concurrency issue like this and read this just about any time that
we attempt to get some data out of Redis, do some calculation or validation on it, and then save that
data.
Any time we are attempting to fetch data, read it in some way, do some kind of calculation, and then
they even update back to us.
We might run into a concurrency issue because in between the time of us fetching the data and then saving
an update back to Redis, some other request, some other process might be doing the exact same thing.
And so we might be in conflict with some other process.
Again any time.
Just I want to add one more time because it's super critical.
Any time we read data and then sit around for a little bit and then save and update back.
We are possibly going to run into a concurrency issue.
Okay.
So now we understand that there is one little caveat here.
In some cases, this is totally fine and we can absolutely deal with problems like this without any
kind of special behavior.
Let me show you a very quick example.
Let's imagine that we are working on some to do list application.
We list out a series of tasks to a user, some different things that they have to accomplish throughout
the day.
Well, imagine that we are storing each of these tasks as a separate hash.
Every hash has a user ID, the name of the task, and then a status which might be something like not
started in progress or completed.
Now it's imagine that two separate people make a request to update the status of a to do we maybe have
one request right here to market to do as completes and then the second one to market to do as completed.
Maybe the first request is going to be handled on this line of execution right here.
And then the second request will be handled right here.
As a very critical part of updating a task.
We need to make sure that the person making the request actually has permission to update the task.
So in that case we would need to get the task easier serialize it.
Make sure that the person making the request has permission and then go and set the status.
Once again, we have loaded up a copy of data onto both lines of execution.
They can look at that user ID and then given that this person actually owns the to do the person making
the request, we'll go ahead and try to update the status property.
Now the first line of execution was trying to set a status of completes.
And the other one was trying to set a status of started that we would be in the same kind of scenario
right here where they both might succeed in saving some data treaties.
But they're kind of in competition.
Who knows if the result is going to be marking this to do as complete or started.
So very similar concurrency issue.
However, in this kind of scenario, is it truly an issue if we accidentally mark a task as completed
versus started?
Well, it might come down to the rules of your application or your app for whatever you are building.
You might be totally okay with running into an issue like this.
Personally, if I was building a to do list and two separate users were trying to update the status
of an item at the exact same time.
I would be totally fine if there was some kind of contention there, and I would just say, you know
what?
Whoever made the most recent request is going to succeed, whoever made the most recent request to update
the status.
That's what we're going to run with.
So it might be up to your application to decide if a concurrency issue actually truly is an issue or
not is again in this scenario.
Hey, sure.
Go ahead.
Update the task.
The first user who is trying to mark this thing is complete might erroneously see after they make the
request that the to do is not now marked as started.
That's totally fine.
It could kind of be up to the user to realize, Oh, maybe someone else is updating this data at the
exact same time.
All right.
So again, just want to highlight that although we are always going to run into concurrency issues,
any time we try to fetch data and then make an update, well, it's up to you to decide if you actually
need to handle that or deal with it in some way.
All right.
So now that we understand the issue, we understand that we don't always need to handle the issue.
How do we actually solve it?
So how are we going to solve this issue of multiple different foods being processed at the same time?
There are four different solutions.
We're going to go over inside this course.
We're going to start off with one and two right now in this section.
And then we're going to come back to it three and four later on inside the course, because they are
much more involved and a lot more complicated.