Let's take a look at one possible way that we can deal with these concurrency issues.
Now, I just want to highlight very quickly that as we looked at this diagram a moment ago, we said
that there is going to be a concurrency issue anytime we try to read some data and then do some calculation
or something like that and then save some data back into Redis.
Now, to be really precise, the true issue here is that there is some amount of time that is passing
between us reading and writing our data because in that window of time, some other request might come
in.
We might attempt to update the data that we are getting during this first step right here.
So when we attempt to do a save operation, the data that we were working with might be stale.
So one way that we could deal with all these concurrency issues is if we could just remove this gap
right here altogether, if there was no delay between us getting data and saving data.
Or alternatively, if we just did not get any data whatsoever and just did only a save operation, all
these concurrency issues would be solved.
So as we have learned over time, there are a variety of different commands that allow us to update
a value in place using the current value without actually reading it.
Let me show you some diagrams and just remind you what those commands are.
Okay.
So I want you to imagine another application here.
Maybe we are building an app that stores some number of cars that we are trying to set to sell.
So inside of Redis, we might have a car hash.
Maybe we've got a kind of car that we're trying to sell.
And then we are recording the number of cars that we have in stock right now.
Maybe there are zero.
Then maybe we get an income.
Your request that tries to add one to the number of cars in stock.
So effectively really just trying to update that zero to a one.
One way we could do this is by taking a look at the current cars, ash, so we could retrieve that entire
hash.
We could see that the current value is zero.
We could add zero and one.
Together we would get one and then run a command to set in stock to the new value, which is one.
In other words, read the current value, add one to it, save the up to get value back into Redis.
If we use this as our update pattern, we once again have a delay or a gap between reading and writing.
So if we had two requests coming in at the exact same time, both them asking to add one, the number
of cars in stock, we would run into the same issue.
We had just a moment to go inside of our bid application.
Both these lines of execution would attempt to read in that hash at the same time.
They would both see that the current value of in-stock is zero.
It would both add one to it and then run a command to save that back in treatise.
After processing both these commands, we would end up with an in-stock of one, which is definitely
not what we want because we got to use up a request to add one.
So it should be two.
But one way we could solve this is by just not reading the initial value of in-stock altogether.
Just skip the entire read it step and just go directly to writing.
To do so we could use the H anchor by command by recall.
That's a command we spoke about a long time ago around horses.
So if we ever are asked to add one to the number of cars in stock rather than try to get the current
value and then update that, we could just run one single command that says go and find this particular
property inside this hash.
Add one to it, one single step.
Right.
Only we are not doing any read operation.
So we could process as many commands as we or any as many requests as we want to.
At the exact same time, each one is going to result in one separate h anchor by and we are always guaranteed
that we'll end up with a number of cars in stock equal to however many requests we originally got.
Okay.
So that's the first way in which we could deal with some of these atomic update operations or some of
these concurrency issues.
I want to give you one other very fast example.
Okay.
Let's imagine that we are still selling cars or something like that.
And now we want to record the color of every car.
And a little caveat here, a little bit of a requirement.
We only want to set the color of a car if it has not yet been set before.
So in this example, I've got a car in red.
It has a name, but it does not yet have a color property.
And I only want to set color if it's never been set before.
Once again, if we get a request coming in that says, okay, try to set the color, but only if it
hasn't been set.
One way we could implement this is by reading this hash out.
Taking a look at the house and making sure that nobody has set the colour property yet.
And if they haven't.
Go ahead and set the color property.
Well, yet again, we run into a concurrency issue here.
If we got two separate requests at the same time, one that says try to set this thing to Blue, and
the other that says Red.
Well, we would.
If the hash.
One for each of the requests.
They're both going to see that the color property has not yet been set.
And so they will both attempt to set the color property.
And so we're kind of violating one of the constraints of our problem here, where we only want to set
the color if it hasn't been set.
The both these updates would process.
One would be correct because we're going to set the color when it hasn't been set.
But the second command, they got processed, the second set operation we do would be kind of erroneous
because we had already set the color.
Yet again.
One way we could solve this problem is by using another special update command.
In this case, we might use h sets and x h that an x allows us to set a property.
Here is my diagram.
Here it is right here.
It's that an X allows us to set a property only if it has not yet been set before.
The annex stands for not exists.
So update a property in hash only if it does not currently exist.
Rather than doing a read and then a right operation, each of these requests could just issue a separate
H set and x.
The first one to be processed would succeed.
So maybe we run this command first and set color red.
And then a microsecond later, we might try to run this command right here.
It's that next car.
Blue light color has already been set.
So the second H set an X would correctly fail.
And we would send back in air to this request right here saying sorry about the color for this car has
already been set.
Okay.
So again, that is the first way in which we are going to handle concurrency issues.
We can find some specific commands that really sets our can handle our particular use case and how we
are trying to update our data.
And the real key to these commands is that they allow us to either completely eliminate the time gap
between a read and a write, or alternatively, they allow us to set some kind of criteria under which
we do the update.
And that's the case of the Set and X Command.
The vast majority of scenarios.
This option right here is not really going to work out.
And that's definitely the case for our application right now or our app as we are trying to create a
bid.
We are trying to do an H set right here, but we're also doing an AR push.
So it'd be really challenging for us to try to figure out some kind of atomic atomic command that we
can use to update the bid history list.
In some way.
We don't really get the benefit of commands like each set an X or things like that for dealing with
lists much more common to see those around sets and hashes, sorted sets and so on.
We're going to need something more powerful for our use case, and that's where using a transaction
is going to start to come in.
Let's learn a little bit more about transactions in the next video.