In this video.
We're going to do a quick aside and learn more about transactions.
Once we understand how transactions work and read as well, then come back to this idea of concurrency
and see how we can use transactions to solve some concurrency issues.
So let's get to it.
Let's do a quick aside on transactions and understand what they're all about.
All right.
A couple diagrams here, a couple notes on transactions in general.
Transactions are used to group together, commands that we want to run sequentially.
In other words, one after another, usually whenever we send commands off to read us, if we have multiple
different commands connected to read us at the same time, and we're issuing commands from all these
different clients at the same time, Register is going to take a command from one client and then another,
another, another, and so on.
And so it's going to process all these different commands coming in from different clients in slightly
different order.
When we use a transaction, we are specifically telling Redis that there are a couple of commands we
want to run one after another, and nothing else should be executed in between them.
Transactions are similar to Nature U pipeline.
You might recall that pipeline is used to group together transactions or grouped together commands and
send them all over to read it at the same time.
When we use pipelines, there's no guarantee that all those commands are going to be executed one after
another.
Some other command coming from another connection might be executed in between them with transactions.
That's not the case with transactions.
We are guaranteed that all these grouped up commands get executed one after another.
Then finally, you might be used to using transactions in other databases and many other databases.
Transactions can be rolled back or otherwise undone.
That is not the case in Redis.
We do not use transactions as a means of check pointing or write in it, trying to do some work and
then undoing it or anything like that.
The transactions are a little bit less useful and reticent compared to many other databases.
Just keep that in mind for right now.
Okay.
So what is a transaction exactly?
Transactions use a couple of different commands to manage.
The first command we're going to learn about is multi multi.
It tells Redis that we're about to send it a couple of different commands that we don't want to execute
just yet.
We want to execute them at some point in the future.
Immediately, one after another.
We first started the transaction with Multi will then send along some other commands to run.
These will be very normal typical commands so sets a get H gets H sets all the commands we've already
learned about inside this course.
Those commands are not executed right away.
Instead, they get queued up.
They're going to be executed at some point time in the future to run all those commands, to actually
execute them.
We'll send another command called Exec.
That means run all the commands that had been queued.
That's really understand the stuff we really need to run a transaction ourselves.
So let's go back over to our booked cloud and just figure out what's going on.
All right.
So back over in our book, Dark Cloud, I've created a new notebook called Transactions.
I'm going to create three different code cells.
And then in each of these different code cells, I'm going to write out a different part of a transaction.
In the very first one, I'm going to put in multi.
And run that and I'll get back a response of.
Okay.
Then in the second code cell, I'm going to do a set alert, read and set count five.
Usually if I click play right here, these commands would be immediately executed.
But because I just opened up a transaction, they will not be executed right away.
Look like play.
And I'm now told that these commands were cued.
That means that they've been lined up to be executed at some point in time in the future.
Now to run all the commands that I've queued up, I will execute.
Exactly.
That's going to run the actual commands, that color red and set count five.
And then as a response I'll get the response or the results of each individual command.
So the first, okay, right here is from setting color to red.
And then the second.
Okay, is from setting count to five.
And that's the basics of a transaction.
So we use multi to begin, we then list out some number of commands and then we execute them.
That's pretty much it.
At first glance, this might not seem terribly useful.
But it turns out that there are a couple of aspects of this and a couple of options we can provide along
the way that makes these transaction things much more useful, particularly any time that we're dealing
with these concurrency issues.
So let's learn a little bit more around transactions in just a moment.