At first glance, it appears that transactions are not very useful.
All right.
It allows us to run commands and order.
What's so great about that?
Well, let's introduce another keyword.
Another command in this video, and I think you'll start to understand why we use transactions.
All right, so this additional command is what we're going to run the watch commands before we execute
a transaction.
The goal of watch is to tell read this to take a look at some value stored at a key.
And if that value ever changes before we run at the next transaction and fail that transaction automatically.
Let me show you an example of this.
Let's imagine that we do a watch on color.
So we're going to watch the value right here of green.
And then we'll imagine that immediately after we execute watch some other client connected to Reddit
tries to update the color property and change it to blue.
Now color has been changed because we changed the value stored at color and we were watching it.
The next transaction we try to run is going to automatically fail so we can try to set up a transaction
they multi and then do a set, a set and then end exact.
As soon as we call exac, we're going to get back null, which means the execution of that command or
the execution, that transaction was halted because the value or the key that we were watching was changed
in some way.
Let's go through a very quick example of this inside of our book.
I still got the multi view sets and an exact right here.
I went out in a new coat, sell at the very top, and I'll do a watch on color.
I'm now watching color.
And if color changes in any way before I run the next transaction, then the transaction is going to
fail.
Right now, let's try going through a transaction without changing color at all so I can do my multi,
I can queue up my two commands and then execute them and everything goes A-okay.
It's all fine.
But if I go back up here towards the top.
And I do a watch on color and then add in a new code cell and do a set color blue and run this.
The set on blue is still going to execute just fine.
Now color is definitely as a value of blue, but if I now go to set up my next transaction right here,
a multi set and sets and then exec, now I get back null because the value stored at color has changed.
You can start to see right away how this would be very useful for dealing with concurrency issues.
Any time that we want to read a value out of this takes some amount of time to process it and then do
a write operation based upon it.
We could wrap all that in a transaction that makes use of the watch command.
We can make sure that we cancel the execution of our transaction if the value we are looking at has
changed in any way.
There are a couple of patterns that we're going to see very often around the watch keyword.
So let's take a look at some of these different patterns in the next video.