The last thing I want to show you around.
Transactions right now are some very common patterns you're going to see in code.
Here's a very common pattern.
We might have a server that needs to make an update to, say, a color property by first fetching that
property, looking at what its current value is, and then making an update based upon its current value.
So this would lead to a classic concurrency issue scenario because we are trying to what read a value,
inspect it and then do a conditional write.
We can solve that concurrency issue by making use of the watch keyword.
We might do first a watch, then get some information out of Redis by doing a get an H, get all or
any other kind of commands.
We can then have some kind of processing step in here and represented by that arrow right there where
we will look at the value of color and decide how we want to update it or something like that.
Then we can set up our transaction by running multi Somerset operations and executing them.
And of course if anything occurred to either the value of color or accounts in between us executing
watch and then the transaction will automatically be canceled.
You could start to imagine how we could use this on our bid issue as well.
So back on our e-commerce application, make sure that we only update or create a bid correctly, and
don't try to create multiple different bids at the same time.
We could simply watch an items hash.
So when we go to create a brand new bid, we might look at item A1 or something like that.
We can then batch that item, hash read in the current bid amount and then start up our transaction.
So do the multiple to an H set and update our list of bids and then execute that.
If any other request comes in, in between us executing watch and exec.
So maybe another request comes in to modify the item and successfully does so.
And our execution right here, the entire transaction will be canceled and so we will no longer suffer
any concurrency issues that we currently have, where many different requests at the same time.
An update or create bids for a single item.
That's one common pattern you're going to see.
Basically start to watch that some data do the transaction.
There's one other thing I want you to be aware of, because as we start to implement this pattern right
here, you're going to notice a pretty good amount of additional code.
So the other thing I want you to be aware of is that whenever we start to make use of transactions,
we are going to be making multiple different connections to Redis right now on our server as we're running
it.
Currently, we're using one single connection for all the different commands we need to execute, regardless
of what request is coming in.
So we might have 20 different quest at the same time coming into our application.
They are all issuing commands against the exact same connection to our Redis server.
But as soon as we start to make use of transactions, any time we use the watch or multi keywords,
we are kind of painting or hijacking our connection.
And that connection should only be used for this transaction and nothing else whatsoever.
So one common pattern you're going to see.
We're going to have one connection that's being used on our server for any typical commands though a
usual sets and l'orange each get all or whatever else.
But as soon as we get a request that's going to need a transaction, we're going to create a new connection
just for the purposes of that transaction.
So create a new transact or a new connection and do our watch multi exec or whatever else, and then
close that connection, the one brand new connection or the transaction.
And that's it.
Close it immediately after.
All right.
So I think we've got a better idea on how transactions work now and how they can solve concurrency issues.
So let's start to implement transactions inside of our app to solve this issue around multiple bids
in just a moment.