The next day.
The type we were going to work on is called a hyper log log.
This thing has a weird name, but it is a data type, just like all the other data types we have covered
so far inside this course.
So just like sets, sorted sets, strings and so on.
It just happens to have a weird name.
The second thing I want you to understand is that even though it's got the word log inside of this thing
twice, it has nothing to do with logging whatsoever.
So nothing to do with console logs or anything like that.
Hyper log logs are used whenever we want to keep track of the uniqueness of a collection of different
elements, and specifically the approximate uniqueness.
And I'll tell you what I mean by approximate in just a little bit, you can think of a hyper log log
as being similar to a set with the important distinction that it doesn't actually store any elements.
And lastly, I want to mention for right now, this thing is going to seem kind of useless at first
glance, but there are some very specific use cases where it is absolutely a fantastic data structure
that you're going to want to use.
We're going to see a very good use case inside of our e-commerce application.
So don't worry, you're going to get a good idea of what's going on here.
Now, I'm being kind of mysterious about this structure right now, not really giving you a very clear
definition of what it is.
You just have to look at some commands around it and you'll get a better sense of what is going on.
So let's look at some commands right away.
There's only two commands, believe it or not, just two that you need to understand.
The first one is P.F. at will call P.F. Ad with some string or a number that's going to take that string
or a number.
And we can imagine that it's going to add it into this hyper log log structure over here.
And again, we can kind of think of this thing as being like a set.
The only difference is that once we add the string in, it doesn't truly get stored inside the hyper
log log.
Instead, this thing has a very complex algorithm inside of it that looks at this string, does some
parsing on it, does some very complex math, and kind of remembers that string, but it doesn't actually
start per say.
So again, we imagine that it's like a set and that it's going to keep track of a unique set of items,
but it doesn't actually store any true values inside of it.
Whenever we call that very critically, if we have not added SDF before this string before.
So this is a brand new string that we are adding into the thing.
We'll get back a one.
Otherwise, if this value already existed or had already been added in the past, we'll get back a zero.
All right.
Onto the second command.
The second command, if count allows us to look at a hyper log log and get an approximate count of the
number of unique elements that have been added.
And that's it.
That's the only two commands we get.
That's all there is.
Now, next we're going to do is going to run these commands over in Arabic very quickly.
So we're going to get some hands on experience with them.
And then after that, I'll tell you exactly why we use this structure at all.
Because right now, between just P.F. ad and puff count, it doesn't seem terribly, terribly useful.
All right, so over in our book, I've already created a notebook.
I've called it hyper logline.
So we're going to run just a couple commands here, just up you have ADD, you have count and so on.
So I going to do a APF ad.
I'm going to create a new hyper log log at a key of.
Vegetables.
And I'm going to add in.
How about celery?
There we go.
Now.
I've never added in a string of celery before to this hyper log log.
So when I run this command, I'm going to get back responsive one.
If I run this command a second time, I'm going to get back zero.
So again, first time we add in a string, we get back a one.
Otherwise, if this thing has already been added, we get a zero.
I'm going to try changing from celery to how about a potato?
We're going to add this thing in again.
First time I add it, I get a one.
I run this again, I get a zero.
Now let's add in another code cell underneath this and I'll do APF count.
On.
Vegetables.
And I get to because of I have added at this point time celery and potato.
Like I said, that's it.
That's all there is to these commands.
Let's take a pause right here.
We're going to come back the next video, and I'm going to tell you exactly why this is a useful structure
and how we can use these two very simple commands to do some pretty interesting things.