Let's look at a practical example of a hyper log log.
Like I said, I think that this is going to clear up a lot of stuff.
So inside of our e-commerce application, remember, we are tracking the number of views that an item
has.
And we really want to make sure that one user can only contribute one view per item.
So if someone would not be able to just create an item and then refresh the page like a thousand times
to get a thousand views, we don't want to allow that behavior.
So we need to track every view per user, per item in some way.
And we need to make sure that every view is unique.
One way that we could do this is by adding in a set, one set for every single item.
So I might have a items five right here hash.
I might make a corresponding views five set.
And this might track all the different views for item five.
And if I had many different items, I would have one set for each.
So something like this.
Inside the set.
I could keep track of, say, the username maybe, or the user ID of every person who has viewed this
item.
And then whenever someone comes to an item page before incrementing the number of views, I could check
and see if their username or their user id already exists inside the set.
This is a very classic use case of sets.
We're using it to track uniqueness.
Very simple.
This would definitely work, but there's a very big downside to it.
If I'm keeping track of usernames inside of here and the usernames are always the same length.
So about nine characters.
So username one username to three for and so on.
Each of these additional strings costs me about 40 bytes to store inside the set so we can do a little
bit of calculation here.
We can easily figure out that if an item has a million different views, we would have 40 bytes, times
a million views divided by 1024 to get into kill bytes, and then 1024 to get into megabytes.
And we're left with 38 megabytes just to store this one set for this one single item.
You can imagine that if we have many different items or we have items with many more views than 1 million.
Well, this is going to start to get really expensive really quickly for such a simple little feature.
Just keeping track of who has viewed the item.
So we should probably figure out a better way of keeping track of this uniqueness.
And for that, we can use a hyper log log.
So.
Here's what we would do instead.
Whenever a user views an item, we could run off, add views and then say username one and this should
specifically be it.
Say views five.
So we'll have still a hybrid log log for every single item.
And whenever someone views the item, we will attempt to add their username or their user ID into the
hyper log log.
Remember that whenever we do a PDF Add operation, we will be told in the response whether or not this
is a new value.
So if we get back one, that means that this is a brand new username that we are adding.
And because this is a brand new person viewing this item, we should increment the number of views that
it has.
Otherwise, if we get back a zero, that means that this person has already viewed this item.
They already exist inside that hyper log log.
And so we should not increment the number of use.
So functionally as just about identical to the set implementation.
But here's the difference, because the hyper log log does not actually truly store the individual records.
So it doesn't actually store these usernames or the user IDs or anything like that.
It has a constant size.
It is always just about 12 kilobytes, no matter what, when stored inside of Redis.
So we could add in a million views.
2 million.
5 million, however, million we want.
And we're always going to be keeping only 12 kilobytes worth of data.
So obviously, if all of our different items have a lot of different views, this is going to be a huge
space savings compared to the set approach.
So this is a great use case of hyper log locks.
This might sound like fantastic.
And it is.
But there is one very small downside that you need to be aware of.
And it comes back to this diagram right here.
I had used the word approximately counting.
That is the downside because the hyper log log doesn't actually truly store these individual items.
It only stores a kind of approximation or representation of what it thinks it might have seen in the
past, through the use of, like I said, a very fancy algorithm.
So in general.
Whenever we do hpf count or whenever we do APF ad and we look at that one or zero that gets returned,
the number we get back is going to be incorrect ever so slightly by the amount of 0.81%.
That's a very small amount of error, but is nonetheless an error.
So in other words, if I ran a PEF ad 1000 times each with a unique value and I added all these ads
into one single hyper log log and then did APF count on average?
I would get back a error value or I would get a slightly incorrect value on the scale of .81 percent.
So I might see a response of anywhere from 991 all the way up to 1008.
So that is the approximate nature here, and this is the tradeoff we make for not actually storing the
original individual items.
So it's up to you to decide whether or not using a hyper log log is appropriate in your application.
In our app, if we are making use of one to keep track of these unique views, it is really, truly
at the end of the day.
Okay.
With me if we are slightly incorrect on a number of views an item has.
That's totally fine.
So what?
An item gets a couple extra or a couple of fewer views for every thousand views.
That's really, truly not a big deal to me, but I might not want to use a hyper log log if I'm trying
to keep track of, say, unique user names or unique email addresses.
In those scenarios, I truly want to make sure that if I'm looking for unique emails or usernames or
something like that, I want to make sure I have truly unique values.
So it probably not be appropriate to use a hyper log log in those scenarios.
But if it's something like we use, hey, whatever, sure, 12 kilobytes, I will make that trade off
happily.
Okay.
So as you can guess, we are going to implement exactly this approach right here inside of our application
to make sure that whenever a user views an item, we only keep track of original first time views for
incrementing the view counter.
So let's take a pause here and we'll start to implement this hyper log log inside of our e-commerce
application.