Let's implement this flow inside of our e-commerce app.
Let it get started back inside my editor.
We're going to first create a new key function to keep track of where our hyper logged logs are stored
for each individual item inside the service's directory of on the Keys Notes file.
This is yet another key related to items.
So I'm going to add into that section export const items views key.
This name is very similar to items by use, so maybe we could think of a better name for this thing.
But for me right now I think it's good enough.
We want to make sure that every single item has its own separate hyper log log structure.
So we will receive an item ID as a string.
And then we can generate a actual key here that will point to wherever that hyper log log is stored.
So I'm going to use a key of items.
Views.
Pound dollar.
Sign.
Curly Braces.
Item ID.
All right.
I'll save this file.
I'll then go into services queries and you might recall we had put together all of our view related
logic inside the view sorts file.
So here's the incremental view we had previously put together.
Up at the very top, I'll find where I am importing my different key functions.
I'm going to add in the additional import for items.
The use key.
Now inside this function, we're going to do exactly what you saw in that diagram a moment ago.
Before we do anything inside of here, we're going to try to add in this person's user ID.
We're not going to use the username.
We're going to use the user ID.
Q This particular hyper log log for the item that they are currently viewing.
Well, then take a look at the response.
And if we got back a one, that means that this is a brand new view.
So we want to recommend to our viewers otherwise if we got a zero, this person has already viewed that
item so we should not do any view incrementing.
Therefore the implementation back in this function at the very top.
I'll say contact inserted is a weight client dpf add.
I want to add in something two items views key.
I'll put in the item ID.
And the actual value that we want to attempt to add into that hyper log.
Log is the user's ID.
So now we can take a look at inserted.
And again, if it is tricky if we get back a one, fantastic.
Otherwise if we get a zero, then we'll just return.
So we can do something like if inserted, then go ahead and.
Run our view incrementing logic which we had previously put together.
Otherwise do nothing.
And that's pretty much it.
Now to test this out should be really easy to test.
I'm going to go back to my main landing page.
I'll go down to the views section.
And remember, previously, we could easily increment the number of views on an item by just refreshing
that page or the page for an individual item over and over and over again.
That's how I got up to 27 views on this item right here.
So if I now go there the very first time I go here because we only just implemented the hyper log log
stuff, now I should be up to 28 views because the very first time I am adding my user ID into the hyper
log log for this item.
So if I go back, I should be up to 28.
Yep.
But if I go there again and refresh, refresh, refresh, refresh, refresh.
No matter how many times I refresh, in theory, I should still be at 28.
Unless I am falling into that error range of the hyper log log, which is pretty unlikely.
And so sure enough, I'm still at 28 views, no matter how many times I refresh that page.
I'll refresh a couple more.
Go back.
Still 28.
All right.
So that works perfectly.
Well, that's really, truly it for hyper log logs.
Like I said at the very first video, this section, these things are kind of simple in nature.
They are one singular purpose, only the two commands you need to be concerned with, and that's pretty
much it.
So we want to reach for hyper log logs any time we want to track approximate uniqueness and it's really
up to you to decide whether or not they are appropriate for your uniqueness check.