In this section.
We're going to move on to yet another data type referred to as streams.
Understanding streams is a little bit challenging, so we can take a couple of videos just to get a
high level overview of what these things are all about and understand why we use them at all, because
they are really unlike just about any other data type we've looked at so far.
So the first couple of things to understand here are that streams are kind of like a cross between a
list and a sorted set.
They are used to store a collection of different records.
We are most commonly going to use streams anytime we need to communicate between different servers.
So although we can store information inside of a stream, the real goal here is coordination and communication
between different servers or different processes.
Streams are most useful when used with a feature called consumer groups.
We're going to go over consumer groups quite a bit.
I just want you to understand that when we first look at streams, they're going to seem not super useful.
But as soon as we introduce this idea of consumer groups, you're going to start to understand, okay,
yeah, this makes sense.
You can see how we would use them.
And then finally, this is the most important item to understand, is that there are tons and tons of
tiny details to understand around streams, tons of tiny little features, little bits of syntax.
And just about every single one of them is very important because they are all used to enable communication
between these different servers in a very specific way.
Okay.
So hopefully up and scared away.
Let's pause right here.
And I want to help you understand why we use dreams in just a moment.