Now that we understand problem one and problem two, we're going to understand how to fix these problems
by using an advanced feature around streams.
This advanced feature is called a consumer group.
Understanding consumer groups is a little bit challenging because there are a ton of very tiny details
to understand.
So in this video, I just want to outline a couple of really big high level points and we'll start to
play around with consumer groups in the next video.
Okay.
So first thing to understand here is that we're going to have some number of workers, each of these
different workers is a separate process that might be a different server, separate API, some separate
program that connects to Redis and is trying to get information out of a stream.
The goal of a consumer group is to get each of these different workers to work together in some way
or to get some level of coordination between them.
All the different workers inside of a consumer group are going to have a unique name.
This allows Redis to identify each worker.
So we might give our first worker a name of their one emailer to an emailer.
Three.
The first big benefit to these consumer groups is that renters can make sure that it only sends a single
message of this dream to one worker.
So let's imagine that we've got these three different workers right here, and simultaneously they all
execute in X read commands.
Because we are using a consumer group.
Redis is going to make sure that for these two messages right here, they will only be delivered to
one single worker.
So the first message might be sent to the first worker.
And then the second message might be sent to the second worker.
So we don't have to deal with any duplicate messages anymore.
Next.
When we create a consumer group readies is going to internally create a log of where all these different
messages are being sent and it's going to keep track of where it sends each one.
The readies is going to say, okay, I've got a message with an idea of one, two, three, one, two,
three.
I am going to send that message off to email or one.
And then four nine, nine nine right here.
It's going to keep track of the fact that it sent that message to worker number two.
Now alone, that doesn't seem super useful, but it's a little addition to that log.
That's going to solve problem two that we discussed where a worker might crash after it is delivered
a message.
So as a part of the stream log register is also going to keep track of whether or not the worker acknowledged
receipt of the message.
So in other words, if we take 1 to 3 right here and send it off to emailer, one emailer one has to
eventually acknowledge receipt of that message.
Acknowledging receipt can either mean that, hey, we got the message and that's it, or it can mean
that WORKER one received the message and tried to process this thing and sent an email off to someone.
So it essentially allows us to send a message or kind of a signal back over to Redis, that worker one
has successfully processed a message.
At a future point, we're going to learn that we can find all the messages that have not been acknowledged
and make sure that those get processed.
And that's how we're going to handle the case in which a worker receives a message and then crashes.
Last thing.
Is that as as a part of the stream log register will keep track of the last delivered ID.
So if we first do 123, one, two, three and then we deliver nine, nine, nine.
Right.
It will keep track of the fact that that was the last delivered ID.
The benefit to this is that if we get some additional message in the future, like, let's say a message
with ID five, five, five and we need to send this off to some worker, we no longer have to make sure
that each worker understands what the current ID is or the most recent ID.
Instead, each worker can just say, Hey, give me the next undelivered message.
And when it asks for the next undelivered message, it will automatically be given the most recent undelivered
message.
So in this case, five, five, five.
And then we would update this last, delivered it right here to the five, five, five I.D..
Okay.
So each of these little features in isolation kind of seems like, yeah, not a big deal, but it's
really when we put all these very special characteristics together that we get a very powerful framework
to implement this kind of job processing setup that we've been discussing.
So this entire flow right here.
So if we ever want to build some kind of message producer and message consumer workflow, we are almost
always going to be using a consumer group unless you've got a very a very good reason not to do so.
So then mind becomes really important for us to understand how consumer groups work.
So as I mentioned, we're going to come back to the next video.
We're going to create a consumer group and then run a couple of commands to just understand how they
work.