To really understand consumer groups.
We need to play around with them a little bit and that's what we're going to do starting in this video.
We're going to learn about a couple of commands we can use to make a group and then add some workers
to it.
So our first command is X group creates, which as you guess is going to create a new consumer group
tied to a stream.
So we're going to run this command.
The first argument is going to be the key of a stream will then provide the name of our group.
Then the next argument is a little bit tricky.
We can create a group for either a new stream or an existing stream.
If we make a group or an existing stream, we need to decide what we want to do about all the messages
that already exist inside the stream.
We can put in an ID right here, like say something like that, which you mean make this new group and
consider all the messages from this idea on to not have been processed by the group in any way.
We could put in a00, which means consider all the messages in the existing stream to not be processed
by this group or a dollar sign, which means consider only messages added from this point on to be needed
to be consumed by the group.
And then the last argument is going to be whether or not we want to use an existing stream or just create
a new one.
So if we are trying to create a group for a stream that does not yet exist, we can run or add on the
argument of make stream.
Now, everything we do, you and I, in this course around consumer groups, is going to assume that
we are creating a brand new empty stream.
So we are going to use an argument of either a dollar sign right there or zero zero, and we will always
add on the make stream argument.
Let's go over to our book and we're going to try to run this command ourselves really quickly.
Now over here, we've already got a stream called fruits.
I want to create another stream called fruits.
What?
I want to be really picky about what data we add to it, because as we start to work with this consumer
group, we're going to eventually have to be very cognizant of what messages exist inside there.
So I'm going to delete the existing cells I have and then I'm going to delete the stream we had created.
So I'll do a Dell Fruits.
I'm starting over from scratch here.
I'm going to leave the adult fruits inside of here because we're going to eventually delete our stream
and the consumer group several times as we explore how consumer groups work.
After running the model all then do our command.
We just learned about sale to an x group creates.
My name is going to be Roots.
The group name will be Fruits Group.
I'm going to start from Dollar Sign and I'll add on make stream to make sure that it's really clear
that I want to create the stream from scratch.
I'm going to run that and that's pretty much it.
So now made the stream and we have a group tied to it.
By default, this group is going to be completely empty.
So we need to add in some actual consumers to it.
To add in a consumer, we're going to use another command called X Group Create Consumer.
So this, as a guess, makes a new consumer.
Now, an important thing to note here is that on some of these diagrams I've shown you, I've kind of
made it seem like a consumer group is something that exists outside of Redis, but it's not.
It's a data structure that exists inside of Reddit's.
Reddit's has some record of all the different consumers that are a member of this given group.
So we're not just carefully configuring a client or something like that to connect to a consumer group.
We are specifically telling Reddit's that a consumer group, it exists and it will eventually have some
different members whose names are this, this and this.
So we're going to make sure consumers, one is going to have a name of Fruits one.
The second will have a name of fruits, too.
The arguments to X group create consumer are the key of our stream and the name of our group and then
the name of the consumer.
We want to add.
Let's try adding this.
I will do in the same cell an ex group create consumer.
Our stream is at key fruits.
We are adding to the fruits group.
And then we're going to first add in a worker called Fruits.
What should I call it?
Yeah, fruits.
One can also call that worker one.
Maybe that would be a little bit more clear, just so we don't have the word fruits all over the place.
I'll call this one.
Worker one.
And I'm going to copy paste that down and add in a second worker called Worker two.
I'm going to run this and it looks like everything worked.
Now at this point, rather than trying to add in any messages or anything like that, I want to just
make sure that we have successfully created our stream and the group and the two workers.
Let's take a look at a couple of commands that allow us to examine the state of our consumer group.
So two commands to understand what's going on with our stream and the consumer group.
First is info groups.
This is going to list all the different consumer groups that are tied to a given stream.
And then to understand a little bit more about the consumers inside there, we can do X info consumers.
Let's try doing just x info groups first.
So on the next code cell down.
We'll do an x info.
Groups.
On the fruits stream.
I'm going to run that.
And then we will be told very simply here that there is currently one group tied to the stream.
It has a name for its group.
There are two consumers.
There are no pending messages, so no messages that need to be processed by this group.
And then we can also see that, yes, it does, in fact, keep track of what the last delivered ID is
for this entire group.
Let's also take a look at info consumers.
On the next code cell down.
I'll do an x info consumers.
Look at fruits.
Rights group.
And remember, France, right here is the name of the stream and we have the name of the group.
So I'm going to run that.
And then we'll be told about the two workers that we have created.
I've got a name of worker one.
It has zero messages pending.
It has not tried to process any messages in the last 95 seconds.
We can see some similar info down here with worker number two as well.
As soon as we start to actually process messages by these new workers, we're going to see some additional
information added into these things.
So we'll come back and run this command a couple of times again, just to understand what's going on
inside of our group.
Okay.
So we've got the group created.
We can now inspect the group to some degree.
Now it's time to actually add some messages into our stream and try to process them.
So let's take care of that in just a moment.