To understand a little bit more around consumer groups.
I would like to add in a couple of elements to our stream.
So inside this first code cell, I'm going to add in a couple lines here at the bottom.
In total, I'm going to add in three messages to the fruit stream.
I'll do an X, add a fruits, and then remember, usually we would put in a star right here, which
means that we want Redis to put in a timestamp for us automatically.
We're going to override that behavior just to make this example in the diagrams around it a little bit
easier to understand.
So I'm going to override the automatic ID creation and put in a hardcoded ID of ten dash zero instead.
Remember, we would normally not do this on any real project.
We would always want to default to allowing readers to assign the timestamp for us.
We're only doing this to make these diagrams make a little bit more sense.
And they're going to add in a name of banana and a color of yellow.
And then I'm going to duplicate that line down twice.
On the next one, I'll give an idea of 20 and then 30.
On the second one, I'll do a name of Apple and a color of red.
And then finally, a name of orange and a color of orange.
What's going to add a comment on here that just makes it super clear?
Don't specify an idea.
Let Red s do it with Star.
Just as a reminder to ourselves in the future.
Okay, Arun, that's.
So now we've got our stream.
We've got a consumer group, two consumers and three messages inside of the stream.
Now we're going to understand how we can read messages out of a stream using a consumer group.
To do so we're going to use a command very similar to X Reid, just a little variation on it called
x Reid Group, so it behaves very similar to X read.
It just follows all the semantics we discussed around consumer groups a moment ago.
The first argument is going to be the name of our group.
So group for each group.
We're then going to specify who we want to pretend that we are.
So we're going to put in a worker name right here.
So remember, whenever we are creating a group, this is not really something that is tied very closely
to the individual clients or the API servers or anything like that that we are interacting with the
writers with.
Instead, this entire idea of a consumer group is something that exists entirely inside of Redis.
So whenever we interact with a consumer group, we need to be very specific and say we are interacting
with this group, pretending that we are currently worker one or worker two, three or four or whatever
else.
We then have two optional arguments once again.
So count one and block 2000.
And then here is another interesting addition.
We're going to specify which streams we want to read from.
And we're also going to put in a special symbol right here.
We can put in the idea of where we want to start reading from our stream from, but we usually are going
to use a shortcut instead of just a greater than sine this greater than sine means.
Give us any undelivered messages, any messages that have not yet been delivered to or processed by
anyone else inside the consumer group.
Yes.
Let's try running this command really quickly.
Back over here.
I'm going to add in a new code cell underneath the first one.
And then we will do an X.
Reid group.
The group is brutes group.
I want to pretend that I am worker one.
I only want to get one element so I can do a count one.
And then streams roots greater than.
That's all on one line.
I'm going to run that and we should get back our idea of ten banana color yellow.
And sure enough, that's exactly what happens.
Now at this point, it looks like we got the message and that's it.
But there's a lot of stuff going on behind the scenes now.
I want to show you a diagram and help you really start to picture and visualize what just occurred.
Okay.
Here we go.
So here's Regis.
We've got our stream.
There are three messages inside of it.
We've got a stream log that doesn't really have a lot of info in it just yet.
We've then got worker one and Worker two inside of our consumer group.
We just ran this command right here.
So this means saying or pretending that we are.
Worker one Go into our stream, get one message and we want to get the first message that has not been
delivered to anyone else.
That's what the greater that means.
The readies internally is going to look at its stream log.
It's going to look at the last delivered ID.
It's going to see that nothing has ever been delivered before.
So it's going to go and find the very first message and send it off to worker one.
After sending that off to work or one Reddit will immediately make an update to the stream log.
It's going to say I sent ten zero to worker one.
They have not acknowledged the message yet.
Remember, every message has to be acknowledged by the worker at some point in time.
Otherwise, Red is going to think that it's still pending and it's still waiting to be processed by
that worker.
We're going to cover the entire process of acknowledging a message in just a little bit.
We have not discussed that yet.
Readers will then also update this last delivered ID.
210 dash zero.
Now remember reticent generally does not delete that message out of the stream.
It still exists.
Any other worker or any other consumer can still read from the stream.
Normally, we can even have multiple consumer groups operating on a single stream.
So the consumer group doesn't change the behavior of the stream itself.
It just really adds on this additional data structure.
The stream log for this particular consumer group.
So the original message still there.
Let's now imagine that we do a second x ray group are we're going to change the worker name to worker
two and everything else can stay the same.
What would happen in this case?
Well, WORKER two We're going to imagine is going to need to get another message.
So this is going to look at the last delivered ID.
It's going to see that the last delivered one was ten zero.
So it's going to go and find the next message, which in this case is 20 zero.
You'll will send it off to work or to and then update the stream log to say I sent one zero to work
or to.
They have not asked the message yet.
And then it will also update the last delivered it.
And I think you can see where this is going.
If we now did another X Reid group.
With Worker one.
We will now get 30.
Send it off to worker one.
We would put in this updated message into our stream log.
Now.
Our last delivered ID would be 30.
That's everything that's going on behind the scenes.
Let's go and run a couple more commands now.
We're going to do some more X regroups.
We're also going to run those X info commands and just verify that this is all how things are working.
At this point.
I've only read the ten zero, so let's try doing an x info groups.
We'll see that the last delivered ID is ten zero.
There's one message pending.
So that's the message that we sent to Worker one.
But it has not yet been asked.
So pending means not acknowledged yet.
And then if we get some info on the group itself, we'll see that worker one has one message pending.
And Worker two.
Nothing pending just yet.
All right, let's do another X, regroup.
I'm going to change the worker name to worker two.
I'll run that.
So now we get 20 8-0 only as expected.
If we do another X info groups, we'll now see that two messages are pending that those are waiting
to be asked.
Last delivered idea of 20.
And as you guessed, if we do an x info, consumers will now see that worker number two has a pending
message as well.
Okay.
So we've gotten pretty far on consumer groups.
I think the last big ticket item for us to understand here is what it really means to ask a message.
Acting is the real key concept here that's going to help us recover if some worker gets delivered a
message and then just mysteriously crashes for some reason.
So let's take a look at acting in the next video.