As I mentioned, we're going to start to understand how acknowledgment or action a message works in
this video.
The entire idea behind asking is handling the case in which we deliver a message to some worker, and
then that worker crashes before processing the message in any way.
So ideally, our worker would receive the message.
Process it.
So maybe send an email or do whatever is required and then acknowledge the message.
Okay, so let's understand how this works.
I'm going to first do a little bit of setup over in Arabic.
So I'm going to reset my entire state by running the first cell right here.
I'm then going to do an X-rated group and assigned the first message to worker one.
So now worker one has ownership of message with ID ten zero.
That message is now in a pending states.
We got something like this right here.
So we need to acknowledge that pending message.
To do so, we're going to run the command x ec.
That's pretty much it.
Pretty straightforward command.
We'll do an exact.
The name of our stream, the name of the group, and then the idea of the message that we are trying
to acknowledge.
Then this case would be ten dash zero.
Let's try this out really quickly.
Underneath the X read group, I'm going to add in another code cell and I'll do an exact.
Roots roots group.
And then the idea, the message is ten zero.
If I run that, I get back a one saying, okay, sounds good.
Message has been acknowledged.
We can then do an x info groups and see that there are zero messages pending.
I can also do an x info consumers and it looks like worker one has zero pending.
So the message that was sent to it has been acknowledged.
That's kind of a happy case.
That's a case in which we get our message.
We process it.
Everything goes just fine.
But what happens if we deliver this message to Worker one and then before doing anything with it whatsoever?
Worker one crashes.
So now we're left in a scenario where we kind of have this outstanding message.
It needs to be processed by someone.
But how do we get it over to another worker such as worker two?
You get these messages that have been left hanging or stuck in a pending state?
We're going to use another command called X Auto Claim.
Exotic claim does exactly what we need it to do, basically.
It's going to take a look at all the different messages that have been left in a pending state for some
amount of time and then assign that message to another available worker.
So we'll run X Auto Claim here, the stream name of the group and then the place where we want to assign
the outstanding messages to.
So in this case, maybe worker two because worker two is still up and running.
Well, then put in a timeout right here.
This is not quite a timeout.
It's more like a filter.
This means go and find all the messages that have been unacknowledged for over 10,000 milliseconds or
10 seconds.
We can, of course, change this value so we can instead look for messages that have been pending for
30 seconds or whatever else.
And then the last argument means find any pending messages that exist after this particular issue.
So we put in zero zero.
That means go back to the very first message and then from there forward, find any that are stuck in
this pending state.
Let's test out ex auto claim really quickly.
Hey, back over here.
I'm going to again reset my state at the top.
I'll then do an X redo group and assign the first message to Worker one.
Now we're going to wait a couple of seconds for this message to basically we can imagine it's time out
right now.
WORKER one is just not doing its job.
It's not acknowledging the message.
And so now we probably want to find that message and claim its or really assign it over to worker two
instead.
So instead of doing the exact down here, I'm going to do an x auto claim.
We're going to look at fruits rights group.
We want to assign any pending messages to worker to.
Our time out is going to be 10 seconds, which I think have definitely passed by this point in time.
And we want to start at message with it zero zero and move forward from there.
Okay.
I'm going to run that.
And now as a response, we get back all the messages that have been claimed or moved over to Worker
Two's responsibility.
So in this case, it was one message.
It was the ten zero message.
We can now do the x info commands.
Let's do groups.
We'll see that there's still one pending.
And if we look at the consumers in that group, we'll see that worker one has zero messages pending.
And Worker two has one.
So that single message has now been moved over to worker two and worker two is now in charge of processing
it.
Okay.
So that's it.
So that's pretty much it on stream.
That's all we're going to cover.
But I think you can kind of get the idea or the picture of how we could take this idea of consumer groups
and use it to put together a working or a work processing framework.