Let's take a look at a couple of diagrams to understand how streams work and then take a look at a practical
use case of a stream.
Okay, here we go.
So as usual, you have read us here in the middle.
We got a stream.
This is our data structure that's going to eventually store some amount of information.
And then on the left hand side over here, I've got something called a message producer.
And then on the right hand side is something called a message consumer.
These producers and consumers are intended to be separate servers, processes, APIs.
Some piece of software that you and I author.
Our message producer is then going to try to communicate some information with the consumer.
So the producer is going to create a message.
A message is like a hash.
It's a collection of key value pairs.
No nesting of data inside this hash is allowed.
So we cannot store a hash inside of a hash.
It's just like a normal, reddest hash.
The message producer is going to add this message into the stream.
Inside the stream.
The message will exist and it's going to be assigned an ID.
The ID is going to be.
The time at which this message was added in UNIX time stamp formats.
That's going to be a millisecond value.
So something like that.
And then a-0 on the end.
I'll tell you what the dash zero is in a little bit.
So we can think of this as kind of like a little key value pair in its own right.
We've got the idea pointing to a particular message.
That's how the message exists inside the stream.
Then at some point in time, this consumer is going to ask for all the most recent messages that have
been added to the stream.
So we're going to take this message and it gets sent off to the consumer.
The consumer can then process that message in some way.
When the consumer reads a message, it is not deleted from the original stream.
It stays there until we specifically say that we want to delete that message.
Okay.
So that's pretty much what a stream is.
It stores these little hash like objects.
We have these ideas that point at them and they are really meant for communicating information between
some producer and some consumer.
Now, obviously, there's still a lot of details to fill in here, but let me immediately show you a
extremely common use case of streams.
This is really the primary use case.
This is really the whole reason that streams exist at all.
So I first show you a little sample application that is not quite set up ideally, so we don't really
want to build an application like this.
I just want you to help you understand why we would use a stream.
So let's imagine we are building some kind of API that's going to receive requests to send an email
to someone.
Leah's request says, Please send an email to SDF at gmail.com.
Our server will receive that and it's going to realize that it needs to make a request to some third
party email API to actually get the emails sent.
Now as servers making the request off to this third party API.
The original request right here is still hanging.
It's still pending.
It is still waiting for a response.
It might take this third party email API several seconds to actually successfully send the email.
So in the entire time that we are waiting for a response from this third party email, the original
request is just sitting there in a pending state.
When we finally get a response from the email API, we can now respond to the original request.
Now, is there something inherently wrong about leaving this request pending?
Well, it kind of depends upon the volume of traffic you are expecting, but in general, we don't really
like to have pending requests just sitting around.
So we might make use of a stream to simplify this process a little bit and allow ourselves to not have
to just have this request sitting around and pending.
So here's how we might use streams to enhance this entire process a little bit more.
Not only solve the problem of having this request pending for a certain amount of time, but also solve
the case in which we might get a lot of requests in very short order asking us to send some emails.
So this is how we would use a stream.
So we've still got a request coming in to some server here.
The server is our message producer.
Though, the message producer, when it receives this request is going to queue up or put a message
into our stream.
The message might look like this might have a two fields and a message field.
So too is where we are trying to send an email to.
The message might be the subject line of the email or whatever else.
As soon as we have added this message into the stream, we can then immediately send a response back
to this original request.
So it doesn't have to sit around pending any longer.
So our producer is going to queue up this message.
Though it will be added into our stream.
And be given that ID which is a UNIX timestamp.
Dash zero.
And then separately, we're going to have a worker over here.
Or again, we can refer to this as a message consumer.
This thing is going to wait around for some message to be added into our stream.
As soon as a message is added, we're going to get it sent over to our worker or our consumer.
The worker is going to see these the hash rate here.
It's going to say, okay, I need to send an email to this person and it must have this subject line.
The worker will receive this message across the set by sending a request off to a third party email
API and get the actual email sent.
All right.
Now, this entire process might not really sound like it solves the original problem of having this
request pending.
Then you might have some outstanding issues, such as how does the person who made this request know
the email was actually sent successfully?
That's all stuff we will figure out over time.
What I really want you to understand right now is that the flow that I just described is really the
primary use case of streams.
We have a message producer queuing up some little data structures.
Those are going to be consumed by some other worker inside of our application.
Just about every major application out there in the world has a set up like this.
It has some number of message producers, some kind of message broker, something like retest, who
stored these messages.
And then we've got some consumers that are taking these messages and processing them in some way.
Again, just about every application in the world has a set up like this.
When we talk about streams, we're really going to be discussing streams and learning about them from
this perspective, from understanding that we're probably trying to queue up some little message here
that needs to have some work done to it, and that's going to be cued up by a producer.
And we're going to eventually get that message with a worker and then process the message in some way.
All right.
So now we understand kind of the use case here and why we're using streams at all.
Now it's time to start to learn the specifics of them, how we create them, how we queue up messages
and so on.