The first command around streams we're going to look at is the X ad command.
This is how we add in a new message to a stream.
So we can kind of imagine that we've got a message produced over here.
We will use X ad to create a message and add it into the stream like so.
And this message gets added in, you'll be given an idea automatically that points to that message.
And again, the idea is going to have the Unix time in milliseconds at which this message was added
into the stream.
You'll notice that we've got that Dash zero on right there.
Really quickly.
What is that all about?
Well, the Dash zero is used to account for any time when multiple messages are added in the exact same
millisecond.
Let's assume that we've got two or three or four messages all added at exactly the same time.
Make sure that each of these messages gets distinguished on its own.
Right.
The first one.
We'll be given an idea of the current time in milliseconds with a-0 and then the next one, assuming
it is processed in the exact same milliseconds, will be given the same millisecond timestamp value.
But instead of a-0, it will be given a-1.
So the dashes on there are just to distinguish between different messages that are added in the same
millisecond.
That's it.
All right, so let's try making use of this ad command.
We're going to exceed.
We're going to provide as the first argument, the key where our stream is stored.
We do not have to create a stream ahead of time.
We can just make use of x ad and it will be created for us if it doesn't already exist.
Then going to put in a star, which means that we want Redis to generate an ID for us, so we want it
to generate the Unix timestamp for us automatically.
Well then do alternating key value.
Key value.
So those are the key value.
Pairs will be stored inside the message hash.
Yeah.
Let's give this a shot over Ann Arbor.
I've already created a brand new notebook over here.
I'm going to do a X ad.
Roots star.
And then we're going to add in all of our keys and values in alternating order.
I might have a color of red and a name of strawberry.
And that's it.
So that right there where we in response is the Unix timestamp in milliseconds dash zero and again that
dash zero means that no other message was added in the exact same millisecond.
Now we've got something inside of our stream.
How do we actually get it out?
How do we actually read data out of our stream?
Let's take a look at that in the next video.