We've got a message inside of our stream.
And so now we would want a message consumer to somehow read this message out and process it in some
way.
To do so, we're going to use the command called X Read.
This is used whenever we want to read messages out of our stream.
So we'll do a x, read streams and the key of the stream we want to read from.
And then immediately after that, we're going to add in an argument designating the range of elements
or the range of messages that we want to actually retrieve.
If we put in zero zero, that means read all messages that have ever been added to this stream.
We can also put in a full timestamp value there as well.
So we do an X, read streams, fruits and then a Unix timestamp.
That means read all messages that have been added to the stream after, but not including this particular
timestamp.
So we can use X Reid to either get all messages or just filter down to messages after some particular
area in time.
Okay, so let's try it out.
Back over inside of our book.
I will do a x read streams.
Our stream is stored at a key of fruits.
And then right now, I'll do just zero.
Dash zero.
And there is my single message that I've added already.
So we get the name of the stream that we just read from.
And then we get the idea of that message and then the key value pairs that make it up.
Zales try using a little bit more specific time stamp in here.
I'm going to find the idea of the message we just added in the last video.
We're going to copy it and put it in right there in place of the zero zero.
Now this means read all messages that have been added after this time stamp, not including that stamp.
So if I run that, I'll get null because we did not find anything.
But if I subtract one from this timestamp, so if I change that four into a three, for example.
Now I'm going to get all messages after that millisecond in the past.
So that would include the message I had previously added.
Now, one thing to take note of, and we're kind of seeing it in action right here when we read a message,
it is not deleted from the original stream.
It still sits around, it's still there, and we can read it as often as we want to.
But just because we're doing an X read right now, the original message is not destroyed or deleted
in any way.
That's going to become rather important later on.
So just keep in mind for a little bit.
There's one other variation on X read I want you to be aware of.
In some cases, we might have a stream that has hundreds or thousands or tens of thousands of messages
inside of it.
So in many cases, we want to limit how many elements we get back.
We could do so by adding on the accounts arguments.
So if we add X read count two, that means read up to but no more than two messages.
Let's try that out.
Back over here really quickly.
I'm going to run the ad up here once again.
I'm going to change the color to yellow with the name of banana.
Now my stream has two messages inside of it.
If I do an x reid with zero zero, I will see both messages.
There's the first.
There's the second.
And if I add on a count of one.
Now I will just get the first message.
One with a colour of red and a name of strawberry.
If I do a count of two, I'll see both them.
And of course, if I do a count of three X, Reid is just going to try to read up to three.
But if there aren't three available, that's fine.
It's going to return what it gets.
So if I do a count of three, I'm still going to get back the strawberry right here and the banana right
there.
Okay.
So that's ex right now.
Although the exact amount in x read seem pretty simple and straightforward.
Well, naturally there is little variation on these commands that make them a little bit more challenging
to understand.
Let's take a look at the first variation of X read in the next video.