Let's take a look at a major variation on the X read commands.
So we will do an X read, but we're going to add on an additional argument here of block and then some
millisecond value.
This dramatically changes the way that the X read command works.
If we were to now run this command and there were no messages currently available inside of our stream
to be read and the X read command is going to sit around and wait for 3 seconds or 3000 milliseconds
and see if some additional message is added in that time.
And to really understand this, probably easiest for us to take a look at a diagram.
So let's do that really quickly.
Okay.
So kind of confusing diagram.
Let's start over here on the right hand side.
So in this scenario, we're going to imagine that our stream is currently completely empty and our message
consumer is going to start off the entire process by running command of X read block.
So we can interpret that command as meaning.
Try and read some messages of the stream, but if none are available, then just sit around and wait
for some number of milliseconds.
And so now this command is going to be sitting around in eight pending states and time is going to be
passing.
And then some number of milliseconds later, maybe our message producer creates a message and adds it
into the stream.
I'm going to add the message in really quickly here.
Like so.
So now a message is available inside the stream, right?
This is going to notice that it had this pending exe read lock command running and so it's going to
take that message and automatically send it off in response to that previous x read command.
So the message consumer is going to immediately receive that message as soon as it has been added into
the stream.
Now.
Why would we do this?
Well, this adds in a really interesting dynamic treatise.
You might have noticed that in the past, the only way that we can really easily tell if some data had
been added Metis was to just send in commands as fast as we could.
And we really saw an example of that when we put together our LOC implementation, when we were trying
to acquire a lock.
We had a retry strategy in there, and the retry strategy basically revolved around just sending in
lock requests as quickly as we could until we eventually acquired it.
That meant that we were sending in a ton of commands to Redis, even though there might not have been
any data ready for us to actually work with.
By using this block argument, we are avoiding having to send a ton of ex read commands off to read
us to see if anything is available inside the stream.
Instead of sending in dozens and dozens of x reads when the stream is empty, we can now just send in
one single x ray block and then eventually be told immediately whenever some data is available.
Let's try an x ray block inside of our book really quickly.
It's back over here.
I'm going to rewrite that X we had done previously.
I'm going to change it to you.
X read Locke 3000.
Streams, routes and then zero zero.
Now, if we run this command, we're going to immediately get a response because some data is available
from the timestamp starting at zero zero on.
If I send that, we immediately get that response back.
You'll notice that the formatting is a little bit different here.
Just because I treat the formatting of x ray block a little bit different inside of our book, just
make it really easy to read the result.
Let's now try changing the ID range here to some time in the future where we will definitely not get
back any info to make sure we get a future timestamp in there.
I could take the latest timestamp out of my messages here.
So for me that would be the color yellow message.
I'll take that idea right there and I will put it in right there.
Now, if we run, this command is going to sit around waiting for 3 seconds, checking to see if any
data becomes available.
If any data does not become available in that time, then the command is just going to timeouts and
we're not going to get any information back.
Let's now try running x ray block.
And then immediately after we run it, I'm going to go up to the top here and add in a new element to
the stream.
Before I do the x ray block, I'm going to change yellow to orange.
And name to orange as well that we will execute the extra block will then very quickly do the add and
we should just about instantaneously see the x read resolved with a newly added element.
Here we go.
Run that in a one or 2 seconds on that.
And then sure enough down here.
Our x ray block does resolve.
It sees that newly added element that just got added into the stream.
Okay.
So it looks pretty good.
We got this big variation on X reed and it really just opens the door of getting information out of
a stream without having to hammer Reddit's non-stop asking for data.
Before we move on, there's one other little thing I want to mention here, and that is the interplay
between x ray block and the count command.
So I'm going to update the timestamp here.
With the now latest timestamp.
So it's going to be for me that timestamp right there, whatever I got back when I just added in the
orange.
Orange.
So I'm going to put that in for my x read commands.
I then put in a count of about five.
Now, if we run this, we're not going to get any response back.
I'm going to change the course at this time.
Will do.
How about a red?
Apple.
I'm going to do the x rayed again and then the X out immediately.
There's the read.
There's the ad.
Now what I want you to notice here, the only thing I want you to notice is that if we put on a count
five here with the block, we're not going to block until we get five elements.
Instead, we're going to return.
From the X read as soon as at least one element is available.
If we do the X read and there's already five or more available, we will get back five.
But otherwise, when we do block and count together, we're going to kind of somewhat ignore that count.
If we get at least one element added to the stream though in short, the X read is going to return early
if it sees even one element added.
Even though we've got the count on there.
Okay.
So again, just want you to see that little variation.
Now there's a couple of very small pieces of syntax around block I want you to understand.
So we'll take a look at those in the next video.