As we just saw a little bit ago, the last argument to the X read command is a timestamp value.
So whatever timestamp we put in there pretty much means look for new messages that have been added after
that point in time.
When we are making use of the block argument, it's very common for us to want to start watching for
messages that have been added after.
Exactly.
Right now.
In other words, we might say block for 5 seconds watching for messages that have been added from right
now on having to figure out exactly what time to put in here to represent.
Now can be a little bit challenging.
So as a shortcut, we can put in a dollar sign and the dollar sign really just means block for 3 seconds
watching for any new messages that have been added from right now on.
Let's try out this variation really quickly.
Back over here.
I'm going to do a dollar sign.
Instead of a time stamp.
Well, then go to the ad.
I'm going to change color to yellow and name to pineapple.
I'll then run the X rewrite here.
So I'm going to block four data for 3 seconds and we're watching for any new messages from right now
on.
Of course, no new messages are being added.
So the command teams out without actually retrieving any data.
Now, I'm going to run it.
I'm going to do the ad and I will see Pineapple immediately returned right there.
So, again, just a little shortcut to represent looking for messages right now going on into the future.