Just a moment ago, I showed you this dollar sign shortcuts in place of an actual time stamp.
There is a little gotcha around using this dollar sign.
I want to tell you about inside this video and in this video as we discuss this gotcha.
It's not really so much that I want you to understand the gotcha so much as I just want you to start
thinking about how streams work and understand that time and streams contain some interesting mechanics
around them.
Okay.
So a couple of quick diagrams right here.
So in this diagram, I've got a time series diagram.
We're starting off up here at the very top.
We've got our stream inside of Redis and then a consumer over here on the stream.
We're going to imagine that some amount of time goes by and then we get three messages showing up that
have IDs of simply ten, 11 and 12.
In reality, the IDs would be UNIX time stamps like so.
Again, we're just going to imagine that they have very simple ideas of ten, 11 and 12.
And then over here on the consumer, we're going to imagine that we run an X read block 3000 with a
dollar sign.
Remember, the dollar sign means starting right now at this present point in time.
Watch for any additional messages that have been added over the next 3 seconds.
I want to imagine what would happen behind the scenes if we executed this with the hopes of getting
all three messages over to our consumer.
In addition, I want to imagine that whenever we receive a message on the consumer, it takes a couple
of milliseconds for us to actually process the message and then start listening for additional messages
again.
Okay.
So let's imagine what happens.
Well, as soon as we run the command, we're going to pause for a wait for 3 seconds.
Then our stream is to have this first element right here show up with an idea of ten.
The instant that message shows up.
Our x ray command is going to resolve that.
We will be sent back immediately.
This message of ten we're going to receive it will well imagine we process that message for the span
of maybe about 20 milliseconds or so.
And then when we are all done processing it, we start doing our x read again, watching for any additional
messages to come in.
And when we do that second x read, you might use that shortcut of a dollar sign again.
But do you notice a little problem here?
When we use that dollar sign, it means from right now look for any messages going forward.
And whenever a single message shows up inside the stream, it will immediately be sent back to our X
read command.
So up here when we got the ten and then two additional messages were added on immediately after.
We are now ignoring or skipping these messages entirely.
Because we did the first X read, we got the first message, we processed it, and then a couple milliseconds
later we start up our next X read and we are not going to actually receive the 11 or the 12 right here.
How would we fix this?
Well, to fix this, we might still be able to do at this very first initial read with a dollar sign
shortcuts.
But as soon as we receive a message, any future x ray that we do needs to use that messages ID as the
starting point for our follow up x ray down here.
So in other words, we should have done in place of the dollar sign right here a ten.
So that means go back to ten right here and look for any messages that have been added after the idea
of ten.
That would then give us 11 and 12.
And then we would process those.
And then we did another x rayed after that.
Our ID down here would be the idea of the most recently processed message.
So now would be 12th.
So this X read would capture any messages out added after the 12th.
So in short, when we make use of the dollar sign, we just need to be aware that if our intent is really
to do a running processing of any messages added over time to a stream, we can't just always use the
dollar sign.
We can use it the very first time that we have a consumer start reading from messages.
But after that we really have to do X reads using actual IDs.
It should be the idea of the most recently processed message.
Okay.
So again, the intent here was not really to help you understand this little gotcha, because frankly,
you're not going to use this very basic X-ray command terribly often instead of going to use a slightly
different command.
Instead, the idea here, the goal was to just help you start to think about these little kind of timing
issues around strings, because a lot of them are going to start to come up as we look at some more
complex use cases around strings.