Let's move on to another command.
This one is X range.
X range is nearly identical to X read, which we are just discussing in great detail.
So you're pretty much going to already understand everything around X range.
The only reason that I'm covering both commands is because some documentation is going to show using
streams with X read other documentation will use x range.
So you kind of have to know both.
And there technically are a couple of very small gotchas and differences between them.
Okay, so x range, the key where our stream is stored.
And then here's the first difference between X read in x range, we're going to put in a starting timestamp
and then an ending timestamp.
So it's going to give us a range of messages between these two timestamps.
And then very important to understand, these timestamps are inclusive.
So if we had a message with a timestamp of one, two, three, four, five, it would include that with
x range it's opposite with x read.
When we use x read, if we put in an actual timestamp value like this right here, this is exclusive.
We will not get a message with a timestamp of 1999.
So it's exactly the opposite between x read and x range.
When we make use of X range, we can also add on a count option as well and that will give us no more
than whatever we are asking for.
But of course, if there are less than five elements, say we will get however many are available.
Yeah.
Let's try this out really quickly in our book.
So back over here.
I'm going to add in a new code cell.
I still have the idea for pineapple right here.
So I'm going to use that idea in just a moment.
I'm going to copy it.
If you do not have that idea still handy, you can either find the ID by doing a normal x read or just
add in another fruit.
Well, then do a range.
On fruits.
I'm going to start at the pineapple and I'll go to the same ID for the pineapple, but I'm going to
add on one millisecond to it.
So there's pineapple.
There's pineapple plus one millisecond.
If I run that, I will see that it does in fact include pineapple, which is the opposite of what X
Reid would have done.
X Reid would have given us everything after that timestamp.
A couple of very quick variations on X reed.
First off, we can change that inclusive behavior by putting in an open parentheses before either or
both timestamps.
So if we do the open parentheses, no closing, just the open side.
And that is going to give us messages starting at but not including that timestamp.
So if I add on a parentheses right before that time stamp right there, that was the pineapple one.
I'm no longer going to get any results whatsoever.
So we can put that parentheses on either or both of the timestamps.
And then finally, a little shortcut that's available to us.
We can use a minus or a plus in place of these timestamps, though minus means go get the minimum.
80 plus means get the maximum so we can use these to say Give me all messages after a point in time
where all messages before a point in time.
For example, if I did something like say.
It's going to delete the last couple of milliseconds here.
So that's kind of some arbitrary time.
Very far in the past at this point.
And then I'll put in a plus somebody from this time long, long ago, all the way to the far, far future.
Give me all elements that should be pretty much everything we've ever added into the stream.
We could also do something like give me everything in the past.
Up to what?
Not including the pineapple time stamp.
That will give us everything in the past, not including pineapple.
That is a previous pineapple I added in right there.
I added in two pineapples.
So that's a previous one.
It's not the one I had added in.
You'll notice the time stamp of it is different than the one I have right there.
Okay.
Like I said, just a couple of variations on X range at the end of day, very similar to X read.
The only big differences are the time.
Stamps by default are inclusive as opposed to exclusive.
An x range also does not have the blocking variant as well.