We understand the basics of streams, and I think you might be able to understand how we could create
a system like the one I mentioned a little bit ago.
So we might create a message producer that would do an ad to add a message into a stream that would
indicate that we need to send an email to someone.
We could then create a message consumer that would do an X read or an X range to get these messages.
Process them in some way and send a request off to a third party API to actually send an email.
So at this point, you know, we could probably build a system like this.
But I want to point out that there are a couple of issues we would run into very quickly if we use only
our existing knowledge of streams.
So two big issues in total.
First off, our standard stream that we've learned about so far is going to deliver all messages to
all consumers.
So let's imagine that at some point in time, we get a lot of requests asking for us to send emails
and we decide that to handle all these emails and the requests, we create multiple different consumers
or multiple different workers.
Now, the downside here is that each message is going to be copied and sent off to each individual worker.
Whenever they do an X read.
So when worker number one an x read on the stream, it's going to see a given message.
Worker two is going to see the same message and worker three will see the same message as well.
So we might accidentally end up sending a ton of duplicate emails out.
Clearly not a good solution.
The second problem is that it's kind of tough right now, too, for us to handle the case in which a
consumer crashes after receiving a message.
Let's imagine that we send this message to this worker and we assume that the worker is going to get
the email sent.
But maybe just after receiving the message, the worker crashes.
So now we're kind of left in a state where we don't really know if the email was sent or not because
the worker never reported the output of the email sending attempt.
The email might have been sent, but it might not have because we really don't know when the worker
crashed.
Okay.
So it's clear that between at least these two issues, our current understanding of streams still has
a couple of holes and we need to figure out some way of dealing with these two big problems.
Let's move on to the next video.
We're going to take a look at an additional feature around streams that's going to make them a little
bit more challenging to understand, but is going to very clearly and immediately solve these two issues.