Once again, we've got our item IDs.
We know which items we want to load up.
So all we have to do is take these item IDs and fetch the related hashes.
So that's how we're going to take care of right now.
And this general idea of taking some item IDs and fetching related data, well, that's what we refer
to as simply loading relational data out of Redis.
There are two strategies we're going to look out for loading relational data.
The first is going to be very simple and straightforward.
It's going to be going to pretty much mirrors stuff that we've done in the past.
So the first way of taking an array of IDs and somehow loading up other data from Redis using those
IDs, we're going to create a simple pipeline that just does a bunch of each get alls.
So pretty much loop over every single idea that we just fetch, do a single h, get all and do all those
commands.
Send them all up to Redis inside of a single pipeline.
Remember, pipelines are going to take a bunch of different commands, send them all over viridis in
one big batch and we'll get a big single batch in response.
The pipelines generally are pretty efficient, definitely a very reasonable way to do this.
The other way that we're going to take this array of IDs and somehow get the related hashes out of Redis
is by using another command that we have not yet used called source.
And this is going to be kind of a clever solution.
We're going to apply it to the other little kind of piece of data loading we have to do.
We're going to use it for back over here.
The most viewed section.
Right now, we're going to use the pipeline method for ending soonest and only use short for most views.
All right.
So with that in mind, let's get to it back inside of our editor.
Once again, I'm at two items by adding time.
We've got this list of ideas right here.
So just like we saw it in that diagram, we're going to loop over that list of ideas for every idea.
We're going to issue a, h, get all commands.
We will then run all those in a single pipeline, get back a whole bunch results D serialize them and
that's pretty much it.
So.
The set up our pipeline or first you issue all the different commands.
I'm going to do an ID start map.
I will take each individual ID.
And then return.
A command or a client.
Okay.
Get all.
Of items key with the given item hash ID.
We could shortness by removing the curly braces.
And the return keyword roundup with just that right there.
Then to actually set up and execute our pipeline.
We will wrap it with a promise sort all.
I'm then going to assign all this to a variable that I'm going to call results and I'm going to put
the awake keyword in there as well.
So now results in theory is going to be our serialised item data just to make sure that's the case.
I will do a console.log of results right there.
And once again, I'm going to test this out by going backward to my browser, refresh to the page,
and then going back to my terminal.
If you do not see any output right here, don't forget that we created these items with an ending at
time.
10 minutes in the future.
So if it took you longer than 10 minutes to get from that previous video to right here, you might not
see any results.
So if you don't see anything at all, first go and try to create a couple more items with an ending
at time, 10 minutes or one day or one week in the future, and then try refreshing the page again.
All right.
So here's my list of items.
And they have titles of Chair.
Couch and table.
And they are also in the correct order as well.
If you recall, I created items in order of chair, couch and table.
You might also notice that the views field on each of these is populated with one because I viewed each
item one single time right now.
So it looks like views as probably also working correctly.
All right, so now that we've got those hashes, we just need to serialize them and return them from
this function.
But to take care of that, I'm going to return results, not map.
I will take each item and run them through the serialized item.
The only other thing we have to do here.
Remember it.
D.C. Serialize takes that second argument of the first argument is the ID.
So we need to just get access to that ID.
Right now, results has just the item hashes without the actual item IDs.
So to get access to the IDs, we're going to use a little bit of trickery right here as a second argument
to the mapping function.
We are given the index of this item in the array of results.
I can use that index right there to look up the ID of this particular item from the IDS array.
It's a long story short for DC realized I'm going to put in a first argument of IDs at I like so.
Okay.
Let's save this.
Now, when we go back over and test this out.
Don't forget that these items, as I read them, I set them to all end in 10 minutes.
So if it took you longer than 10 minutes to get from where we created these different items to right
now, you might not see anything right here.
So if you don't see anything, just go and create a couple more items and then it should start to appear
right here.
Well, for me, it looks like everything worked out.
So I've got chair, couch and table.
And in theory, they are all listed in the correct order as well.
I can really test that out by going creating another item.
I'll give this one the item.
Name of.
Yes.
Go back to the landing page and now desk should appear at the end right here with an end in 9 minutes.
Perfect.
I'd say this is looking pretty good.
Okay.
So loading relational data in this case, super straightforward.
We had an array of IDs to get all the related data.
We just looped over the IDs, didn't get all.
We issued those get calls inside of a pipeline.
Now we've got this step done.
Well, let's move on.
Just showing a very similar list of items, the ones that have the most views and to load up the relational
data.
In that case, we first have to figure out the command to write.
The command to get the related IDs is going to be pretty easy.
Once we've got those IDs, the items with the most views, we can then use the sort commands which we're
going to go over in great detail as well.