Now seeing one example of loading up a bunch of relational data using a simple pipeline.
So that's what we just did.
Now, this definitely worked, and it was a pretty simple and straightforward approach.
But it had one simple downside to it.
And a downside was that it takes two separate quest to load up our data.
We had one request to fetch all the relevant keys out of our sorted set, and then we had to make a
second request to do our each get calls.
And there's really no way around that.
It's always going to take two separate requests.
Three going, go.
Now take a look at a second way of loading up some of our data.
In this case, we're going to use a command that we've not yet discussed, called sort.
Now, understanding sort is rather challenging.
It's one of the more challenging commands in red is to understand.
So in this video, we're going to write out a little bit of of code just to prove that we can load up
our data, this relational data, with one single command using source.
And then after that we're going to do a deep dive on the source command itself will then come back to
our application and kind of patch up our query a little bit more.
So again, right now, little bit of code writing just to make use of sort.
We're not going to dive into sort too much, come back, understand sorts and then eventually finish
up the implementation.
Okay.
So back inside my editor, I'm going to find our I views knots file inside the queries items directory.
This file is identical to the ending time file that we were just working on.
There's a single function inside of here that's going to be called with some order argument, offsets
and count.
And our goal is to return an array of items that have been serialized that have the most views.
Like I said, we're going to write out the implementation very quickly and then just kind of make sure
it's somewhat works and then do a deeper dive on source.
So let's get to it at the very top.
I'm going to first begin by importing client.
From services.
This.
Then our items key and items by views key.
Okay.
Then inside this function you can write out results is a weight client sorts.
I'm going to put in items by the use key.
So that's the key of our sorted set.
That's recording all these different item IDs with respect to the number of use they have.
And as a second argument, I'm going to put in an options object and here's where things are going to
get a little bit strange.
So just bear with me for right now.
Like I said, we're going to come back and go over all the code a lot more once we understand sort by
itself.
The first option we're going to put into the options object is capital G.
It gets.
This will be an array and we're going to put a couple of rather strange strings inside of here.
I'm going to put in a pound.
And then going to put in.
A template string.
So that is a back tick.
It is not a single quote, it is a back tick.
That's a character to the left of the one on your keyboard.
Inside if you're going to do a dollar sign.
Curly brace.
Items key.
Star.
Then right outside of the curly braces dash.
Greater than.
Name.
I'm then going to copy that down once and change name to views.
Now please, please, please triple check what you've got right here on these two lines.
These are two very tricky lines.
Just make sure you have the correct syntax.
After we've got that get in there.
I'm going to add on one or two more options I'll put in by.
Score.
And once again notice that by is all capitals.
All right, finally, I'm going to do it down here.
A console.log of results.
I'll save the file.
Then to test all this out, I'm going to go back over to my browser.
I'm going to refresh the landing page and then go back over to my terminal to see the console.log.
And now I get a result right here.
And the result is a little bit challenging to read, but let me kind of interpret it for you.
Inside of this array of strings, I've got the idea of an item, the title of an item, and the number
of views of the item.
And it looks like that order is repeating.
So I see it title views, i.e. title views, i.e. title views and so on.
Now, this is a little bit unexpected.
I shouldn't say unexpected.
It's totally unexpected.
But this is a kind of data that we've definitely not worked with before.
It's rather clear now that we are somehow working with a sorted set, but also simultaneously accessing
data that is stored inside of hashes.
So this is the sort command in action beyond just sorting data.
It also allows us to join together data from different sources into one single structure.
Okay.
So now that we've got this little bit of code put together, we do, of course, have to come back and
do some more implementation, like I mentioned.
But first, we're going to do a quick aside and get a much better understanding of the Sorte Command
because it is a tricky one.