All right, my friends, we made use of sorts, and some of the syntax in here looks really mysterious.
So let's do a quick aside, deep dive on the sort command.
We're going to leave our code editor for a little bit.
We're going to make use of our book again.
So I would encourage you to create another notebook.
I've already done so myself.
I've created a notebook called Simply Source.
All right.
A couple diagrams.
So all these videos are going to be about sorts.
And the reason we're going to spend so much time on this is that it's probably the trickiest command
to really understand in all of this.
I'm going to give you some reasons that it's really tricky, and I'm going to highlight all these difficulties
as we go through the command.
First thing to understand is that the sort command is used on three different data types sets, sorted
sets and lists.
We have not yet discussed lists.
We have spoken about sets and of course, sorted sets were kind of going over right now.
And one of the first things you might start to notice here is how in the world would be sought.
A sorted set is a sorted set is already sorted.
Well don't worry.
Will go into why we would sort a sorted set in great detail.
The two things I want to immediately call out and draw your attention to is that the sort command?
Just calling it sword is kind of misleading.
We do not always use the sort command for sorting data, and there's actually many other very good uses
of this sort command where no sorting is done whatsoever.
And that's what you and I are going to really focus on.
So I'll tell you exactly why we do not use salt for sorting.
The other thing I want you to be aware of is that there are a couple of terms that we use around the
sorting or the sorting command, and it turns out that the way we use these terms or these technical
terms actually conflict with other terms around data structures we have already learned.
So what I mean by that is in the world of sorted sets, we have learned that a score is paired up with
a member in a sorted set.
But in the world of the sort command, a score has a slightly different meaning, technically the same
meaning, but it refers to something different.
And again, I'll give you a very good example of this.
Now, the entire reason I'm showing this diagram right here and not just getting into the heart of what,
sir is, is to just help you understand that this really is a tricky command and there's a lot going
on with it.
All right.
So now.
Quick example, you're not going to really worry about the sort command just yet.
I just want to kind of point out some attributes or some things that go on in the world of sorting data
in general.
So I want to imagine that I've got a table like this right here, not stored in red is just written
out on paper or a spreadsheet or something like that.
My table has three columns, so I'd title and you're published.
Each of these rows represents a book.
So a book has an ID.
A book has a title.
And a book has a you're published.
Notice that the IDs in this case are good or bad in.
Okay.
Rather than a more traditional ID looking thing.
I've done that just to make looking at these ideas a little bit easier to understand and remember which
ID is tied with which book.
Now.
I got a little task for us.
Something I want to do with this data.
I want to try to list out the I.D. of each book.
And I want to sort those IDs based upon the year that the book was published.
Before we kind of go through that operation.
I really want to point out something very critical about this task that I've outlined.
We've really got two very different requests or two different pieces of data.
The first thing that we specified, I said we need to list out the idea of each book.
That is specifically the data that we are looking for.
We are looking for an output of just the idea of each book.
That is the output.
But then I also provided some sorting criteria, kind of like a score of sorts.
The sorting criteria is how we decide to sort each ID.
In this case, we are sorting by the year published.
What I also want to really highlight here is that our output is going to be just the sort of list of
ideas.
And even though we are sorting them by the year that they were published, the year publish is not included
in the results set.
The only thing included in this results set would be the list of ideas for each book.
Okay.
So let's kind of go through this in action.
Well, to get this kind of output right here, I would reorder perhaps each row to get them in the correct
order of your published.
So I see a 1930 right here in 1940.
In 1950, I think if I just pull down the 1950, now these things are all sorted based upon the year
published.
So they are correctly sorted.
I sorted based upon some criteria.
And now to get the final results.
Going to unlock these things really quickly.
Oh, come on.
There we go.
Now, to get the final result, I would extract just the ID from each row.
I did not do that one correctly.
Here we go.
All right, now we got it.
I would extract just the height of each row, and I end up with that.
Okay.
And good.
And just once again, this might seem like a very small thing, but I just really want to highlight
it.
My results set right here of bad.
Okay.
Good.
Does not include the criteria I used for sorting.
The criteria I use for sorting was a year published, but just because I used that criteria doesn't
mean that the sorting criteria is included in the results set.
Once again, this might seem like a very strange thing to highlight, but if you just really understand
this right away, it makes understanding the command a lot easier down the road.
Okay.
So now you've got this ring.
Take a quick pause and then we're going to go back over to our book in the next video and start playing
with the sort commands.