To better understand sports.
We are going to write out a little bit of data inside this first code cell right here.
We're going to set up three separate hashes and one sorted set will then make some sort to play with
all this data.
Here's a diagram of the data that we're going to set up.
In total, we have three separate hashes, like I mentioned.
Each one represents a single book.
So we've got a book with an idea of good, a book with an idea of bad and a book with an idea of OC.
Once again, I'm using good bad in OC as the IDs rather than numbers or something like that.
Just to make sure that the IDs are very easy for us to just look at and identify what that ID is referring
to.
We are also going to have a sorted set as well.
The sorted set will be stored at a key of books, likes and sorted set will have members of the idea
of each book and the number of likes that this book has received through imagining that I don't know,
we're making a book writing platform or something like that, but in this case, the book Bad has gotten
zero likes.
Nobody likes that book.
But 999 people liked the book.
All right.
Like I said, we're going to write out a couple of commands to get this structure set up inside of readies.
So Bakari here.
I'm going to do an H set of books good with the title of Good Book and a year of 1950.
I'm going to copy that down twice.
I'll change the second one right here.
Two books bad.
Bad book.
I'll make sure that is published in 1930.
And then on the third one, I'm going to change the ID to books.
Colin.
Okay.
Okay book.
Published in the year 1940.
Please double check your spelling on all these words and the capitalization as well.
If you have any typos in here, things are going to get a little bit strange later on.
Next up, we'll set up the sorted sets.
So I'll do a Z add on books likes.
Well, first, take care of the good book.
So that one has 999 likes and the member in this case is good.
And zero bad.
And 40.
Okay.
Once again, please double check your spelling and capitalization there.
Also, notice that all these prefixes are books.
So books.
Books, books, books.
Once you've double checked all that stuff, I'm going to run this thing and I'll get back to zero.
So presumably all the data is in here.
You might get one.
Actually, now that I think about it, I already had the sorted set created with these elements inside
of it before I recorded this video.
Okay.
So all the data is in here.
So now I'm going to add in another code self and as promised, we'll start making use of the sort command.
I'm going to write in sorts and remember what I told you in the last video.
The sort command operates on a sorted set, a set or a list.
We're not going to worry about list just yet, so we're only concerned with sorted sets and sets.
Let's do the kind of obvious thing.
Let's try to sort our sorted sets of books Colin likes and just see what happens.
I'll do books Colin likes.
And then going to run that.
And immediately, we're going to get our first very confusing error message.
Now, this is where in the last video I told you that some terminology around sort of conflicts with
other pieces of terminology we have already learned.
So there's a word in here that we've already seen somewhere else, and it means something completely
different than when we learned it previously.
So the ear says one or more scores can't be converted into double.
And the issue here is scores.
So what's going on?
Well, as usual, quick diagram.
All right, here is our sorted set.
Whenever we use the sort commands on a sorted set, sort is going to operate on the members of the sorted
sets, not the scores.
So we are currently operating on these members.
We are trying to sort these members in some way.
The reason we are seeing that error message is that all these members are listed out as strings and
sort by default expects to be working with numbers.
And that's kind of the error that we're seeing right now.
We're seeing something that says can't be converted into double double.
In other words, can't be converted into a number.
The reason that scores is so confusing here is that in the world of sorted sets, these over here,
these are our scores, our scores, our numbers.
But in the world of the sort commands, the members are referred to as scores.
They are sorting criteria.
They are sorting values.
Though, because it refers to these members as scorers.
It's in kind of direct competition with the terminology we learned when we were working assorted sets.
And so this is the first really confusing thing that we're going to run into.
So once again, as soon as we start making use of the Salk command in the sort world, when you apply
sort to a sort of set, members are scores.
I know it is confusing.
So we are seeing an error right now because it is trying to operate on these things and organize them
in some way.
By default tries to operate on numbers.
If we want to, we can apply an additional argument to the sort command.
Patel sought to try to organize these things, treating them as strings and so sort them alphabetically.
That's going to be the first variation of the sort command we're going to look at.
So back over here.
I'm going to put in sort books Colin likes and I'm going to add in Alpha.
So if we put in the alpha keyword, that means specifically sort all the members which again are referred
to as scores, but sort them alphabetically rather than treating them as numbers.
And if I run that journey now, if I end up with bad.
Good.
Okay.
Which is sorted alphabetically.
Well, let's add in another code.
So we're going to look at a second variation on sort now.
So I'm going to write out the same initial a little bit.
I'll do sorts looks likes alpha.
Now in this variation, I want to try to limit how many elements we get back.
Whenever we apply the sort keyword to a sorted set or a list, we might be sorting many, many, many
elements.
And the words are sorted.
Set might have a million elements inside of it.
And when we apply sort, we might not want to get back all million elements.
We might might want to get back just a couple.
So if we want to get back just a subset of the sorted results, we can make use of the limit argument.
Limit works just the same way as it does back when we were learning about the range.
So limit is going to take in two numbers.
The first number is going to be a number of elements we want to skip in the result set.
And the second will be how many we want to include.
So if I put in one space two, that means skip over the first element of bad and then give me the next
two.
I can run that and sure enough, I get good and okay.
If I put in one one, that means skip over bad and then give me just one element.
So that would be good.
And then finally, as you probably guessed, I did zero one.
Don't skip over any and give me just one.
So that would be just bad.
I'm going to leave that as one to you.
All right.
So there is a basics of sort around sorted sets.
We've learned about two variations.
So we got sorts our sorted set key and an alpha that causes all the members to be sorted alphabetically.
And we've also seen limits that just hair's back.
How many elements get returned at this point?
This doesn't look too bad, with the exception of understanding that we are sorting the members, not
the scores or anything like that.
Let's take a pause here and we're going start to dive into the more interesting aspects of sort.
In just a moment.