Or this next variation of the sort command.
We're going to try to answer this question I put up here just a little bit ago.
So here's our three books.
This is the exact same data that we just loaded into this.
I want to list out the ID of each book and I want to sort those IDs by the year published.
So in theory, I should get back something like that.
Okay, good.
That should be our ultimate answer.
Okay.
So to actually write this stuff out, I just want to have you recall very quickly here what I made a
huge point up just a little bit ago.
There is a very big difference between the data we are looking for and the sort of criteria.
Let's keep that in mind for a moment now.
I'm going to go back over I'm going to add in a new cell right here.
I'm going to write out the full command to get all the different IDs sorted by year, and we'll take
a look at a couple of diagrams to understand how this command works.
All right.
Here goes.
So it looks like.
And then here's our new argument.
I.
Well then put in books.
Poland Star.
Dash greater than year.
And that's it.
And if I run that, I get bad.
Okay, good.
Now, I just want to make sure that is correct.
That should be the IDs listed in order of year.
So the correct answer was on this diagram right here.
Bad.
Okay, good.
First year of 1930.
40, 50?
Yep.
Looks like we got the right answer.
The now obvious question here is what's going on with this syntax and what's going on with the by keyword?
Well, like I said, this is one that trickier aspects of this sort command.
So let's break down what's going on behind the scenes, step by step.
Okay.
So we're going to walk through what is going on step by step.
And I've got what's going on in each step on the bottom right hand side.
So step number one, we're going to extract all the members from the sorted set that we are attempting
to apply this sort command to.
So in our case, we are extracting all the members from books colon likes.
So I'm going to delete everything yond just those members because this is the data that we are immediately
working on.
Step one.
Then step number two.
We're going to take each of these different numbers and we're going to insert them into this template
in place of the star.
We're then going to look at the entire results.
And if that results in a field on a hash, we're going to retrieve that field.
So it's going to walk through this step by step.
Here we go.
So we're going to look through each member.
So we start off with bat.
We're going to take that.
We're going to put it into this template right here in place of the star.
So I end up with books coal and Bad Arrow Year.
Everything before the little arrow right there is treated as a key.
So Redis is going to automatically look up inside of all the different structures that it has.
It's going to try to find a key of books, coal and bat.
And sure enough, it finds that key right here.
And stored at that key is a hash.
The little arrow right here means on the hash that is found at books calling bad.
See if that hash has a field of year.
And sure enough, it does.
It's got year of 1930.
The Reds is going to extract that value right there and use that as the sorting criteria for bad.
We're then going to repeat that same process for okay and good.
Four.
Okay, once again, we're going to replace the star with OC.
We're going to find a key of books.
Colin okay.
There it is right there.
Look at the house.
Does it have a field of year?
Yes, it does.
We'll extract that value and associate that with.
Okay.
And then, as you can guess, same process is repeated for books.
Colin Good.
All right.
So now we've got this structure right here.
This is the net result of step number two.
Now we're going move on to step number three.
And step number three, we're going to take a look at each member.
So the members are on the left and we're going to sort those based upon the by field.
And the by field is the numbers on the right.
Well, turns out that in this particular case, with the way I structured everything, it turns out
it's already in order.
So we've already got these numbers.
They're already in the correct order.
Pretty much everything is good to go as it stands right here.
But if they were for some reason in a different order, if we had say.
27 up here at the top.
Well, then that would be moved to the bottom like so.
But that's not the case.
Now on to Stettner for an Stettner four.
We're going to discard the sorting criteria and return only the members.
So we discard all those years and we return just these IDs right here of bad.
Okay.
And good.
And so this is exactly what I spoke to you just a little bit ago about this idea of.
Data we are looking for versus these sorting criteria.
In this case, our sorting criteria was the year, but we were not using that as the reporting reported
results.
It was all in the sorting criteria.
Once we use that data, we threw it away entirely.
Now, once again, I repeat, this might seem like I'm making a huge deal out of this, but trust me,
just pointing this out very early, it makes understanding it a lot easier.
Otherwise, you end up saying, wait, where did the year go?
We specified the year.
Why am I not seeing an output of the year though?
It just makes it a little bit easier to understand.
Okay.
And that is, of course, the result we saw over here.
So these are IDs and those ideas are sorted based upon your.
All right.
So now we understand this variation.
We're going to look at one more variation in the next video that builds upon this idea of by.