All right.
Here's the last variation on sorts.
This is where things really get interesting.
This is where sorting is not really like sorting.
It's more like a general purpose command to kind of join together different sources of data in readies.
In this example, we're going to imagine a very similar problem, but with a little bit of a twist.
So this time around, I want to list out the title of each book sorted by the year published.
Now, at first glance, as we look at this table right here, that sounds just trivially easy, super
easy.
I mean, we can just look at this thing, say that's already sorted by year published, we would just
take bad book.
Okay, good.
And that's pretty much it.
But implementing this with Redis in one single command, little bit more challenging.
Remember, this is the data we have access to in Redis.
So we've got our hashes over here.
We got this sorted, set over here.
We need to somehow look up these IDs.
We need to somehow sort the IDs based upon these years.
But then instead of returning these IDs, we need to return some data from the hashes.
Over here on the left hand side.
So good book.
Bad book.
An okay book.
So as usual, we're going to write out the command to solve this and we'll walk through how it works
step by step.
It's the back of a hearing, an ad in another code cell.
And this time around we will do a sorts books likes.
We will still sort by book's Colon Star era year.
But then I'm going to also add on one additional argument of get.
Books.
Colin.
Star Arrow.
Title.
Yeah, I'm going to run that and I get my titles and in theory they are sorted in order of year published
so bad.
Okay.
Good.
All winds up with the result we got last time.
So yeah.
I'd say that this is probably correct.
Let's now take a look at a couple of different diagrams.
You know, just understand how this thing is working.
Well, once again, the first step or two are going to look very similar to what we went through a little
bit ago.
We're going to first take a look at the assorted set that we're trying to sort.
We're going to extract all the members.
So we're going to take the members of BAT.
Okay.
And good.
And I'm going to just delete everything else just for the sake of keeping this diagram simple.
Then in step number two, we're going to do the exact same thing as before.
We're going to loop through each individual member.
We're going to insert the member into this by template.
And then if this result right here points at a hash, we will extract that field and add it up here
at the top right hand side.
So we put in a bad and result in books.
Bad year.
So that would give me right here the 1930.
So 1930 right there.
Same thing for.
Okay.
Same thing for good.
So the buy is specifying our sorting criteria.
Then on Staten or three is where things get a little bit different.
So step number three, we're going to repeat that same thing we did with PHI, but now we're going to
use the template that was provided to the Get argument.
So we put in to the get argument a template of books.
Poland Star Title.
We're going to look through each member starting off with bat.
I'm going to insert that in place of the star.
Look at this key.
Points to this hash.
I'm going to look up whatever is on the right hand side of the arrow.
So it's title.
There's bad book right there.
So I'm going to take that value and I'm going to put it now on the left hand side of this diagram.
Now I've got this kind of association of bad with bad book and the sorting criteria.
This little pair right here is 1930.
Well, then repeat the same process for the other two members.
So this would go to books.
Okay.
There's the key look up title.
There's Oak Book.
Put it right there.
And then it's same thing for.
So book's good.
There's the title and put it right there.
All right, so now I've got these pairs.
On the left hand side of some amount of data.
And on the right hand side is these sorting criteria.
On to step number four.
Same thing as before.
We're going to sort each member based on the by field and those are the things on the right hand side.
Once again, values are already sorted.
I know I probably should have jumbled the data, but totally fine.
Actually works out better for something else we're going work on later on.
So do the sorting.
Already sorted?
Totally fine.
Move on to Stanton or for you're only going to return the fields specified in the GET template.
The Get template gave us these titles right here, so we would drop off the sorting criteria.
We would drop off those members because they were not specified in the GET template and we are left
with just that.
Okay.
And good book.
And that's how it works.
Okay.
So that's kind of the last big variation on sorts.
But there are a couple of other little odds and ends that you need to understand, particularly around
Git itself.
The first thing I want to point out is that we can apply the get cured multiple times to a single sort
command.
Let me show you an example that very quickly, I'm going to put a new line right before we get and then
tap this thing in.
Now, if you do the same thing to reformat this, make sure you put in a tab right there as well.
If you put in, just get like.
So these will be interpreted as two separate commands.
So now I'm doing a sort with one get operation right here and I'm going to add in a second get operation.
In the second get operation.
I'm going to Books Star.
But this time I'm going to try to look up the year.
So now do the same sorting operation.
But in addition to telling you the title of each book, I also want to know the year of each book.
So I'll run that and we get a results.
Formatted as the title and then the year title year.
Title the year.
So again, we can put in as many of these gifts as we want.
Another little variation on here.
We might want to get the title and the year, but also understand the idea of this book as well.
So I have the title and the year, but what is the idea of this thing?
Well, for that one last little piece of syntax here, I'm going to put in another gift and then a pound.
Pound means insert whatever the original member was.
So in our case, the member.
Was bad.
Okay.
And good.
The pound means keep this thing around.
Keep bad.
Okay.
And good around though in Stettner for as we are returning only the fields specified get we delete the
sorting criteria and we are left with the original member plus title and then plus technically right
now we've also added on the year as well.
Be something like this.
Now if I run that, I end up with the ID, the title and the year.
There is one other thing I want to point out around sorts.
We are not required to use the by keyword right here if we don't actually want to do any sorting operation.
So remember in our example with the data we are working with.
I had specifically said that I want to print out some information around each book sorted by some specific
criteria.
There might be some scenarios where you just want to use this kind of joining together feature of the
sort command without doing any explicit sort operation.
In addition, you might just want to rely upon however the data is naturally sorted inside of your sorted
sets.
So books like right here, these members are already sorted on the number of likes that each book has.
So there's already an implicit sorting order here to the members themselves.
So if you specifically do not want to do any additional sorting, if you just want to rely upon whatever
order the members are inside the sorted set, you can replace that little part right there at the by
with no sorts.
No sort is a special keyword.
That means don't do any sorting operation.
Just take a look at the order of members inside of the sorted set and do the data joining operation
without applying any additional sorting stuff to it.
So if I run this variation.
I'll end up with bad okay and good, which again is just the order in which they occur inside of that
sordid set.
By adding on the buy no sorts, you are implicitly going to make the sorting command go a little bit
faster because it says, okay, I don't have to worry about even remotely thinking about doing a true
sorting operation.
So again, if you're just using sort to do this joining stuff as we're doing at the get, then I do
recommend adding on the buy statement.
All right.
So that's it for sport for right now.
So I think that we have got a little bit more information on what's going on with this code over here,
with the exception of some stuff around like by score and whatnot, but good enough to go back over
to the code and figure out what's going on with this line and complete items by views.
So let's take care of that in just a moment.