At the end of the last video, I mentioned that we could put in a buy no sort right here, and that
will cause sorting to be disabled, which saves us a little bit of processing power.
I just want to clarify that a little bit.
Putting in a buy no store is a little bit of a convention.
If you put in any key right here that does not exist inside of your hashes or inside your app in general,
then sorting will be disabled so you can put in by those sorts.
You can also put in something like that, and it's going to also skip the sorting operation because
this key presumably does not exist.
That is also why back inside of our project.
So right here I put in sort by score.
We don't have a key called score.
And because that key does not exist, we are essentially disabling all sorting on the sort call that
we're doing right here.
Okay.
So now that we cleared that up, just one or two other quick things on go over back on items by views.
I just want make sure that it is now crystal clear what is going on with our overall command.
So just once again, very quick diagram.
We're going to walk through this entire process, very abbreviated.
So we are taking a look at our items, views, sorted, sets.
All the IDs inside of here are already sorted by the number of views.
So we don't need to do any additional sorting whatsoever, no additional sorting required, which is
why I put in score right here.
We could have also put in no sorts just to say don't do any sorting as everything is already sorted
for us.
So we're going to extract those IDs.
We are then going to apply those jet templates that we listed in this array.
So the first part of the jet template, the first entry you have inside of here is LB, which means
give us the underlying ID, give us the idea of this element.
And then after that, we got this kind of crazy syntax.
All this does right here, as crazy as it looks.
I'm just using the items key function and putting in star right there.
The result of which is we're going to end up with something that looks like items around Star.
So that is going to resolve to some items.
Harsh.
We're then going to look up the name property on it.
So again, I'm just using our items for our key function for entering this key right here just to stick
with that same convention of using our key functions in general to avoid typos.
So we're going to try to retrieve the name and views of the items.
So you can imagine that for the member at year six, we go and find this thing right here in our application.
It technically has a pound.
No big difference.
We're going to get the name of that thing and the number of views.
Well, then repeat that for the next element.
So, chair.
And views.
And then table.
So that is the entire set of values that we are trying to return.
So all these things will be turned into strings and then sent back to us.
And that is really the console.log we saw a little bit ago when we tested out our code.
Now there are a couple of other very small considerations.
Some ways in which we need to update this function that we definitely need to be aware of.
First off, because we were relying upon the default sort order of our sorted set, right now we are
getting back all these results sorted in terms of the items that have the least views to the greatest,
because that is once again how our sorted set is sorted.
It's going from the least number of views up to the greatest.
The entire goal of the function we are working on right now is to see the items with the most views.
So when we get this kind of net result right here, we don't really want it in this order.
We want it to be sorted in this way, but we want to flip the ordering.
So at the very top I really want to see the item that has the most views and then I want to see the
item with the second most views, and then the least views should be at the bottom.
So I want to keep the same sorting criteria.
I still want to use the score over here as the sorting criteria, but I want to flip the order entirely.
To flip the order or essentially is what the entire result set, we can put on one additional keyword
to our sort commands.
So just a quick example.
Back over here right after this buy right here, we can put in a sending AC for short or DC descending.
So go from greatest down to least.
So in this case, if I do a descending, I'm not going to get the greatest values first going down to
the lowest values.
So 1950, 1940.
1930.
Okay.
So that's what we need to do here as well.
We want to get our items sorted, sorted from the ones that have the most views down to the least.
Now.
Fortunately, our function already accepts a argument called order that's going to tell us whether we
should run this query or this command with descending or ascending.
All we can do is really make use of this order arguments.
So to customize our sort commands without order argument.
Right after by I'm going to add in direction with order.
So now whenever items by views is called, the other part of the application that calls this thing is
almost always going to put in a descending string.
We're going to run this entire sort of operation and get everything sorted in descending order.
And then the last very small change we're going to make.
One of the other arguments to this are offsets and count just to make sure we don't get back a ton of
items here.
So by default, we're going to get the first couple of items and only ten of them.
Let's just make sure we make use of those arguments.
So we can limit how many elements we get back by putting the limit option with offset and count.
And that should be it.
Okay.
So we went over a couple of things here.
First, just clarify the Byfield.
We understand what it is doing here with these kind of weird little bits of syntax.
We understand that direction is controlling the order of results.
It doesn't change the criteria, just the ordering and then limits.
Once again, we're just making sure we don't get back a ton of different items.
Last thing on do very quickly is just test this out with the updates we just made.
In particular, I want to go and create a brand new item inside of our application.
I then want to give that item a couple of different views.
So we're just going to go to its product page and refresh the product page a couple of times, and then
we will try to rerun this function and just make sure that our results look like they make sense.
So make sure that the items with the most views appear on top.
So let's do that test very quickly.
Get started back inside my browser.
I'm going to go and make a new item.
I'm going to call this new item.
How about something like new?
This chair?
I'll have it be alive for 10 minutes.
And then once on this page, I'm going to refresh this a couple of different times just so it gets a
bunch of views.
So I'm refreshing, refresh and refreshing tons of refreshes right now.
I'm just hitting refresh, refresh.
Then once I've added a couple of views, I can go back to the main landing page.
Then once we go there, this console.log should have fired.
So we go to our terminal and check out the console.log.
We should see now at the very top newest chair with 27 views, and then everything after that should
have less views, as I see 27 and then eight.
And then one, one, one and one.
Okay.
So I'd say that this looks pretty good.
So we've now got a pretty good solution here.
Using sorts, we are issuing one single command and getting back this kind of merged data.
We're taking multiple different structures in Redis and throwing it all together into some useful results.
And we're not even really doing any sorting whatsoever for flipping the order of something.
But is that a sort of I don't know.
I wouldn't really call it a sort.
All right, so this looks good.
But there's still one last thing we need to do.
We are currently getting back an array of strings.
We are supposed to be returning a bunch of serialized item objects.
So what we have right now, this array of strings not useful to us.
We need to take all these strings and turn them into an array of objects.
That's one last challenging thing we'll take care of in just a moment.