There is one last thing we need to do around our items by use function.
Remember, right now, when we get this results variable and we console.log it, we have just a big
array of strings and that's not very useful to the rest of our application, the rest of our app.
So whatever parts of our app calls this function, expect to get back an array of item objects.
But we just have this array of plain strings right now.
So we need to take this array of plain strings and parse each little group.
So each collection of those three strings and then these three and then those three right there into
separate item objects.
So the rest of our server can make use of all these items.
So we are going to pretty much take the first three parts of them into this first object with an ID,
a name.
And number of views and then repeat the same process for the next three strings.
So 18 share in six, seven, nine.
And then the next three strings.
And so.
The other thing I want you to be aware of.
We also need to return a couple of properties beyond just the name and views.
So the part of our application that is relying upon this array of item objects, that is the homepage
specifically right here.
So this section right here, it also needs to know the image URL for each product.
The number of the user has the ending at time, the price and so on.
So beyond just the three strings, we are currently getting out using the get operation.
We need a couple additional properties as well.
Now all this parsing stuff we are about to do is really just a lot of JavaScript specific stuff.
So now that we understand the kind of big issue here, the actual implementation, we're going to speed
through rather quickly because again, I'm not really focusing on the JavaScript side of things inside
of this course.
So let's just get to the actual implementation.
Well, they get started at the very top.
I'm going to import these.
Realize.
From same directory de serialize.
We're going to use that function to eventually take these grouping of strings and turn them into item
objects.
Next up, I'm going to make a little update right here.
I'm going to say let's results and I'm going to annotate results as type any.
The reason I'm using it right here, you'll see in just a bit.
It's related to how we're going to do the actual item parsing.
Next, I'm going to remove the console.log results.
I'm going to create a new array called items.
And then we're going to loop through.
All of our results.
So remember, results is the big array of strings.
So I'm going to say, as long as there are any strings inside there, I'm going to continue rehearsing
through.
Then at the top of our while loop.
I'm going to do a little bit of restructuring on results.
I'm going to try to pull off each successive grouping of strings.
So the ID.
The name and the number of views.
And then the rest of the elements inside that array.
I will then create my item object by serializing.
I'd.
Name the use like so.
Notice I've got curly braces around name and views.
So this is my last item right here.
I'm going to take that last item and add it into my array of items.
So items, push item.
And I'm going to update the results variable to be just the rest of all these strings.
They will say rest or be results is rest.
There we go.
And then finally, after a while loop, I will return items.
Just in case you're curious and you're not quite following the code here, I'm creating the second array
that's going to store the big list of items and then eventually returning it.
And the goal of this while loop is to take this big collection of strings.
Chunk off the first three.
Turn them into an item object and then chunk off the next three.
Turn off them into an item object and then chunk off the last three.
And as soon as there are no more strings available inside that array, well, that means we must have
parsed all these strings into items.
And so we're all done.
We can return.
So that's the general idea with this block right here.
Now I am going to test this out very quickly.
I going back over.
So I've got now most views and I can see my different items.
So I see the same number of views.
And that's pretty much it right now.
I see a lot of error data.
Obviously a lot of bad data inside of your is just because we are, like I said, not retrieving all
the data we need during that joint operation.
We need to also get the price of the item.
You need to get the ending at time and so on.
So for that, we need to make a couple of very small updates.
First we're going to.
Pull out a couple more properties beyond just the ID name and boots.
So in addition to those three properties, I'm going to also get out.
The ending at time.
The image u.
R.
L.
And the price of the item.
By adding in these additional jet fields right here.
This just means that the results that we get back out of the entire SALT operation are going to be that
much larger.
So before for every single item, we got back three strings, got the idea, name and views.
Now we're going to get a total of six strings.
So I.D. name views ending at image URL and price.
So we need to make sure we also update the passing logic down here as well.
So in addition to its name and views, we're also going to get ending at image URL and price.
And we need to make sure that we include those on the DC realize step.
And that should be it.
So I'm going to save all this.
Look back over one more time and there's most views and sure enough, it all looks pretty good.
So I see the titles.
I see the correct ending at time.
The number of use prices is showing up correctly.
We don't only have the ability to change price just yet, but data's definitely there and I've definitely
got an appropriate number of items showing up.
Now I just want to repeat, I know I went through all this JavaScript stuff rather quickly just because
we're not quite so much focused on the JavaScript side.
Well, that's it.
I think this looks good.
In closing around all this relational stuff.
Remember, the entire point of all this was to take a look at different ways of handling relational
data.
It is right here.
So we did the two requests method with a pipeline with all the kettles, and we did one with a sort.
Obviously we have two requests up here.
One request down here.
But the tradeoff is doing this sort of operation is just a lot more code on our side.
So making use of sorts.
We then also have to list out each individual field we want to get.
And we also have to do this kind of annoying parsing step right here.
So it's really up to you which method you want to go with.
Without a doubt.
Doing the skit all's.
Absolutely easier.
Definitely easier.
But doing this sort of operation, it's probably going to be more performant because you only have to
make the one single request after edits as opposed to two.
So really up to you which one you want to go with for just about everywhere else in the application,
wherever we need some relational data, I think we're going to end up splitting the difference.
So sometimes we'll do a sort.
Sometimes we'll do a pipeline of each get calls, and we'll just decide which method we want to use
on the fly.
All right.
So that's it on relational data.
For right now, we are going to touch on a subject or that later on.
For right now, I think this is probably good.