At this point, we've been looking at storing planes, strings and numbers inside of readies.
As you see right here, it's a color red.
We're not going to move on to our next data structure, which is a hash hash allows us to store a collection
of nested key value pairs inside Redis.
So at a key of company, we might have a hash data structure.
This is the hash over here on the right hand side.
You can think of this once again as like a nested key value structure.
So we might have a key of name, the value of concrete code.
Read it out.
1915 Industry of concrete.
The most common use case of hashes is to store information about particular records or entities inside
of your application.
So you might have a hash that stores information about a particular user, a hash that stores information
about a particular post or a house that stores information about a particular image.
By far the most common use case.
But there are, of course, many other use cases as well.
One thing to be aware of around these hashes is that they are not allowed for us to have nested or deeply
nested evaluators.
You can really think of our hash data structure as being like something like this right here, a JSON
object.
We have a collection of key value pairs where the values can be numbers or strings.
We are not allowed to have deeply nested structures, as you see in this case right here.
The deeply nested nested aspect would be industry with a sub object of primary and secondary.
We also cannot have arrays inside of your as well as you see in this example.
Again, a hash value pairs where the values are only strings, only numbers.
Now there are a tremendous number of commands that we can take a look at around houses.
I shouldn't say tremendous, but a reasonable number.
A lot of these are going to be very similar to the commands we already went over for numbers and strings.
So it should not take very long.
Let's get started in a new our books cloud notebook.
In the next video, we're going to start taking a look at some of these different commands and how they
work.