Let's take a look at a couple of basic commands around houses.
We're going to first look at the commands that we use to create and retrieve data from a house.
Those are H sets.
H, get an H, get all.
In general, these commands are very similar to the string equivalent commands of jets and set.
All right.
To take a look at these commands, we are going to use Arbuckle out again.
So at Arbuckle Out, I've already created a new notebook called Hashes.
The first command that we're going to take a look at is the H set command.
And this is what we use to create and store a hash inside of Redis.
When we call each set, the first argument is going to be the name of the key.
Inside of red is where we want to store the hash data structure.
So if we did something like each set and then company, that means that inside of red is we're going
to create a new hash structure at a key of company.
Then immediately after that first argument, we are going to alternate E value, key and value.
So we put in name company CO and age 1915.
We would end up with a structure like this right here.
I've got a key of name and a value of concrete.
Go.
Then a key of age up there be age right there and a value of 1915.
Okay.
Let's give this a shot.
Back over in our book, I will do an H set.
Company.
Name of concrete co.
And age or creative, that doesn't really matter.
I'll put in 1915 in this case.
Then if I run that, I'm going to get back rather than the OC that we had seen previously.
When we were setting a plane string or a plane number, we instead get a number of two.
That is meant to indicate that we have updated two key value pairs in this case, name and age.
That's pretty much it or h set.
Now just be clear.
You can add on as many key value pairs as you want.
So I can add in in addition to just name and age.
Something like industry.
Concrete or about materials.
Maybe then another field of revenue and have that be something like, say, 5.3.
Now I would expect to get back a value of two in this case because although we have set four different
key value pairs, we have only added in or really made two additional updates to our hash.
If I run this command a third time, I'll get back zero because we have not made any additional updates
to the hash.
Okay.
So that's how we can store value or store a hash inside of Redis.
Now, let's take a look at the other two commands very quickly, each git, which allows us to get a
single field from a hash.
Let's make a quick example of that.
I'll do an H, get on company and I'll try to get the field name.
This will give me back concrete co.
I could just as well do something like say revenue.
Get back 5.3.
The other canard that we used to retrieve data from a hash is h get all this is going to give us all
the different key value pairs that are stored inside of a hash.
So if we do a.
Each get all of company.
There we go.
So there is our entire hash right there.
But one thing to be aware of is that if I click on this little paint icon right here on the right hand
side, that will cause the raw response to come back from red.
So the raw response to be printed out right here.
What you see currently, what looks like an object, that is our book, Taking Back the return value
and formatted it nicely for you in this kind of object structure.
But what actually gets returned from Redis is an array of values.
And this array that you get back, we get the key.
And then a value key value, key value key value in some is clients that you're going to use for your
particular programming language.
They will give you back an array like this and you might have to manually take these different key value
errors and assemble them into an object other right.
As clients such as the node readies client that we're using inside of our e-commerce application is
going to take that response and automatically form it for you into an object that just a very small
thing to be aware of some right as clients you might get back response.
That's not quite expected, but it does have all the correct data inside of it.
This requires you to go through one additional step.
Okay.
So not the worst commands here.
Hashes are one of the easiest data structures we're going to take a look at.
Let's continue on in the next video.
We're going to get through a couple more commands very quickly because in general, these are all rather
straightforward in nature.