Let's take a look at some very basic commands or in hashes that allow us to create or retrieve data
from a house.
These are each that H gets an H.
Get all H set and H gets are very similar to the very basic set and get commands that we used in the
previous videos when we were working with plain strings.
So sets allows us to store or update a hash each get and each get all allow us to retrieve information
from a hash.
Let's first take a look at each set and how it behaves.
Okay.
So we use each set any time we want to store a hash or to create one or any time we want to update a
hash.
The first argument to it is going to be the name of the hash or really the key inside of red is where
we want to store our house.
So if we run a command of H set company inside of red is a new key will be created of company and it's
going to refer to a hash data structure.
Immediately after that first argument we're going to list out in alternating order our keys and our
values to store inside that house.
If I put in a key of name and a value of company CO, I will end up with a name and a value of that
should be company.
Go right there.
Why then list out age 1915?
That's going to make a key of age with a value of 1915.
Whenever we run the H that command, we are going to get back a number in response.
And this number represents the number of fields that we created inside the hash that we are trying to
modify or update.
All right, let's go back over to Arbuckle.
Out.
I've already created a new notebook called Hashes.
We're going to try out that each set command very quickly.
Inside of a code cell right here.
I went to run h sets company.
But the name of concrete co and an age of 1915.
When I run this, I'm going to get back to you, which indicates that two yields have been created.
If I run the command a second time, I get back to zero because I have created zero additional fields.
We can also use the h that command to update data inside of an existing hash as well.
So for example, I might want to change the name and the age of this particular hash so I might change
the name to something like.
Fancy concretes.
Maybe this company was created in 1950.
If I can run that, you'll notice I once again get zero because I created a zero additional key value
pairs here.
But I did make an update to some existing fields.
I just don't really see that reflected inside the response.
Now each set is only for storing or updating a hash in order to retrieve information from how much hash
we're going to use.
H get or h get all.
The command allows us to get a single key value pair from a hash.
We might run something like H, get a company name and that would give us the the value at name for
our particular company.
Let's try that out very quickly.
So H gets company name and I would expect to get back fancy concrete and sure enough, I do.
And then each get all allows us to get all the key value pairs from a hash.
In this case, we don't list out any keys inside the hash.
We just say the entire hash right here.
So where our hash is stored inside of red itself.
We'll try that out very quickly.
It's get all.
Company.
And there we go.
I get back my name and age.
All right.
So like I said, pretty basic, straightforward commands when it comes to storing hashes, updating
hashes and retrieving information from them.
So we'll use each set any time we want to create or update, we will use each get anytime we want to
get a single field and each get all any time.
We want to retrieve the entire hash.
Now a couple more commands for us to go over.
All the other ones we're going to look at are going to be pretty basic as well.
Not the worst things in the world.
I bet by just looking at the names of these different commands, you can kind of guess what they're
going to do for us.
So let's start to dive into these other commands in just a moment.