Three more very quick commands.
First off, each exists.
This allows us to check and see if a key is defined inside of an existing house.
So for example, we might run h exists company age.
That means go and find the hash stored at company that would give us this entire house right here and
then see if the age key is defined inside there.
In this case, age is defined inside that hash.
So our command would return one.
If age did not exist for some reason, then we would get back zero.
One thing to be aware of is that US is not checking for the truthiness of the value stored here.
So age might refer to empty string or zero or false or otherwise.
Some all see value.
If a false value is stored there.
You are still going to get back one because it is only looking for the existence of that key.
Now let's try out the h exist command very quickly.
Very simple one.
So h.
Exists company with age.
And sure enough, we get one.
We try to look up a key that does not exist inside this ash.
We'll get back to zero.
Okay.
Next up is the Dell Command.
This works identical to when we used it around strings so we can use Del to delete an entire hash that
is stored at a particular key.
But once again, very simple usage here.
Dell Company.
We'll just delete the entire hash stored there.
Now, that hash no longer exists.
If I try to do something like a h get all company, I will end up with an error.
Or in this case, excuse me, an empty response right there, because we no longer have any data stored
there.
And then finally with this video each though this allows us to delete one single key value pair that
is stored inside of a hash for each cell we can look up, say company once again and delete just the
age key value pair.
So in this case, we would find our hash late age and that's pretty much it.
Once again, very quick demonstration.
I'm going to first redefine.
My company has hash by rerunning this command up here.
Then down at the bottom, I'll get another code cell.
You HDL company.
And age.
Now if I do an H get all of company going to get back.
Just name.
No longer do I have any age.
Okay.
So once again, pretty basic commands.
We're going to get through all the rest of these commands in the next video.
Just kind of knock them all out in one go.
Should be pretty quick.