Once again, a couple of different commands very quickly.
First is H anchor by and H anchor by float.
These two commands allow us to add either an integer or a float to an existing number inside of a hash.
So if we do h anchor by company age ten, that means find the hash story company, find the field called
age and add ten to it.
So I would end up with 1925.
Its anchor by float allows us to add a float value.
So again, find your hash stored at company.
Find the key by pair of age and add 1.00 Ford to it.
So what I would end up with?
1916 004.
Now if you are attempting to call H or buy on a key that does not exist inside of a house, then that
key will be created for you.
So for example, if we did an h inker by revenue with ten, the revenue key does not exist inside this
house.
So a new key will be created for you automatically of revenue.
Its value will be set to ten.
Lastly, little bit of a trick.
You'll notice that this says H anchor, which means increase or increment.
But we can just as easily supply a negative value right here if we actually want to subtract from an
existing number.
So if I put in, say, -15 and ran that against age right here, I would end up with 19.
Okay, as usual, will test this out very quickly because very similar to the string command of anchor
and anchor by.
I'll do an H.
Anchor by on company age with ten.
I'll then do a.
Right after that.
Each gets all on company.
And oh yeah, I deleted age just a moment ago in the last video.
So I've got just ten right here.
I can go up to the very top of this notebook and reset my company hash.
Here it is right here.
Okay, that's better.
And now if I do an H anchor by ten again, I'll get that 1960 and I can see that very easily right there.
Now also do an h incur by float.
Like.
So now when I run the cell, I'm going to add another ten and then add on a 1.001.
So end up with something like 19 70.001 or 1970 1001.
There we go.
And there we go.
It's simple enough.
On to h string length.
This allows us to get the length of a string stored inside the house.
This is definitely another one of those commands where you kind of have to wonder, when am I going
to use this?
I remember when we looked at strings previously there were many commands like that and we kind of had
to figure out clever uses for them.
So when are you going to get the length of a string inside the house?
Probably not super often, but it's one of those commands you can use to kind of twist Reddit's just
a little bit to service something in a kind of a more clever fashion.
If we do h string length.
Look at company.
Find the name of a pair.
Just give me that length of that string right there.
We'll try that out very quickly.
H string length company name.
And so that string has 14 characters inside of it.
Okay.
One last set here.
Each key is and its values.
Get all the keys out of a hash and get all the values out of a hash.
We can do a h ease of company and we'll get back just the name and age.
We can also do an h values to me h vowels.
And get back to fancy concrete and the newly updated 1970 1.001.
Okay.
So these commands are we're looking at inside this video in particular.
Yes.
Once again, you're probably not going to use these terribly often unless you're doing something really
clever with Redis.
Nonetheless, you are going to see code every now and then that makes use of these commands.
So it is good to just know that they exist, especially since it only takes a moment or two in this
course for me to mention them.
Very quickly to you.
Now we've got them in a notebook, so you can always refer back to them in the future.
All right.
Well, believe it or not, that's pretty much all the commands that you need to understand around houses.
But there are many, many uses of houses, and that's where things start to get very interesting.
Now, now that we understand the basic commands and some limitations, we can start to look at when
we would use these houses to store information.
We can start to get some practical examples inside of our e-commerce example as well.