As I've hinted at several times, we are going to revisit the idea of concurrency inside of our application.
We have previously put together some work around concurrency.
Notably, we made use of transactions and that Watch Command solve a couple of problems around our bidding
process.
But in this video, I'm going to show you a couple of issues with using that watch command, and I'm
going to show you those issues in action as well.
We're then going to learn a little bit more about concurrency and eventually use a loose script to put
together a slightly better solution to our concurrency problem.
Okay, so let's get to it.
First, very fast reminder on the issue we previously had.
We've got some logic inside of our app to create a bid on an item, and as a part of that process,
we attempt to get an item hash.
We then take a look at the amount of money currently bid on that item.
We compare that against the amount of money that's being bid and the incoming request.
And as long as that is greater than that amount right there, then this person now has the winning bid.
We'll update that amount and update the hash back inside of this.
That'll work just fine.
But we very quickly saw that there were some issues any time that we have multiple bids coming in at
the same time for the same item.
So in this scenario, I've got a bid for $10 and a bid for 15.
So my server's going to try to process both these requests at the same time.
At the same time, they're both going to try to get the Item House, so they're both going to get a
copy of the item hash where the current bid is only $5.
They're both then going to take a look at the current amounts and compare against the amount in the
incoming request.
In both cases, these are valid bids.
So maybe we try to process or resolve this request right here first.
We're going to take that 15 right there and save that 15 as the most recent bid on the item.
That request is now complete.
And then simultaneously somewhere else on the server, we have another line of execution right here
where we are trying to take a look at a bid amount of ten.
In this case, our server thinks that the current bid amount is five.
So this is considered to be a valid bid.
We go and update our hash over here and we go backwards.
We go down to $10 where it was previously 15.
We are implementing an auction platform, the most recent highest value, which should always be the
winner.
We're now seeing a scenario where we are accidentally decreasing the current amount of money being bid
on this item.
That's definitely something we do not want to have happen.
Yes, that was the issue.
Now, as a reminder on how we fixed it, we made use of a watch command along with a transaction.
Let's go find the code for that very quickly.
The back inside my editor, I will find services, queries, bids.
Yes.
And here it is right here.
At the group ID function, we created a new connection to our Reddit server.
We then did a watch on the Item House.
Remember what a watch does?
The watch statement is going to watch a particular key stored inside of us, and if that key ever changes,
then the next transaction is going to automatically fail.
But we added in this step right here.
We said, watch this hash.
If that thing changes, then fail.
The update that we're going to make in just a moment.
But once again, we can imagine what's going to go on behind the scenes.
We've got these two lines of execution.
We fetch the hash.
Once again, we'll imagine that this over here is going to be processed first.
We go and update the inmate to 15.
Now, that hash has been changed.
The key stored there has changed in some way.
Now we will process this request over here.
It looks like the amount is valid and we go to update the amount.
But sure enough, that amount or this hash has changed.
So the watch statement is going to cause the update on this request handler to fail.
So it fails entirely and we do not make an update to the house.
Now everything there looks good.
At first glance, it appears that everything's going to work as intended and we are not going to accidentally
regress the amount of money being bid on this item.
I don't want you to really think about what this means for our application and really for the business
that we might be trying to bid or build around this application.
We're really talking about two different scenarios here.
There's one scenario in which we first process the $15 bid and another scenario in which we first process
the $10 bid.
Then the case where we first processed the $15 bid, we update our item hash with $15 and our watch
statement would cancel the bid for $10.
That's why I just showed you a moment to go on the diagram, and that was good.
That is what we wanted.
The $10 bid would have been invalid and we definitely wanted to cancel it.
However, think about scenario two.
And scenario to you.
If we process the $10 bid first, when we go to apply the $15 bid and update the item house that watch
or the transaction would fail.
That is actually when we think about it and we think about the goal of our application, that is really,
really bad.
We just canceled a bid that was completely valid.
Absolutely.
A $15 bid is completely valid because it is the latest and highest amount of money that has been bid
on this item.
But because of our concurrency solution, we failed that request.
And so any user who might be trying to bid $15 might say, Oh, the bid failed.
Well, I'm just not going to bid any money.
And they might walk away and not try to apply their bid at all again.
So we might have just lost out on $5 here because of a very simple concurrency issue.
Again, even though it appears that everything is working well, I think that we need to figure out
a better solution.
Now there is one very obvious solution.
We could put it the obvious solution.
Do this fact that we are possibly failing otherwise valid transactions is that we could implement a
retry mechanism.
So whenever a request fails or a transaction fails due to a watch command, we could just have a little
bit of code that tries to rerun this entire block.
Though, if this entire block right here fails due to a watch error, we could say just go ahead and
try to run it again.
Maybe try to run it ten times get.
There's two problems with that.
First, this approach doesn't really scale all that well.
We're going to quickly see that using the watch commands quite a bit is going to slow down our read
a server a little bit compared to another alternative that is available to us.
Secondly, if we wanted to retry this, it would introduce a lot of additional load on our read a server
just from the additional requests for getting information.
Remember, every single time that we tried to retry this block right here, we would have to get the
latest item details.
This entire point here is we always want to see the latest item hash every time we tried to do the retry.
All of our DNA fetching logic would have to run again and again and again and again until our transaction
eventually succeeded.
So even though we could implement a retry mechanism here and it might work out well, it would probably
introduce a lot of additional load on already server.
So as you guess, we're going to take a look at a better solution to this problem.
We're not going to use the watch command at all, which is great.
And it can definitely work in some cases.
But in other cases we're getting a lot of incoming requests.
It's going to fail far too many transactions.
Okay.
So we're going to take a quick pause right here before this video gets too long.
We're going to come back the next video.
I'm going to show you some issues with Watch in action.
And we're going to take a look at a better solution to this concurrency stuff.