Let's take a look at how we're going to solve this issue.
Now, believe it or not, it turns out that understanding this issue is a lot more challenging than
solving it.
So solving this problem is going to involve a very simple Lewis script.
It's going to take not a lot of time to put this together and fix this potential issue.
So here's what we're going to do.
Before I tell you in great detail on what's going on, there's a detail around Louis scripts I just
want you to remember.
Whenever we are executing a Louis script in Readies, Readies is not going to process any other commands.
So it doesn't matter if 50 clients start to send commands to Redis when it's executing a Louis script,
the script will go from start to finish without doing anything else.
And that's a super key element of our solution here.
All right.
So once again, we've got process.
One is going to acquire our luck with a token number that's a randomly generated string of high.
So we're going to store high right there.
Then when we are all done processing data and we're ready to release the lock rather than doing a direct
delete call, we're going to instead make use of a script.
So we're going to run behind the scenes through Node Redis.
Remember, we don't really run our store directly, but Node Redis is going to run something like email
store, script ID.
We're going to provide one key of lock item A1.
So that's that key right there.
And then a single argument of hi.
And that's really the token we have right there.
So we can imagine that we are sending off keys of one of like item A1 and HGV at one of high.
And then our script is going to look something like this right here.
I'm going to take the script.
This is not exactly what we're going to write, but it's awfully close.
And I'm going to substitute out the keys at one and RGV at one for the actual values.
We're going to essentially do a get of lock item, a one.
We're going to see if that is equal.
The string of high.
And if it is, then we're going to delete block item A1.
And that's it.
So why does this fix any problem?
What this really does is it makes sure that we are only deleting this token mixture.
We are only unlocking this thing if our process P1 is still in control of the lock.
If the automatic.
Lock expire right here has already kicked in and we've already deleted the value right here.
Then our Lewis script is not going to delete anything, so we are not going to risk accidentally unlocking
this thing just because we have some timing issues.
So the script is more or less saying Is the lock token here still what it was?
When we set it.
That's really what's going on.
And that's going to solve all of India or all the issues I mentioned in the last video.
Like I said, a lot easier to process the solution than to understand the underlying issue.
Now that we understand the solution, hopefully we'll start to put together this custom script in just
a moment.