Let's create a new custom Lewis script.
Remember, we can create scripts inside of our services.
Read his client's file.
Inside of here, we have the big script section.
So I'm going to add in a new key to this thing.
Our new function, which is going to be tied to our client, is going to be called simply a lock.
Whenever we call unlock, we're going to ultimately provide two different arguments.
The first argument is going to be the name of the key that we want to unlock.
That's going to be the lucky.
And then the second will be the token that we want to use for the comparison.
So we only are going to be providing one key.
With that in mind, I'm going to enter a number of keys of one.
And let's go ahead and put in our transform arguments and transform reply functions, and I will take
care of the script itself.
Transform arguments.
Is going to take in the lock key.
That's whatever we want to unlock and the token.
And then we will just directly return.
Exactly.
Key and token.
Remember, the purpose of this array is to figure out how to take some number of arguments and put them
into the email shore command.
Because these keys and tokens are already strings, we don't have to do any further messing around with
them, which is why we're just putting them into an array and return them right away.
Fort Transform.
Reply.
We might get a reply.
Once again, we don't really care about it because reply.
There we go.
We don't really care about it in any way.
It's going to be whatever we return from our script, we might not return anything.
So again, not a big deal here, but it's going to pass through whatever reply we get back.
And then finally our script.
So our script is going to be just like what you saw in that diagram a moment ago.
We're going to do a red skull.
We'll run a JIT command on keys at one and we're going to check to see if the value stored there is
still equal to a RGV at one.
And if it is.
Then we need to delete it.
So return.
Red Skull will do a delete on keys at one.
And that's pretty much it.
So now we can save this.
And to actually make use of the script, we need to go back over to our lock implementation.
So here's a Whitlock right here.
I'm going to go down to where we were previously doing a manual delete right there.
And rather than calling Dell, we're going to instead call the custom script we just put together the
we will call unlock.
And then the arguments to this are what we just specified inside of transform arguments.
So the first argument needs to be the key we want to unlock.
And then that special token we had generated the lucky that's the correct argument.
And then the second argument is going to be that token we had generated, which we had called simply
token.
And that's it.
Let's go ahead and test this out again.
Back over here.
I'm going to make another new item.
I'll put in a bid of 15 bit of 20.
A bit of about ten bid of 50.
It looks like everything is working completely as expected.
And then finally, as just one last quick demonstration, I'm also going to run that entire scripting
set up I had put together previously.
So I'm going to put this entire thing under load and just make sure that if we're sending a ton of requests
at the same time, it all still works as expected.
You do not have to go through this step.
I'm just going to make sure that it all works.
So for the testing process, once again, I am temporarily going to disable the bid to load command
just because it makes testing a little bit easier for me.
And then back over at my terminal.
I'm going to rerun these three scripts.
Go.
And yep, it looks like they are all still 100% success.
Very good.
Okay.
So that is our lock implementation.
It's looking pretty good.
There's one last thing I want to mention just in passing, in the next video, we might do a little
bit of a side topic, something you might be a bit curious about, something where you might look at
some of the issues that we solved and say, Hey, wait, Stephen, there's still this other big issue
that we haven't really addressed at all.
So one last, very small topic very quickly in the next video.