As I mentioned at the end of the last video, there's one last little topic I want to go over.
I'm going to explain the issue to you in this video, and we'll take a look at two possible solutions
in the next video or two.
Okay.
So what's the last issue?
We've gone over so many?
What's the last issue?
This one is possibly the most obvious problem that might come up.
One thing I want to remind you about is that we put together this locking mechanism, but it's really
not quite as secure or really truly a lock as we might think.
The entire locking mechanism revolves around this idea of just setting some value at a key.
That's it.
There's no actual locking of data occurring here.
There's nothing that is inherently preventing a right to this hash that we are saying we are we are
locking.
We're saying we locked it, but it's definitely not locked.
We are just trying to follow some convention for deciding when it is safe to write to the hash and when
it potentially is not safe.
The best way to understand this is to go back over to our editor and take a look at the locked yes file.
So inside of this Whitlock function, we receive that callback argument.
And then down here, once we acquired that lock, we then invoked the callback right here.
Once we call that callback, we essentially lose all control in the with lock function because the callback
could take an arbitrary amount of time to run.
Let me show you a diagram to help you understand what I mean by that.
Okay.
So in this diagram, once again process, one gets locked, it fetches some data, add the hash, and
then let's imagine that it starts processing some data.
And for whatever reason, maybe this is really heavy duty data processing.
Maybe that entire process takes 5 seconds to run.
At present, we are automatically expiring these locked values.
After that, we can look at the option right here after 2 seconds.
So after 2 seconds, we automatically expire the lock.
But our processing of data might take 5 seconds.
And then after those 5 seconds inside of our callback function, we might have a command to write some
data.
And that right operation right there it is going to succeed is again, there is nothing that is actually
preventing writing to this hash.
We are only using this locking mechanism to control whether or not we execute the callback function.
As soon as we call it a callback, that's it.
We don't really have any control after that point we ever put code into.
The callback is in control of the game.
They're the ones who get to decide whether or not they are reading data or writing data, and they could
take as long or short as they want.
And again, right now, we have no control over that whatsoever.
But processing data takes a long time and we expect the luck some other process could acquire that lock.
It thinks that it's in total control of the item hash, but it's really not because our callback function
is kind of like a rogue IT agent.
It's going to do whatever it wants.
We don't have any ability to kind of reach into the callback function right now and say, Hey, please,
the lock expired.
Please don't try to write in more data.
It just doesn't exist right now.
But to fix this problem, we really have to have something.
That says.
Inside of our callbacks.
I'm looking at create it right here.
We need to have something in here, theoretically, that says what?
How much time do we have left on our lock?
Is the lock still active?
If it's not active, then we need to just abort whatever we are doing and return early from this function
or throw some kind of error or we need to otherwise cancel whatever we are doing inside this callback.
If our lock has expired, that's the idea.
That's what we need to do.
That's the last challenge.
We take a look at the let's think of some possible solutions in the next video.