Let's take a look at one possible way of solving this problem of our callback function continuing execution,
even if the lock might have expired.
So in this first possible solution, we're going to provide an extra argument or just, I should say,
an argument to the callback function.
So whenever we call with lock, we put in the callback right here.
Our callback is going to receive an argument that we're going to call signal and I'm going to market
as type any for right now.
The idea here is we're going to pass in an object which is going to have a property on it that tells
us whether or not the transaction or I should say the lock has expired.
So then at any step along the way inside of our callback function, we could take a look at this object.
We can look at the property on it.
That's going to tell us if the lock has expired and use that to decide if we need to return early from
the callback.
So essentially Signal is saying, Hey, sorry, your lock has expired.
Please don't try to write any more data because you're not guaranteed that you actually hold the lock
anymore.
Okay.
Let's implement that back inside of our locked up to yes file.
I'm going to first find where we have the Whitlock function declaration.
Here's our callback argument right here.
We're going to say that the callback must be a function that now is going to take in something called
a signal.
And again, we're just going to ignore types here just to make everything as simple as possible.
Read market as.
Type any.
Then down where we call our callback function.
Right.
Before we invoke the callback, I'm going to make this signal object, which is going to have an expired
property.
By default, it's going to be false.
But after a timeout.
So I can do a set timeout right here.
After a timeout of 2000 milliseconds.
2000, because that's when our lock automatically expires after a delay of 2000 milliseconds.
I'm going to update the signal that expired property to be true.
And then I'm going to pass that signal object into the callback.
All right.
Now back over to bids.
Yes.
Now, whenever we are about to access credits in any way, we're going to take a look at that signal
that expired property.
If it is true, that means we lost the lock and we should either through an error or return early or
just do something like that.
But we definitely don't want to continue on assuming that we still hold the lock.
So we might go down.
Right before we tried to write some data in.
And right before that, before we tried to send off any commands and tell us to update or save some
more information, we might say, if signal expired.
And throw a new air and say lock expired.
Can't write anymore data.
Now to test us out and make sure it works.
I'm going to introduce in a little fake pause, kind of an arbitrary pause inside this callback function.
Inside of locked out.
Yes.
Once again, at the very bottom, you'll notice I put in a function here called pause.
We can use this thing to just put in some pause anywhere inside of our code.
So I'm going to copy that function.
I'm going to take it back to it.
Yes.
I'm going to paste at the top like so.
And then right after I attempt to fetch the item inside of Whitlock, I'm going to add in a wait pause.
5000.
So this is going to simulate some really heavy duty processing in our code.
By the time these 5 seconds have passed, our lock will have expired.
And it's definitely possible that some other process might have acquired the lock.
So we definitely will not want to update or try to write any data, assuming that we still hold the
lock.
Yeah.
Let's save this.
And then back over in my browser.
I've got a brand new item right here.
I'm going to try to place a bid.
So after one, two, the lock expired.
Three, four, five.
And there we go.
So lock expired.
We can't write any data because potentially after the first 2 seconds, another process might have gotten
lock.
Okay.
So definitely work.
Stefan looks good.
I'm going to take out the pause right here.
I want to have 5 seconds every time someone tries to make a bid.
And I want to point out that although this works, there's just one small issue.
Remember our Whitlock function we put together?
You can imagine that we're working on a real project.
You and I, as writers.
Developers might be the one to put this function together, and there might be other people at the company
that we work for who are going to make use of this function.
So we are kind of assuming here that all these other engineers are going to now use this signal object
correctly.
We're assuming that before trying to write any data entreaties, they're going to check that expired
property.
But obviously, there's no guarantee that another engineer might just have no idea that this is a potential
issue.
So they might not ever put in that expired check.
So they might accidentally have some code that's going to do that really long processing step.
The lock might expire automatically and they're going to try to write some data.
So even though this works, it's definitely no guarantee.
It's entirely possible that even you and I in the future will forget to put in a check like this.
And so we might accidentally run into an issue here as well.
So even though this definitely works.
Yeah, it's just not super ideal.
Three to take a look at one other possible solution in the next video.
This other solution is really advanced, super advanced typescript JavaScript stuff.
But I just want to show it to you to just give you an idea of kind of what's possible around all this
lock and concurrency stuff.