Next, I'm going to scroll down and find a function called build client proxy.
So this is where we are going to take our read his client and wrap it up in a proxy.
Okay.
So inside of here, I'm going to receive one argument.
It's going to be the timeout in milliseconds.
Whenever we call bill to client proxy, we're going to immediately figure out what the start time is.
In other words, when are we initially building the client proxy?
So we'll say start time is date now.
Then I'm going to build up a proxy handler.
And this is where, as I mentioned, I'm going to assume that you are somewhat familiar with JavaScript
proxies.
I'll say handler.
It's going to have a jet method on it.
The target is going to be of type client.
And then prop Kiev client.
I know we have some areas around right here to fix those up.
Right above the function definition I'm going to add in type client is type of client.
Then inside the get function, I'm going to check and see if someone is trying to access a property
on the right client.
After the expiration time of our entire lock.
So I'm going to look at the current time.
And if that is greater than or equal to the start time plus the time out in milliseconds.
Then that means our luck has probably expired.
So I'm going to throw a new ear and say luck has expired.
Otherwise the lock is probably still valid.
So I'm going to look up whatever property the person was trying to find on the client.
So that's going to be.
Target crop like so.
Prop or go.
Then I'm going to look at what value I just got off.
So I'll say type of value that is a function.
And I want to find the value to target otherwise value.
All right.
I know these last two lines of code right here that we just put together.
Total mystery, not clear what's going on.
Again, comes back to proxies.
We're not going to sweat the functionality of that part just too much right now.
After building up the entire handler.
Last thing I will do inside of here is creates and return my new proxy.
And then I also have to fix up a little bit of typing here so I can add in as clients.
Okay.
So again, without going too far in the proxies, any time someone tries to use a method on the reader's
client, we're going to see if the lock has expired.
If it has, we're going to throw in there.
That's what all this code is doing.
If it has not expired, then we're going to allow the person to go ahead and cull whatever method they
are trying to access.
Now to use this thing specifically to build client proxy function, I'm going to go back up right here.
The right.
Before we call the callback, I'm going to create a new variable called proxy ID client.
And that's going to be the result of build client proxy.
And I'm going to pass in the timeout milliseconds.
And then I'm going to pass that in as the second about let's make it the first argument to the callback.
Like so.
We're getting an air right here because our function definition of what the callback should be was not
expecting to arguments.
It was only expecting one to fix that up.
I'm going to scroll back up again.
Do the top of Whitlock.
And I'm going to say that a callback function is going to receive not only a signal, but as the first
argument.
It's also going to receive a client, a call that read his client.
We have type client.
Okay.
So now finally, a demonstration of actually making use of this thing.
So to use this, I would go back over to midcourt.
Yes.
Here's the callback function.
It now is receiving as the first argument, something that we'll call locked clients.
And that's going to be a pipe.
Above.
Client.
So then inside the callback function, any time I want to access Redis, instead of using this client
that we are importing, I'm going to use the proxy version which is going to start throwing errors if
someone tries to use the thing after the lock has expired.
So I'm going to go down to where we do our three right operations.
And instead of using client, client, client, client, I'm going to instead use.
We call it.
Locked clients.
Yeah, there we go.
So instead of client client clients, I'm going to use luck.
Client.
Okay.
So now it's time to test this thing out.
I'm going to save everything.
Go back over to my browser.
And now if I refresh.
Everything still works.
I can still see the item.
And if I start to enter in a bid, totally fine.
All works as expected.
Well, let's see what happens if we start to introduce a big timeouts or a big pause while we are trying
to create a bit.
So once again, towards the top of with luck.
Right after I get the item, I'm going to add in and await odds of 5 seconds.
So now just to go over what's going to happen again, we're going to acquire the lock.
We're going to wait 5 seconds.
By the time 5 seconds have elapsed, the lock will have already expired.
So we no longer have a valid lock.
We don't want to allow anyone who's right in this callback function to do anything else.
So when they tried to access any property on your client, an error is going to immediately be thrown.
So no, our push is going to occur.
Know each set and knows the add will occur.
So this is what's going to make sure that no one ever tries to mess around with any data after the lock
has expired.
To make sure this is really working.
I'm also going to comment out these signals that expired check right here as well to make sure that
we're actually relying upon the proxy implementation as opposed to the signal effects we put together
just a moment ago.
Okay.
It's now time to try it again.
So I'm going to try creating another valid bid.
I'm going to wait.
One, two, three, four, five.
And I should eventually see the error that says lock has expired and that's it.
So now we don't have to rely upon other engineers putting in that manual signal check.
We could just start throwing errors as soon as the lock has expired.
Okay.
So that's it.
That is pretty much it.
On concurrency as far as this course goes, I'm going to take out the pause right here, by the way.
I don't want to have a big pause.
So we went a little bit off the rails here.
A lot of detail on concurrency, probably more than we needed.
But I hope this gives you a big picture view on some big issues to consider around concurrency.
There are other locations inside of our project where we definitely should be concerned around concurrency,
but we're not going to add in any more stuff around concurrency just so we can focus on individual topics
as opposed to having to keep on come back and talk about concurrency over and over and over again.
All right.
So I think we're all done.
Let's move on.
Still have a lot to talk about in the world of protests.