You really don't have to take my word for it that we're going to run into issues around this watch command.
As I mentioned, it definitely appears to solve problems.
But as soon as we start to introduce any amount of serious load on our server, we'll see that a lot
of requests start to fail very quickly.
So to demonstrate this, I made a little change to our application.
You do not have to make this change.
As a matter of fact, I really recommend you do not make this change.
I just slightly change the architecture a little bit and I put together a script.
The goal these changes was to try to create a lot of bids for a single item at a time.
So in the changes I made to my server, which I'm going to undo here very quickly at the end of this
video, I changed it.
So I'm now running three copies of the Node server.
I also am connecting to a local copy of Redis instead of a remote copy just to minimise the amount of
latency between my server and my running register.
And then finally I created three separate bitter scripts.
These are no Java scripts.
They tried to make a ton of different bids on a very particular item at the same time.
So there's three better scripts, three servers and one copy of Redis.
We're really simulating kind of a real application here where we have a lot of users who are all trying
to bid on the same item at the exact same time.
These scripts are all going to run and then report some information about how many requests to make
the bid succeeded and how many failed.
We can get a better sense of how often watch is going to cause a request to fail or a transaction to
fail in a moderately loaded application.
Without further ado, let's run these scripts.
I'll run them on my machine.
We'll see what happens as a result.
All right.
So here's the script right here.
I put it into the sandbox index.
Not to.
Yes, file.
As a very fast overview is again really recommend you don't try running this because it required a couple
of other code changes inside of our application.
I've got a function that tries to create a bit right here, so it's going to create a bid on a very
particular item.
I then record some metrics around whether or not this thing failed or succeeded.
And then down at the bottom.
I've got a cookie to handle authentication.
I've got the number of bids.
I'm going to try to make the idea of the item.
And then here's where I try to create a whole bunch of bids very quickly.
You also note that I am running three copies of the server on ports 3000, 3001, 3002.
And so for each bidding script they are alternating which server they are sending a bid request to.
Even though I'm showing one arrow here, here, here.
Each bidder is sending bid requests off to each separate server.
All right.
So.
I'm going to run this now and we'll see what output we get.
Now.
My windows are kind of crazy right now.
So on the left hand side, I've got my code editor right here in the center.
I've got one bit scripts, here's the output from it and I've got a second bit script and a third right
here.
I'm going to run the scripts.
There we go.
And that was it.
It's very, very fast.
Each script is currently attempting to create 50 separate bids on one item, so in total 150 bits.
And then I know the text is a little bit small, but you can see some metrics around what occurred when
the script ran.
So in this case, the scripts ran all the requests in 122 milliseconds.
35 of those 50 requests succeeded.
In other words, we successfully created 35 bits, but 15 of them failed due to transaction cancellations
due to the watch command.
In this case, only 70% of all the bid requests exceeded.
Over here, only 60.
And over here, only 64.
Now it might seem like, hey, 70% of requests trying to create a bid that's reasonable.
70%.
It really isn't.
We're talking about handling money here.
We're talking about receiving bids into our application.
And if we're building this for a real business, we want every single bid to be processed successfully.
70% is not good enough.
We want 100% of bids to succeed as long, of course, as they are valid.
The success rates of 70, 60 and 64 just doesn't cut it.
We have to come up with a better concurrency mechanism.
We need to make sure that every valid bid that comes into our app is always within reason, always going
to succeed.
That's our goal.
We need to get these numbers up.
We've got to get up to 100% success for all valid bits.
Over that.
Of course, as I mentioned, we need a better concurrency handling system.
So the next video, we're going to take a look at a slightly better way of handling concert currency
by using a loose script.