Let's take a look at a couple of different diagrams and understand how we're going to solve this concurrency
issue.
First, I want to really simplify the situation that we're running into around these concurrency problems.
The problem specifically that we are really seeing here is we have two processes that are both trying
to read a value out of Redis and then do a right operation based upon that value.
So if you're ever in this scenario where you have one process that is doing a read and then a writes
and then a second process that is just doing a read of the same value.
This is okay.
No problem here whatsoever.
The issue is when we have two processes that are both trying to read and write to the same value at
the same time, because we might end up with different results depending upon which processes right
operation goes first.
So that's specifically the problem that we are trying to fix.
So ideally, we would have some way to say process one is going to go first and then process two will
go second.
We ideally want to pause temporarily one process or the other.
Here's how we're going to do that.
Whenever we have two different processes that are trying to update some value inside of Redis or really
do a read and then a write operation, and it doesn't have to be something stored inside of a hash,
it could be something inside of a list or a sorted set and so on.
We're going to try to say that only one process can modify a given value at any given time.
And we're going to do that by using a technique called a lock.
So whenever process one or process two, you wants to update something tied to this hash, they're going
to first try to set a very specific key in Redis.
This is going to be a separate key.
There's nothing special about the name.
It is going to be just a random convention that you and I come up with.
So we might try to set a key of something like Lock Colon, item A one, which would indicate that we
are trying to lock the value stored at the key item A1.
They're both going to try to do a right operation and set some value right here.
The right operation that they're going to do will be a simple set.
So at the same time, process one and process two are both going to send off a set command.
They're both going to try to set the key lock item, A-1.
And then process one might try to store some random string there, something like high and process.
You might try to store something random there like say the string by.
And then very critically, we're also going to add on the annex arguments to both these commands.
Remember what Annex does.
It means only try to set the value if a value is not already stored here.
Let's imagine.
That may be process one sends off its set command just a little bit before process to.
At that point, lock item A1 is currently not referring to any value.
The first set command is going to work because there is no value stored there yet.
We're going to do a high.
When process one gets a response from Metis, it will be told that the set operation was successful.
Well, then imagine that a half a millisecond later, Ross has to set Comey.
I just processed.
It runs the same set operation, but with a different value right there.
And in this case, when it looks up this key, it's going to find that the value is already stored there.
So it's going to return null back over to our process.
And so our process is aware that the set operation failed.
Because Process one was successful in doing a set and Process two failed in doing the set.
Process one currently would have exclusive access to read and write to the hash stored at item A1.
So at this point in time, Ross, this one has exclusive access.
It can read from that value, it can update the value and so on.
And once again, to be clear, any other process can read it from this House right now.
Absolutely.
They can read from that house.
No problem whatsoever.
What we specifically want to prevent is any other process doing a read and then a rights operation.
The process.
One is going to mess around it, that hash as much as it wants because it knows that in theory, nobody
else should be trying to modify this value at that point in time.
Simultaneously.
Process two is not going to give up just yet.
Instead, it's going to keep on sending that same set commands every couple of milliseconds.
So it's going to keep retrying this command over and over and over again in very quick succession.
Then at some point, Ross, this one is going to finish up with all of its work.
So it's done, it's read operation, it's done its right operation.
And so now it needs to say, Hey, I'm all done working on this item hash.
So it's going to delete the key stored there, stored at specifically lock item A1.
That value is going to be removed.
Now, as you can imagine, the next time process two sends off its set commands, it's going to succeed.
So it will store by their process.
You will get a response from Rita saying that the value was successfully stored.
And so now Process two has exclusive access to item A1.
And that's it.
That's the entire flow.
We're going to use this technique of a lock to make sure that only one process has that read and rights
operation or responsibility around any given key at a given time.
Any other process that wants to do this, read and write is going to have to keep on trying to set a
very specific key.
And only when that set operation succeeds will it have the ability to do a read and write operation
to that particular key.
Now, I've given you a very high level definition of what we're doing here.
Very high level look.
But there are a couple of other little odds and ends that we're going to run into along the way.
So we are going to slightly change this process just a little bit as we do some further investigation
and implementation.
But for right now, this is a pretty accurate overview on what we're trying to achieve.
Let's get started on our implementation in just a moment.