Before we get started on our implementation, I want to give you a couple of notes.
The first thing to understand, we are going to be building a lock implementation that is a dramatically,
dramatically simplified version of another algorithm called Red Lock.
Red lock is a production grade concurrency locking algorithm.
So if you ever have a series project, I really recommend you use a red lock algorithm instead of what
we are building here.
You do not have to build red lock from scratch.
Instead, there are popular libraries in just about every different language that automatically implement
the red lock algorithm for you.
And you can just make use of these different libraries in your project very easily.
We are only building a locking algorithm here in this course, so you can kind of understand the concept
of locking and what it does behind the scenes.
Very quickly, I'm going to open up the link I have down here.
So over my browser.
If I go to that page, it has some information on locks in general, and if you scroll down, you'll
find links to different implementations of red lock in many different languages.
So again, if you ever have, say, a JavaScript project where you need to have some kind of concurrency
algorithm or a lock algorithm, we would use possibly node red lock right here.
Okay.
One other set of notes very quickly.
We're going to put together our implementation in TypeScript, and this is going to involve a little
bit of complex TypeScript.
I'm not going to do a ton of slide discussion on the code we are writing per se, so I'm not really
going to explain the TypeScript aspects of it.
So with that in mind, if you don't know TypeScript or if you don't care about TypeScript, no problem
whatsoever.
Just skip over the next couple of videos.
You can skip over the next couple of videos where we implement all this concurrency stuff and it's not
going to break anything else inside the course.
This is the only place where we are going to create this locking algorithm and actually make use of
it everywhere else.
I'm going to mention stuff around concurrency and say, Hey, this would be a good place to use our
locking algorithm, but we're not going to actually put the implementation anywhere else or use the
implementation anywhere else.
Okay.
So enough of this.
Enough notes.
Let's get to it.
So back inside, my editor.
We're going to first begin by finding that bid.
Start to yes.
File the inside of services.
Where is it?
Yes, we were looking at creep ID just a moment ago.
Inside of here, we've got that execute isolated function.
That's what's going to create a new connection over charities.
But then does the watch then read some data, does validation, and then write some data inside of a
transaction?
Let me tell you what our end goal here is around our locking algorithm.
What exactly are we trying to build?
Well, here's what I want to have.
I want to have something like this.
I want to have a function called width lock.
So that's going to a function that you and I are going to write somewhere else inside of our project.
The first argument is going to be some key that we want to temporarily lock down access to the for us.
That's going to be the item ID hash.
The first argument here would be add or sort item ID.
That's what we want to lock down.
The Whitlock out function right here is then going to go through this entire process that we just walked
through in the last video.
So it's going to do all these set operations until eventually a set succeeds.
Once the set succeeds, Whitlock is then going to call a callback function that we're going to provide
as a second arguments.
And this callback function is where we are going to implement all the logic to run.
After the lock is acquired.
So for us, that's going to be the entire process of matching.
The item.
Doing validation.
And then writing some data.
So in other words, exactly what we're doing inside of execute isolated down here right now with the
exception of we no longer need a watch statement.
So that's it.
That's the goal.
We want to have a function.
All that with luck.
It's going to take these two arguments and Whitlock internally is going to implement this entire process
we just walked through.
Now that we understand the goal, let's read this Whitlock mentioned in the next video.