Now it's time to define with luck.
I've already created a file inside of our project that's going to contain the implementation of that
function.
So over here, inside of Services Treatise, I'm going to find the file called Locked.
Yes.
But here's the empty Whitlock function that you and I need to implement.
Let's begin by adding in a couple of arguments we expect to receive into this function.
The first argument is going to be the key that we want to try to lock down access to.
And the second argument is going to be the callback function to run.
Once we acquire that lock, I'm going to abbreviate that callback function as CB and then it's type.
Right now we'll just be a function that returns anything.
Then inside of Whitlock, I'm going to write out a couple of comments just to guide myself.
The first, I'm going to initialize a few variables to control retry behavior.
Remember, if our lock implementation doesn't initially successfully get the lock.
So if the set an X fails, then we want to implement some kind of automatic retry behavior.
We want to keep trying to run the set command.
So we need to put together some kind of default values for how often we're going to retry and the total
number of times to retry.
But right now I'm going to say.
Now I'm going to put in retry delay in milliseconds.
So this is how often in between retry attempts.
Expressed as milliseconds.
I'm going to put in for right now 100.
At these values that we're going to enter are totally arbitrary and we're going to see that it's probably
going to be very useful to try to tweak these values a little bit over time.
And the other value that we're going to put in here is how many times are we going to attempt to retry?
We're going to eventually modify this variable.
So I'm going to define it using the let keyword.
I'll say retries is going to be about 20.
We'll try to retry acquiring that lock 20 times in total.
All right.
Now, a couple of more comments here.
Just to continue guiding our implementation, I'm then going to put together some code to generates
a random value to store out the lock key.
So remember, whenever you are doing these set operations, we are going to set some actual value.
So this first command is trying to set the value high right here.
Second one is trying to set the value by.
It is really important for this to be a random value.
You'll see why in a little bit.
This right here indicates.
Yep, we need to make this random value.
Then after that, we're going to rate the lock key.
The argument that we got up here, this key is the key that we actually want to lock down access to.
So that would be item A1.
We need to take item A1 and turn it into something that looks like this.
So something that says lock colon and then maybe the key that we're trying to lock down.
Then after all that, we're going to set up a while loop.
To implement the retry behavior.
And inside the wild loop we're going to.
Try to do a set.
An operation.
If the asset is successful, then, Randy, call back.
So that callback is the one that is provided as the second argument to Whitlock.
Otherwise, if it was not successful, if we were not able to set that value successfully, then we're
going to do a brief pause.
And the brief pause is really however many milliseconds we designated right there.
And then we're going to retry the operation.
That's it.
That's everything that we need to do.
Finally after we call the callback function.
So that step right there, we need to make sure that we unset the locked key.
So remember, once again, back over here, once process number one is all done working on item A-1
or whatever else it needs to do, it needs to eventually say, hey, I'm all done with my work.
I've completed everything I needed to do, so it needs to run a delete and unset the value at the lock
key right here.
Okay.
We've got the comments.
I'm for implementation.
The first to generate a random value.
We could definitely just generate a random number.
But something you're going to see a little bit more common is to generate a actual hash.
So kind of a series of random numbers and letters.
We're going to generate that hash by using a library built into Node.js.
So I'm going to go up to the very top of this file and import random bytes from crypto.
Then.
Down here.
I'm going to generate a value called token.
So this is the random value they were going to store at that lucky and I will generate it by calling
random bytes six to string x.
So again, that's going to give us something that looks like that or something similar.
Just a big, long, random string.
And we need to take that.
He here we provide as the first argument and create our locked key.
That's going to be that key right there.
It's really up to you how to generate this key.
But I think what I show in that diagram is going to work just fine for our purposes.
They'll say Lock Key is going to be Lock Colon, and then whatever was provided as that first argument.
Next up will implement that while.
For the while loop.
I'm going to keep retrying as long as this retry is variable right here.
Is greater than or equal to zero.
Just keep on trying over and over and over again.
Then inside of here, we will implement all the steps we have committed right there.
So I'll just move those into the wild loop.
I do know that as I run the while loop, I want to decrease retries every time.
So the very last line here will be retried, minus, minus, or alternately we can just do it first
so we don't forget about it.
That works as well.
Then we can do our sets and x operation.
Go for that.
Will do and awaits client dot set.
We want to attempt to set the lock key.
We want to set the value token there.
And then we'll provide options of an X.
True.
Again only set the value is not currently set.
We're getting an error from client.
That's just because we need to import it.
Let's take care of that very quickly at the top of the file.
So at the very top, I will import.
Clients from.
Plant.
Then whenever we do our set operation, we're going to take a look at what Red has returned to us.
And I'm going to assign that to a variable called acquired.
So if quired is truth.
If we were able to set this thing, that means we have acquired the locks successfully.
Otherwise, if the value was already set because the next flag is on here, acquired will be null instead.
So I'm going to check to see.
If acquired is not, I'll say, if not acquired.
So that's the case in which we want to do a brief pause and then retry.
So in that scenario, I going to call a weight as I'm going to pause for a retry delay milliseconds.
The pause function was already put together for us.
Inside this file you can find the implementation of it down here.
It's just a arbitrary little pause for some amount of time.
Then I don't want to do anything else inside this wild loop.
I just want to go to the next iteration of the wild loop, so I'll do a continue.
That's going to skip over everything else inside the whale.
And, of course, go right back up here to the top.
Then otherwise if we did acquire the lock so we were successful, then we want to run our callback function.
So I'm going to do and await CB.
I'm going to take whatever is returned from that callback, assign its results, and then I will return
the results.
This return result is not strictly necessary.
I'm just assuming that when we call with lock, right, we're back inside of bits not to.
Yes, we might want to get whatever value gets returned from that callback.
So eventually, if this callback right here returns something we want to use somewhere else in cyber
app.
I'm just making sure that we take that return value and return it from with lock itself.
Then finally outside the wire loop.
And not outside the world.
I just mean to say we left the comment outside the well loop.
Before we return entirely from this function, we need to make sure that we unset that lock.
So we're going to do that right before we return.
And to unset the lock, all we have to do is delete the value that was stored at the lucky.
So that will be an await client dot now.
And I want to on set was our key called the Lucky.
And that's it.
Okay.
Now I want you to be aware our current implementation has a small problem or two that we definitely
need to fix up.
So we're absolutely in revisit this function.
It is not yet complete, but I just want to try running this as it is and say okay, like we're making
progress.
And point out there was one or two issues we need to come back and fix.
So pause right here.
We'll come back in just a moment and we're going to start implementing this bid's sportsfile, the Whitlock
Hall right here.