Back inside of bids.
Yes, we can now import the Whitlock function we just put together and then implement the callback where
we need to fetch the item, do the validation, and then write some data to Redis.
So to get started, I'll find where I am importing clients right here.
And in addition to importing client, I will also import with lock.
Then inside of Whitlock, we need to go through these three steps.
We have already implemented those inside of execute isolated.
So we're going to copy some code from execute isolated and paste it up into.
Whitlock The lines we're going to copy are everything from contact item right here down pass the if
statements.
And then all the way up to you, but not including the exact statement.
So I'm going to copy all that will then go up to the Whitlock.
And I'll do a paste.
So here is the updated Whitlock.
We no longer have an isolated client inside this and we don't need the multi anymore either because
we're not going to be using a transaction to handle this concurrency stuff anymore.
So we need to remove those two lines.
We do still, of course, have to run these three commands.
We can run all three of those by just making use of a pipeline, which we've covered several times before.
So to create the pipeline, I'm going to add on client.
Clients and clients.
And I'm going to pass all three of these commands off to a promise that all.
Remember, we need to pass in a ray into promise.
Not all.
So I'll.
Do you promise?
Dot all parentheses, open square brackets.
And then on the other side of all three commands, I'll put in a closing square brackets and a parentheses.
And then after each the client commands, I'm going to add in a comma.
So comma right there.
Comma right here.
And we don't have to put one right there, but if you want to go for it.
And then finally, I'm going to make sure I return the promised all.
Okay.
So that should be it.
Again, the lock implementation is not perfect, but it's pretty much there.
So we do have to fix a couple of very small things around it.
We at least have enough now to do a quick test.
So let's pause here.
We'll come back in just a moment.
I'm going to do a little bit more benchmarking for you on my augmented server setup, where I have a
couple of servers running with a couple of different separate bidders as well.
We're going to make sure that the bid implementation or really the lock implementation is working as
expected.