At the end of last video, I made a very small mistake inside of bids.
Yes, I did not comment out the remaining execute isolated call down here, so we no longer need that
entire executed isolated block.
I'm going to just call it all out for right now.
I'm not going to delete it because I want to eventually compare our lock implementation versus the transaction
based approach.
Okay.
So I'm going to make sure I comments all that and save the results.
Temporarily.
You do not need to do this, but for just as I'm testing everything.
I'm also going to comment out recheck to see that the items price is enough.
This just makes doing my little benchmarking process a little bit easier for me.
So you do not have to comment that out.
I'm just doing it temporarily.
Now I'm going to go back over to my benchmarking script that showed you a little bit ago.
So this is where I attempt to create a bunch of different bids for a particular item at more or less
the same time across three different scripts going to three different servers.
And in this case, each separate script is trying to create 50 different bits.
So 150 bits in total.
Let's see what the result is.
All right.
So once again, I've got script number one, two and three.
So I'm going to run all through them.
And there you go.
So it looks like it was successful.
All three scripts were able to create all the different bids successfully.
Now, wanting to immediately be aware of is that running the scripts now took much, much longer.
You might recall that previously it only took like 200 milliseconds when we were using the transaction
based approach.
The reason it's taking so much longer now is that with the transaction approach, we would automatically
fail every single request right away.
There was no retry behavior whatsoever.
Now that we're using the lock implementation, if any given process fails to acquire the lock, it's
going to sit around and retry the set operation after those 200 milliseconds have passed.
So that's why we're seeing so much longer now.
If we were concerned about this duration, then we can always go back into.
Our Whitlock implementation and change the retry to light in this why could decrease this quite a bit
if I wanted to and I think I might just said to in milliseconds a little bit ago by the way it's actually
100 milliseconds.
So again, if I wanted to, we could really shave off some amount of time on this retry delay.
But right now, I'm happy with 100 because it definitely appears that it's working out pretty well for
my case.
All right.
So it looks like this initial implementation is working just fine.
But as I've mentioned several times, the implementation is not perfect.
So I want to go over a couple of corner cases that we need to be aware of.
Some problems with this, with implementation, and we'll take a look at how we can solve those in the
next video.