As I have hinted at several times, our lock, for the most part, is working successfully.
But there are a couple of small issues with it that we need to address.
So for the first issue, I'm going to run through a little example inside the actual application.
Are we going to see that unfortunately, the lock is appearing to fail underneath a rather common scenario?
So back at the application, I'm going to make a brand new item with a duration of 10 minutes.
And then going to add a valid bid to the item.
So about $10.
That definitely worked.
Now I'm going to put in an invalid bid of five in this case.
And just as a quick note, I have enabled the check right here to make sure that we throw in air if
the bid is too low.
So when I entered the bid amount of five right here, a air should be thrown inside that Whitlock function.
Okay, I'm going to place it.
And hey, sure enough, we capture the air and it gets reported to the clients and I'm told bid too
low.
I need to adjust it.
So I'm going to try to put in a valid bid now of 25.
And it looks like everything just hangs for a little bit.
And then I'm told, okay, success of the winning bid.
But it still says that the high bid is $10 and there's only one bid.
I'm going to try to refresh really quickly.
There's still the same thing if I put in 25 again.
Okay.
I'm told success again.
And if I refresh it definitely is not working correctly.
It says that the bid was accepted, but clearly it is not.
Clearly something is not working.
Let's try to figure out what is going on here.
All right.
First, want to give you a quick reminder on a very specific part of our lock implementation.
After process, one acquires a lock.
It then tries to do some amount of work.
And then once all that work is done, a very critical part of this entire algorithm is to make sure
that we unlock the lock key.
So we need to unset the value right here so that some other process can succeed in its set operation
and acquire the lock.
So if this delete does not occur, then process number two is never going to be able to acquire the
lock and be able to safely modify the item hash.
And as you can guess, that's exactly what is happening right now.
Process one is acquiring the lock and then immediately after that, as we are trying to validate the
incoming bid and make sure that it has enough money, we are throwing an error.
And so our with lock function doesn't have any error handling right now.
So it never issues that delete command and never onsets this key.
And the result is process number two is going to forever try to set the key until eventually it runs
out of re tries.
That's the exact behavior we're seeing inside of our app right now.
If I put in a valid bid and click on place bid, I wait about 2 seconds until eventually all those retries
get eaten up and then the request kind of silently fails.
Yeah, I get a success message here, but truthfully, the thing definitely failed.
Now in this case, the crash here isn't really a crash per se.
We are just throwing an air within our locking function.
That's something that's going to happen all the time.
In many scenarios, we want to throw in air.
Even if we are inside of a locking function, we should probably add in some basic air handling, which
we could definitely do.
That's not really going to solve the underlying issue.
Whenever we are in a lock function, we truly have to assume that our entire server might crash.
For some reason, there might be some unrecoverable error.
We might lose power to our server itself.
We might take down our server.
Who knows?
So if at any point in time we crash before we unlock that key right there, that's pretty much it.
That key is going to be forever locked unless you and I go in manually and unset that key.
So we need to have some kind of extra feature here to make sure that no matter what, even if process
one fails, crashes, throws an error no matter what, after some period of time, we always automatically
unset that key.
And to do so, we can make use of a argument that we learned about a long time ago on the set commands.
So when we tried to acquire the lock with a set command, we're going to start to add on the arguments.
You might recall that the argument causes a value to automatically expire after some number of milliseconds.
So when process one acquires a lock and puts in a value of high right there.
It now has 2 seconds or 2000 milliseconds to do whatever work is required to be done with that.
And then after 2 seconds, that value is going to be automatically deleted.
If Process one finishes with its work before those two millisecond or those 2000 milliseconds, that's
fine.
It will still call delete as expected, and so that value will be deleted.
But if for some reason it fails to call delete, it will be automatically cleaned up after those 2000.
That's it.
That's how we're going to solve this issue.
So just be super clear now.
Process one, it's a lock, crashes on set after 2000 milliseconds.
Now, process two, you can safely acquire the lock.
Okay.
To put in this implementation, it's going to be super easy and straightforward.
Back inside of locked.
Yes.
But here's with lock.
I'm going to find where we do our set operation in addition to the Annex arguments.
I will also do a tax of 2000.
So now any with lock function really just has 2 seconds to complete all the work that is required.
If that is not long enough, we can always adjust its value.
We can go up to say 10 seconds or whatever else.
But for our application for testing purposes right now, 2000 is definitely reasonable.
Okay.
So now if I save this.
And go test my app again.
This chair that I was working with previously, this thing is forever locked.
It is unrecoverable at this point, unless we run a command to manually unlock it.
So just to make testing a little bit easier, I'm going to go make a new item very quickly.
And I'm going to repeat the same operation.
So I'm going to put in a valid bid, then an invalid bid, and then another valid bid.
And it works.
Okay.
So that's definitely a good step forward.
As I very briefly mentioned, we probably should put in some air handling inside of our Whitlock function
to make sure that if for some reason when we call the callback right here, so if something goes wrong
with that, we should probably still make sure that no matter what we call delete, that's definitely
something we should do.
We can handle that very easily.
By wrapping the tri statements.
We're seeing the results with a tri statement.
And a finally.
So we're going to try to run the call back if anything goes wrong with that whatsoever or if everything
succeeds either way, we're going to enter the final statements.
And inside there, we will make sure that we call delete.
And I will also give the written results up here as well.
So now, no matter what, whether the succeeds or fails, you're always going to do the unlock.
Okay.
So this looks good.
Now.
We really do want to have both.
Just be clear.
We definitely still want to have the peaks up here.
The peaks is going to make sure that even if our server completely crashes, that value gets unset.
The try finally down here is going to make sure that if you just have any plain JavaScript error, we
will still attempt to immediately unlock that lucky.
I can do one more very quick test here just to make sure it's working.
So I'm going to put in an invalid bid and then a valid one.
Yep.
Definitely works.
Okay.
So that is one more issue solved.
But there is another problem that we're going to take a look at with our implementation in just a minute
as well.