In this video, we're going to take a look at another issue with our current with lock implementation.
Before I describe the issue, I just want you to be aware that understanding the problem in this video
is going to be rather challenging.
So as you're going through this video, if everything is really confusing, don't sweat it.
I've done my best to explain what's going on.
I'm not sure if I'm going to succeed, but I'll just do my best.
I do want you to know that if you get confused at any point in time, don't sweat it.
We are really thick into concurrency issues at this point.
Kind of getting a little bit far from red is related stuff.
And ultimately the solution to the problem we're about to run into is just a couple of very short lines
of Lua.
So even if you don't super clearly understand the issue, the solution is going to be very straightforward.
Okay, without further ado, let's get to it.
Once again, we're going to imagine we have p one right here or process one.
It acquires a lock by putting in a value of hi right there.
Once it has acquired the lock, it's going to fetch some data.
Once it gets some data, maybe it's going to process it in some way.
And then eventually, when it's all done, as we've seen, it's going to send off a delete command to
clear out the value of high right there.
And that allows process two to acquire the lock by putting in a value of five.
Now I want to imagine a little variation on this process.
Let's imagine that process data right here.
This step takes some amount of time.
Who knows?
Maybe a couple of seconds, maybe just plain longer than we expected for some reason.
Would that cause any issue?
Remember that we do now have automatically expiring keys.
So no matter what, if this stalls out, we're going to clear out.
Hi there.
No matter what.
But maybe there's some kind of middle ground where things don't quite work as expected.
Let's take a look at the next diagram.
One thing to keep in mind around working with some server and communicate with Redis is that we never
have any guarantee on how long it's going to take to send a command from the server over to Redis and
actually get it processed.
So I want to imagine a real corner case here.
This is definitely not going to happen very often, but it absolutely, positively could.
Let's imagine once again, we have Python.
It gets a lock, takes forever to process this data and then eventually it says, okay, I'm all done.
I need to unset that lock.
So it needs to clear out the value of Hi right there.
So it's going to send the command off and we're going to imagine that for some unknown reason.
Who knows why?
It just plain takes a while to get the delete command sent from our server over to Redis.
And we're going to imagine that within that period of time where we have some laggy connection here,
the lock automatically expires.
The lock expires read it will automatically clear out the value of high.
And then maybe a couple of milliseconds later, Reddit's actually receives that delete command.
It looks at lock item one and says, Oh, there's already no value there, no problem whatsoever.
It's already gone.
Now, as you look at this, seems like there might not be an issue.
But again, let's really think about any possible corner case.
Here's one possible problem.
Let's imagine that we have the exact same scenario.
So we finished processing.
We sent off the delete command.
And for some reason, that command is just laggy.
It takes a second or two for the delete command to get over to Redis.
In that delay, the lock automatically expires.
So the value right there has been cleared out.
And then here is the wild card.
Here's the issue.
When the lock expired, automatically, another process might come in and try to acquire the lock with
a set command that's going to send off that same exact set and try to put in a value right here.
And to be clear, it will be set an X.
Because there is no value right here because the lock automatically expired.
E2 is going to acquire the lock.
It's going to put in a value by right there, and then half a second later, maybe a couple of milliseconds
or a second, who knows?
Finally, the delete command is going to reach retest and the delete, regardless of what value is right
there, is just going to plain delete that value.
So BI is going to get deleted.
What does that mean?
It means that process two thought it had a lock, but it just lost it completely.
Unbeknown to process to.
Now.
Is that a problem?
Absolutely, yes.
Because what could happen now?
Now, at this point in time, a third process could come in.
This third process might come in.
Try to do that set annex.
It is going to successfully acquire it because we just process the delete.
And so now maybe process three is going to put in something like see right there to say that P three
has acquired the lock.
So now we have two processes up to one P3 that both think they own the lock to some amount of data.
And it's all because this delete command right here was just a little bit laggy.
It just took a little bit longer than we expected to get that command sent from P one over to Redis.
So how could we solve this?
How could we somehow fix it?
Well, maybe one possible way would be to implement an extra little step in here in P one.
Now, I want you to know this is not going to work out, unfortunately.
But I just want to walk through this process because maybe it's going to guide us towards a solution.
Let's imagine.
Same exact scenario we got you.
One gets a lock, it takes over to process some data and it says, okay, I'm all done processing.
I better unset that lock.
But maybe we want to make sure that the correct value is actually in there because we only want p one
to unset the value right there.
If this token is equal to what it had previously stored in there when it acquired the lock.
So we could make sure that we're not deleting someone else's token and to make sure that we're actually
correctly should it issue a delete at all and that we have not expired or anything by adding in a little
get.
So we could issue a get get the token stored right there.
Well then received the response of hi.
We can compare is the response we just got back.
So that string of high equal to the original token that we had set when P one had originally acquired
luck.
If they are equal, then we can go ahead and run the delete.
This seems like this might kind of solve the issue to some degree.
But unfortunately, no, it doesn't.
Here's why.
So we're going to imagine.
At once again, we do that comparison.
We get back a string of high.
We say, yes, they're equal.
So let's go ahead and run the delete.
But if we get that same kind of little delay right here, unfortunately, well, the lock might expire
in that time that it takes for the delete command to be sent off and processed by Redis.
And so in that little window right there, we would run into the exact same issue.
As this.
So we send off the delete.
It takes some amount of time we process P2 and app meantime might issue it set that delete when it eventually
gets received and processed would clear out the value right there in LP three can come in and do a set,
acquire the lock and once again P2 and P3 all think that they are in possession of the lock at this
point.
So the whole issue here is the kind of delay that we have in the delete command.
We definitely want to issue the delete, but we don't want to run the delete.
If the lock has already expired or if for some reason some other process has acquired the lock.
So we need to think about some way of still doing this delete operation, but being a little bit more
intelligent about it.
Okay.
So that's the issue.
Hopefully we now understand it.
We're going to come back the next video and take a look at how we're going to solve this by using a
Lua script.