Hello and welcome.
My name is Stephen Greiner and I'm really excited to teach you everything I know about Redis.
Before we dive into our first technical topic, however, I just want to make sure that you have a couple
of notes on how to get unstuck if you ever run into any trouble inside this course.
So if you ever get stuck or you have any big questions, come up.
A couple of quick tips here.
The first thing you might try to do is do a search on the course.
There's a lot of discussion going on in the queue.
So always do a quick search there because if you have a question, chances are someone else might have
already asked it at some point in time.
Second, you can ask a question on our Discord server.
Discord is a free chat application.
You can find a link to our Discord server in the next lecture.
It's the one right after this one.
And then finally, don't forget, you've always got Google at hand as well.
Redis is a very popular database, and just about every problem that has ever come up with rightists
has been asked at some point in time somewhere online.
So you can always do a search and try to find a solution somewhere online.
Okay, so that's it.
Let's get started on some actual technical stuff in the next video.