Now that we've got some administrative stuff out of the way, let's start to dive into some technical
topics.
In this video, we're going to try to answer one single question What is this all about?
So we're going to start with the basics.
Redis is a database that means we can use it for persisting information for any kind of app information
like user accounts, blog posts, comments and so on.
After storing information, we can then retrieve it later on by writing queries.
Now, this behavior is similar to just about every other database out there.
The how it's right is different.
And why do we decide to use right us over any other database?
Well, the answer is simple.
Software engineers like yourself and myself just use Redis for one primary reason.
It is incredibly fast.
Redis can store and retrieve data extremely quickly.
The question here is where does Redis get its performance from?
Redis is not fast because it was created by some coding genius and it is not fast because it is written
in some kind of super special programming language or anything like that.
Instead, Redis is fast for three primary reasons.
First, all data is stored in memory.
Most databases store all their information between both the memory of a computer and a hard drive.
Accessing data in memory is fast, but getting data that is stored on the hard disk is relatively slow.
The register makes a very simple decision here.
Rather than storing any information on hard disk, it keeps all the data in memory.
And that means that accessing any data inside of a registered database is usually a very fast by default.
Now there is a very clear downside to this approach.
It means that by default, it can be challenging to work with a dataset that is larger than the amount
of memory that your computer has.
So, for example, if you have a dataset that is 100 gigabytes large, but your computer only has eight
gigabytes of memory, that is not going to fit in memory.
That might sound like a tremendous problem, but do not worry about it.
We're going to spend a lot of time later in this course discussing very clear strategies for working
around this limitation.
All right, onto the second reason that is very fast.
The second reason is that Reddit stores all of its data or organizes all of its data in simple data
structures.
Now, there's a lot of detail in this diagram right here.
Don't worry about the details.
All I need to indicate is that all of our data is organized into classic data structures like link lists,
sorted sets, hash maps and so on.
These different data structures have very well known and very well understood performance characteristics.
So you and I, as developers, can decide exactly how our information is organized in memory, so you
and I end up with a very good idea of how to efficiently query data.
Finally, red is very fast because it is very simple in nature.
Other databases like say PostgreSQL or MySQL and so on choose to layer on a feature upon feature to
make them easier to use.
But all those additional features have big performance penalties.
Red is takes a very different approach.
Rather than stuffing in a ton of different features into the database, it is kept very simple on purpose.
Okay.
So right away we are understanding here in this video that this is very fast.
That is why we use it.
It is fast for three reasons.
We keep all this data in memory.
We organize this data in simple data structures.
And this, on purpose has a very simple feature set.
Now, these three notes right here really have one big takeaway.
Understanding, reticence and learning how it works ends up being very different than other databases
we use write us because it is fast and it is fast because of these limitations right here.
So in order to use Redis, we have to understand how to fit our data into a limited space.
We have to understand how to fit our data or organize it using these simple data structures.
And we have to understand how to kind of work ourselves around this limited feature sets.
That really starts to paint a picture of where we're going to spend our time when we are learning this.
We need to understand how to work with data, how to organize it, and how to work with this simple
feature set.
Okay.
So with that in mind, let's go through a little bit of setup in the next video.