In this video, we're going to go through a very small amount of setup.
Now, please do not skip this video.
You have to go through this setup even if you have a running copy of Redis on your computer already.
Okay, so let's get to it.
The first piece of set up that we're going to go through.
We need a copy of Redis, something where we can actually store data, run commands and so on.
In this course, you have two options for running Redis.
You can either create a free instance of Redis on RedState.com.
This is a publicly available website that you can use to run Redis or alternatively, you can install
and run Redis on your local computer.
And for right now, I really, really recommend you create an instance of reticence on RedState.com.
And I'm going to show you that in this video later on Inside the course, I will show you how to install
and run this on your local computer.
The only reason I'm not showing you that right away is that sometimes the setup is a little bit complicated,
in particular if you're running on windows.
So again, for right now, I really recommend you follow along and create an instance on red is cloud.
So let's get to it.
To get started, I'm going to open up a new browser tab and navigate to Red Ask.com.
At RedState.com, you'll see a page that looks like this on the top right hand side.
Find the button that says either try free or log in.
You can then sign up with either Google GitHub or use an email address.
I'll leave it up to you to actually sign up once you are signed up.
You will see a page that looks like this.
So once you log into this cloud, you're going to see something that says you have no active subscriptions.
Or you might see a welcome screen, of course.
But this is what I see.
The to create a database, we first have to create something called a subscription.
We'll go into more detail later on on what a subscription is versus a database.
Right now, we're just going to make a subscription.
Well, click on that new subscription button.
Well then make sure that I have fixed plans selected.
Well, then scroll down to the bottom.
And the only thing I really have to do on this page is enter in a name for this subscription.
I'm going to give it a name of three dash sub.
Once the subscription has then been created, we can then make an actual database.
So on the right hand side, I'll click on new database.
I'm going to give this a name of free dash DB.
And then on the top, right inside, I'll click on Activate database.
Now creating the database might take a couple of seconds.
So we're going to wait for that little yellow icon right there to turn green once it's turned green.
Our database has been created and we are good to go.
We're going to pause this video right here.
We're going to come back in just a moment and do just a touch more set up.