It looks like my database has been created.
So now that we have a database, we're going to move on to a second piece of very quick setup.
Now that we have a database, we need to actually run some commands against it.
We need to be able to add data to our database and eventually query for that data as well.
There are a couple of options you can use in this course or running commands against Redis.
I'm going to show you in these first couple of videos a tool called our Books Cloud.
This is a publicly available website that I put together just for you.
Just for this course is a website that allows you to connect to a running Redis database and run some
commands against it.
Kind of a nice looking interface if you do not want to use our Bakkt Cloud, which I'm about to show
you in just a moment.
That's totally fine.
You can instead make use of a command line program called Red Acela.
I am going to show you how to use Red Acela later on inside this course.
Right now, just to get started very easily and very quickly, I recommend trying out our books out
just for a couple of videos.
Let me show you how to use that tool.
Back inside my browser, I'm going to make another tab and go to our cloud.
Once there, we'll see a page that looks like this.
On the top right hand side, click on the button that says New Notebook.
This will create a brand new notebook for you.
A notebook is a place where you can write out some comments or some notes to yourself, and you can
also write out some reader's commands and execute them as well.
So this little grey box right here, if you click on it, you can add in your own notes.
So is something about read this and then click out of it.
Right underneath that is a food running, celery calorie running cell.
So I can type in a Redis command right here.
So some kind of command and then run it.
If I try to run it right now, I'm going to get an error because I'm not yet connected to a register
database.
Once I successfully run a command, the result will then be displayed on the right hand side of this
little box.
You can also add in additional sections so I can put in some more boxes for running commands or some
more note sections and so on.
You get the idea.
So again, you do not have to use this tool if you do not want to.
But just for the first couple of videos, I recommend trying it out because running right ACR, I can
sometimes be a little bit of a challenge of a challenge.
Okay so to make use of our but dark cloud do is set up our connection to a read a database we just created
to set up that connection I'm going to go to the top right hand side and find that connect button.
Well, then see a connection settings window like this appear.
We have to enter in a host, a port and a password for the database that we just created.
Let me show you how to get that information.
I'm going to go back over to Rita's Cloud.
I'm going to make sure I'm looking at my database that was created.
And I'll make sure that I'm on the configuration tab.
Well then scroll down a little bit to public and point.
I'm going to highlight everything in here all the way up to you, but not including the colon and the
number at the end.
So I'm highlighting everything up to the adcom.
Well then copy that.
Go back over and paste it in as the host.
Then back over here.
I'm going to grab the number at the very end of public and points.
Copy that.
And put it in this window at the port.
And then finally, for the password.
We'll scroll down to the bottom of the section and find a default user password right here.
I'm going to click on the copy button.
Back over and paste it in as the password.
No username should be required so you can leave that just completely empty.
Once I've got the host port and password in here, I'm going to click on test.
And then I should see a connection successful.
Once I see that, I'll click on Save and that's pretty much it.
Now as a very quick example of a very simple command that we could run against Redis.
I'm going to type in here, set P value like.
So I'll then click on this play button right here.
Now, if you see some big orange box over here that gives some kind of error message.
As long as the error message does not say connection error, that's totally fine.
So if it says connection error, there is some issue and you want to double check your connection settings.
Otherwise, if you get some kind of error that says invalid number of arguments or invalid syntax.
That is totally fine for right now.
Okay.
So that is setting up our but once you've gone to that set up, we only have to do it one time.
So now that we have a database and we've got a place to run some Redis commands, let's take a pause
right here and understand what these commands are all about in just a moment.