As I mentioned, previously sorted sets are very flexible and we can use them in a wide variety of different
applications.
We're going to focus right now on two very particular use cases around sorted sets, because I think
that they're probably going to be the most common use cases you run into.
The first use case is going to be tabulating the most of or the least of some attributes of a collection
of related hashes.
Now, that probably in plain English does not make any sense whatsoever.
So quick diagram.
All right.
So let's imagine we are making some kind of book purchasing application, say something like Amazon
and we are using Redis as our primary data store.
Well, to make a book purchasing application, the first thing we need to do is store information about
individual books.
Let's imagine that for every different book that we have, we create a separate hash.
So here is a book with I5.
It's got a hash with a key of some title and some author.
And then same thing.
Another book with an idea of 18.
And of course, we could try to list out all these different hashes to the user and just make them some
big list.
But we would want to apply some ordering to list of books that we show to a user.
We might want to list out the books with the most reviews or ratings or purchases.
And to list out the books in some particular order.
That's where a sorted set would come into play.
But we might want to list out to users the books sorted by which have the most reviews, which have
the best ratings and which had the most purchases.
For each of these three different attributes, we would have a separate sorted set.
So to answer which book has the most reviews, we can have a sorted set where the members are the keys
of our different book hashes.
I've got this book right here stored as a member, and when I say stored as a member, I mean just the
key of that book.
Just the key is stored as a member.
And then a score would be the number of reviews that this book has received.
I've also got books 18 right here, and maybe this one has only gotten five reviews.
But now with this sorted set, I could very easily answer the question Which book has the most reviews?
I would do a very simple Z range operation on this and maybe get the book with just the top level,
the absolute most reviews.
Well, I could do that with a very simple Z range, with a reverse argument and then a limit of one.
Technically a limit of zero one.
That would give me books five.
I would then take that key right there and do a separate lookup.
So a second query and get the books at five right here that give me back my cache and I'd have the title
and the author of the book with the most reviews.
We can then repeat very similar operations to answer the question Which book has the highest rating
and which book has the most purchases?
Now in each of these sorted set examples here, one thing I want to point out very quickly.
As the member, I'm putting in the full key of, say, books, 18 books, five and so on.
But just to save space, we don't really have to store that entire key right there.
We might instead store just the idea of this book.
So just say 18 or just five right there.
We don't have to store the entire key, the hash.
It can be just the ID by itself.
All right.
So that is one possible use case any time where we want to store the most of or the least of some attributes
of a couple of different hashes.
Second very common use case.
And again, we're going to run to this quite a bit on our e-commerce application is any time we want
to create relationships between records and we want to sort those relationships based on some criteria.
So again, let me show you an example.
Okay.
Once again, let's imagine we are making a book sort of application, something related to books or
writing books or something like that.
Maybe in this case we are allowing people to write books or author books on our platform.
We might have a list of authors and a list of books that are being written.
And maybe we'll say that our book is a.
Or our application is a collaborative book writing platform.
So two different authors and work on the same book.
We'll say maybe Samantha and Alex are both working together on a book called.
A biography.
And they are also both working together on another book called History Book.
There we go.
Now we've got a relationship between these different records.
The story, this kind of relationship inside of red is we might first create a hash to represent each
individual author and each individual book.
And so we'd end up with something like this.
We've got the author with a name of Samantha, an author with the name of Alex, and then the hash for
the first book and a house for the second book.
Now we need to add in some more data here.
We need to somehow relate together the fact that Samantha and Alex are both working on different both
these different books.
And in addition to that, we might also want to order this relationship based upon a number of reviews
or something like that that each book has received.
Well, let's just go to the next diagram and I'll show you what I mean by that.
Okay.
So I've added in two sorted sets down here, the first sorted sets doors information about what books
the author with Id4 has worked on.
So this would be a sorted set dedicated entirely.
You author with four for that is Samantha.
So inside of our sorted set a member might be the idea of each book that Samantha has worked on.
In this case, it's telling you that Samantha has worked on the book with it.
Five.
That's this one up here.
And Samantha has also worked on a book with i-D 43.
That's that one right there.
Now just knowing that there is a relationship between that author and those books, that's definitely
useful.
Like I said, in many cases we want to sort this relationship in some way.
So as a score for each of these individual books we might store.
As a score right there, the number of copies that has been sold.
So we might have look with 85 has sold 560 copies book with 8043 has sold 4500 copies.
Now, we not only know that Samantha has worked on this book and this book, we also have an ordering
to that relationship.
So if you ever wanted to answer the question, what books has Samantha worked on that are the most popular?
We could use this sorted, set right here.
We would go into the sorted set, go to the very last row, and we'd be guaranteed that that would be
a reference to the book that has sold the most copies.
So book with 8043.
We would then repeat the same process for the other author as well.
So over here, we got the second sorted sets.
This belongs to you, Alex.
So I.
14.
And it's going to tell us exact same data.
What books has Alex worked on?
So 85 and 43 and the scores, the identical because they worked on the same books.
So Alex or a book five had sold 560 copies and 4500 copies per book with 8043.
Okay.
So once again, any time where we are creating relationships between records and we want that relationship
to be sorted by some criteria, again, I got to repeat, this is extremely common.
It turns out that any time that you've got a relationship between different records inside of an application,
you usually want it to be ordered in some way.
Now, maybe the number of copies sold isn't super common, but another criteria that you might want
to sort by that is very common is maybe a created ad date.
Let's say we want to say or find out books that author with 84 has written.
Sorted by author date or maybe by author date.
I mean, when was the book actually written?
So in this case, as a score we could store when each book was created stored as you next time.
I could put in a Unix time stamp right here, so something like that and maybe something like that.
Remember Unix time is the number of seconds or in some cases milliseconds that have elapsed since January
1st, 1970.
Now, if I ever wanted to figure out what was the first book that author 34, worked on?
Well, I would go to the very first element inside of this sorted set that would be told, well, the
first element or first book that this author worked on was the book with 85.
And what is the most recent book?
Let be the last record.
Inside the sorted sets begin sorting relationships by some kind of criteria.
Extremely common occurs on an incredible number of different applications you work on.
So usually, not always, but usually whenever we are trying to reflect some kind of relationship between
records, even though we have used a plain set in the past, we will very often instead use sorted sets
moving forward.
Now that we understand what these things are, because again, usually we want to sort our relationships
in some way.
All right, enough theory.
Time to actually put this stuff into practice on our e-commerce application.