Between ending soonest and most views.
We're going to work on ending soonest first.
So we need to somehow make use of that sorted set we just put together to figure out which items are
being closed for bidding soonest with any to fetch some information about those items and display them
on this little carousel right here.
Step number one in this process is to figure out what command we can use to figure out which items are
ending soonest.
Using this sorted set that we just put together.
So let's just figure out how we can figure out which items are ending soonest.
We can do so with a very quick example.
We've got a very small sample data set right here, three different items.
I'm showing their item IDs, the names and the ending at time.
Remember, these ending at times are UNIX timestamps expressed in milliseconds.
So in reality they're going to be rather many digits long, something like that.
But for the purposes of this diagram, I'm displaying them as very small values just so that they are
easier for us to read and understand.
So again, ending at really a very long number, but just very small on this diagram only.
So let's try figuring out what query we need to write.
What command are we going to issue here?
To figure out which items are ending soonest.
As this example, we're going to try to find the two items.
So just the first two that are ending soonest in this data set right here, if the current time were
130.
So if the current time, the whole world like as we are talking right now, is 130.
Which items would we want to find and what command would we write to find those items?
Well, at a very practical level, if the current time is 130 and we want to find the items that are
ending soonest.
We definitely would want to get the item IDs of 18 and five.
Because one toe already past one toe.
That is a time in the past it already elapsed.
This item's auction has been closed.
So the next item that is going to end is 18 because that has a time stamp of 150.
And then after that, the next one is the item with 85 because that has a score or a ending at time
of 180.
So what kind of query can we write to get these two item IDs right here?
Well, to just go over the solution, I think it would be something like this.
I think we would do a Z range command.
Z range allows us to look at a sorted set and get some number of members out of there based upon some
filtering criteria.
So we would do a Z range.
On items ending at.
And then remember how ze range works after specifying that key right there, we have two different options
available to us if we just put in some plain numbers like this with no other arguments.
That means just give us the elements at index or rank zero and one that we just executed this right
here.
We would get back six and 18.
Definitely not what we want.
The other way that these numbers work is if we add in an additional argument after them, if we put
in the argument of buy score, it changes the behaviour of those two arguments and it causes the Z range
to now work based upon all these scores as opposed to the index of each member.
So if we put in a buy score now, we can do some more intelligent filtering.
For our buy score.
We want to find all the items up to and including or at least hint including 130 is that is the current
time.
That is our start time.
That is the start of the range of items we are looking for.
So we would put in 130 right there and then we would want to have an upper bound of pretty much infinity.
We want to find all the items in the future, all items that are going to end at any point in the future.
So we could put in a plus in right there, positive infinity.
So again, give us all the items from the current time of 130 up to infinity.
Any time the future.
And then finally we only want the two items that are ending soonest.
So if we had a million items that are going to end at some point in time, the future, this commander
would give us all million items.
Definitely not what we want.
So we want to constrain how many items get sent back to us.
You limit the number of items we get sent back, we can use the limit argument.
Remember, limit takes two numbers.
The first is going to be the number of elements.
So we want to skip over out of the result sets.
In this case, we don't want to skip over anything.
So we put in zero.
And then the second number will be the number of elements we want to return from the results sets.
So for us, that would be to.
And that's it.
That's our comment.
So we need to somehow express this command in our code somewhere inside of our code base.
Yet.
The thing that I want to mention very quickly, this command is just going to give us these two IDs
right here and nothing else.
So that command is not going to actually get us the item hashes, which is what we eventually need to
retrieve.
This kind of gets us there, but not really all the way.
Let's at least try to implement just this part for right now.
Okay.
So to get started on the implementation of this command, let's go back over to our code editor.
I will find queries, items and then by ending time dots.
So as you probably guessed, this function is intended to retrieve a list of items that are ending very
shortly.
So they're going to end at some point in time in the future.
The arguments this function are order.
That's going to be whether we want to get items that are ending the absolute soonest in ascending order
or descending order.
Right now, do not worry about that argument.
We're not going to worry about the order just yet.
We are going to make use of offset and counts however is offset and count values are going to be pretty
much exactly pass through to the limit argument right there.
So offset is how many items in the results that we want to skip and count is how many items out of the
results that we want to get access to.
Now from this function, we're going to first find the IDs of all the items we are looking for.
And then after that, we're going to fetch the actual item hashes and serialize them.
So ultimately from this function, we need to return an array of item hashes.
That's we have to return, not the item IDs.
So not those things right there.
But again, for right now, we're just going to focus on getting those item IDs and we'll worry about
actually loading up the related data in just a moment.
Okay.
So enough talking, let's actually write some code.
Get started on this command at the very top.
We need to import a couple of different things.
First, our clients.
From services readies.
Then that key we had just put together that is pointing to our sorted sets.
So that is items by ending at key.
From Services Keys.
And then finally we're also definitely going to need to DC realize the list of items at some point in
time once we fetch each individual individual item hash so two DC realize them will get the serialize
function.
From Dot slash.
These relies.
And because we are trying to retrieve some item hashes, we will also need our item key function as
well.
So I'm also going to get items key.
Except.
All right.
Finally, time for our commands.
Second studies.
Now we're going to write out our Z Range Command.
We'll do it and await client dot z range.
We want to look at the sorted set stored at items by ending at key.
And then we're going to put in our filtering criteria after that.
When you apply it inside of two additional arguments here.
So I want to go starting at the current time.
So whatever the current time is expressed in seconds or milliseconds, excuse me, that's going to be
a date dot.
Now, that's whatever the current time is.
And then I want to go all the way to the very, very far future.
Find all the items that are ending at some point in time.
The future for that will do.
Plus, I can.
We're then going to add in another argument here, as can be an object.
This is where we're going to put in some additional configuration options for Z range.
The first option we want to put in is buy score.
Notice that BI is capitals.
So capital B, capital Y.
And the score is of course, all capitals as well.
And we will also put in our limit criteria.
So we want to limit to whatever this offset is.
By default, it is zero.
And whatever this count is, by default it is ten.
So again, that limit operation is what can make sure that we don't get back a million items that are
ending the future, just the first ten or so.
They'll put an offset.
And count.
And that should be it.
So now to test this out right now, I know this video was very long.
I apologize.
But let's just do a very quick test after the entire command.
We've got that array of just IDs right there.
I'm going to do a console log of those ideas.
And then save this.
All right.
Testing time.
Back inside the browser, we first need to create a couple of new items.
So we have some items that are actually ending in the future.
So once I sign in, I'm going to go to new.
I'm going to create a new item with a duration of 10 minutes.
I'll give it just item, name of chair.
It doesn't really matter.
Then hit submit.
And I'll do one or two more.
So in addition to Chair, I'll do a couch that ends in 10 minutes.
And how about a table?
That ends in 10 minutes as well.
Okay.
So we should now have three items, at least inside of our sorted set that are ending at some point
in time, the future.
So now to get that console.log to fire, we can just go back to our main landing page.
And then go take a look at our terminal.
And that's where we should see our console.log.
The back at my terminal.
Sure enough right here.
Those are the item IDs that are ending soonest.
So we've got the item IDs for a.
Now we've got those item IDs.
All we have to do is load up the related data.
That's going to be all these different item hashes.
Over here, we need to load up each of these hashes d serialize them and then return them.
Let's take care of that last step in just a moment.