Back over to our e-commerce application.
Firstly, we are going to use sorted sets for is to fix up the sign in flow inside of our application.
Right now, if I go to sign in and then I try to sign in with any credentials, I get an error that
says username does not exist.
So we need to of course fix this up and figure out some way to, well, make the sign in flow work.
So traffic sign in flow.
We're going to go to our SC services where iOS users dot yes file go inside of here we've already got
a lot of code related to sign up and handling users and whatnot.
The reason that sign in is currently not working as intended is that we have not implemented the get
user by username function.
That's going to be the first thing we're going to fix and as you can guess, we're going to fix it using
a sorted set.
Now I'm going to tell you immediately you implement git user by username.
We could use a hash.
Absolutely.
It would work just as well as what we're about to do.
But instead we're going to use a sorted set for one single purpose.
And that is just help you understand that sorted sets are very flexible and they can be used in place
of many other structures, such as hashes or plain sets.
Look at that.
Further ado, I first want to help you understand why our application is working right now around the
sign in flow and how we're going to use a sorted set to fix it.
First, quick review on what goes on during sign up.
So sign up, not sign in.
Whenever someone tries to sign up, we check to see if a username is in use and we are doing that currently
by making use of a set assigned to the key of usernames unique.
If the user's username that they're trying to sign up with is not in use, then we're going to generate
an ID and then save the user's details inside of a new hash.
So we end up with something like this right here.
So we might generate an idea of, say, 56.
Store a hash with the user's username and their password.
And we also are adding the user's username to the unique set over here as well, so that users can't
reuse a username that is already in use.
Again.
This is everything related to sign up, just a review.
Now let's take a look at sign in and understand what's going wrong with it and why we haven't been able
to implement it just yet.
Okay.
So here is sign it.
Whenever someone tries to sign in, they're going to send us a username and password.
The first thing we need to do is check to see if the correct password was supplied in the check to see
if the correct password was supplied.
We have to look into Redis and find the hash corresponding to this user.
In order to fetch their hash, however, we need to know this person's I.D..
And that's the issue.
When we received the signing request, we only know the username and password.
That's it.
We don't know anything about this person's ID just yet.
And we don't have any ability using default redness or kind of the feature set we've learned about so
far to somehow look over all of our user hashes and find a hash with a particular username, and then
to kind of back out to the key assigned to that house.
Right now, we just plain have no idea what this person's IDs and that's why we have not implemented
that function.
Get user by username just yet because we don't have this ability.
And so that specifically is what we're going to fix using a sorted set.
That's got to be pretty straightforward.
We're going to add in a new sorted set assigned to a key of usernames.
This is going to store as the members the different usernames and then the score for each username is
going to be that person's I.D..
A username of seller might have a score, which is actually their idea of 56.
So whenever a user makes a request to sign in.
We're going to take their username.
We're going to look up that username inside of our sorted sets that will give us back that person's
ID.
Well, then use that ID to get that person's user hash.
And then we can do the actual password comparison.
I'm actually doing the password comparison is implemented in some code that I already wrote.
So all you and I have to do is really maintain this sorted, set and use it to look up the idea of a
particular user based upon their username.
Now I want to repeat one thing just one more time.
We could absolutely implement all this stuff using hash.
I just want to show you that we can use sorted sets in place of hashes in many scenarios and things
are going to work out just fine.
Sorted sets are a very flexible structure.
There is one other little issue we're going to run into along the way, and solving that issue is going
to be pretty interesting as well.
I think also worth using a sorted set just you can see this issue and understand how to fix it.
All right.
So in closing.
Make sign and work.
We need to implement that function of git user by username and we're going to implement it through the
use of a sorted set.
So let's get started on that in just a moment.