Let's get started on our implementation.
There are three distinct tasks that we need to go through.
First, we need to create a new key function.
So that function that's going to generate the key of simply usernames.
Number.
We've been creating these these key functions throughout the rest of the course whenever we need to
generate a key, even if it doesn't have any IDs in it.
So back inside my editor, I'm going to find the services he's got to file and add in a new key function
of usernames.
Key?
And then going to find once again the queries users not to yes file.
And I will implement the or import the usernames key function at the top.
All right.
That's step one.
Now, step two.
Step two is whenever someone tries to sign up to our application.
But here's the sign up flow.
We need to take the idea that we generate for this this person, and we need to add that ID along with
this person's username into this new set that we are talking about there.
During sign up.
We need to add in this username as a member along with their ID as a score.
Now in the last video I mentioned at the very end that we were going to run into an issue.
This is where the issue is going to come up specifically as we tried to add in the idea of the user.
But we'll see what the issue is in just a moment.
First we'll take care of the implementation back over inside of users.
Yes, I will find create user.
This is the function that gets called whenever someone tries to sign up.
This is where we generate an ID.
So after we generate the ID and we make sure that this username is not already in use, we can then
set the user hash, add in their username to our username set and then right after that is probably
a good place for us to add in a new record to our sorted set.
I'm going to do and await client z add usernames key and then to add in a new member score pair using
the node read client, we put in a second argument of an object that is going to have a value.
And a score.
So with no protests, they don't call it a member, they call it a value instead.
But value is members the same thing.
So the value is going to be our username.
Our username and be looked up through that adders object.
So adders has a property of not username.
We used it back right there just a little bit ago.
So we can put in our value as adders dot username.
And then the score is going to be the ID, which we had generated right there.
I'm going to put in ID and right there is where we're going to run into our issue, like I said.
So we expected this to come up and this is a error that I really want you to see and I really want you
to see the work around to it.
The error is specifically by hover over this, you know, really long error here that says type string
is not assignable to type number.
So what's that all about?
Well, remember, our sorted sets, all sorted sets in red is the value or the score.
Over here on the right hand side must be a number.
And in all these diagrams I've been showing them as numbers, even in this diagram right here, I'm
showing the ID as a number.
However.
The function that we're using to generate an ID right here.
Returns a string of a mouse over ID.
That is a string right there.
An I.D. function creates a ID that looks kind of something like this.
It's a string that represents a number encoded in hexadecimal.
So we get this kind of collection of alphanumeric characters, though it appears at first glance that
we will not be able to use the ID as a score inside of our user username.
Sorted.
Set.
Well, that's definitely an issue.
Let's take a pause right here.
We'll come back in just a moment and I'll show you how we can very easily get around this limitation.