We just ran into a little issue around our the ad function.
Right now we are trying to provide a score that is actually a string.
Remember that ID is generated by the gen I.D. function.
Whenever we call gen ID, it gives us back a number in hexadecimal format.
Let's kind of go more into hexadecimal values for just a moment.
Okay.
So here's what's going on behind the scenes during the signup flow.
We are still generating that ID.
We're then taking that ID and trying to store it as a username I.D. parent inside of that brand new
sorted set.
And it's as we're trying to issue that Z add command that we're doing Ziyad usernames.
There's the username itself and there's the score that's supposed to be our ID, but it's a string instead
of a number.
But here's the little trick.
Here's the thing I just want you to be aware of whenever we have this limitation of only storing numbers
anywhere in Redis.
Okay.
So I've extracted from that command just the ID portion.
And again, this is a hexadecimal value.
So technically is a number that is being expressed using a base 16 numbering system.
So we can take that as a hexadecimal encoded string right there and we can turn it into its equivalent
base ten number.
So these two values are completely identical.
This is base 16.
This is base ten.
So we convert that ID into a base ten value.
We have a number that we can safely store inside of Redis.
And that's exactly what we're going to do.
We're just going to add in one additional little step here during the sign up process after we generate
that I.D. and we go to store that ID inside this username sorted set, we're going to convert the ID
to base ten.
That's it.
We try to do that, Ziad.
We'll have an actual decimal value to store and we can store that number safely inside of our sorted
set.
When we eventually try to pull this data out of our sorted set, we just need to remember to convert
it back into hexadecimal.
That's it.
Okay.
So for this back here at the Ziad function.
I'm going to take school right there.
And in JavaScript, you convert a string that is encoded in base 16 into a number.
We should just wrap it with a pass into.
Comment 16 like so.
We're going to take that hexadecimal ID, convert it into an integer and that's it.
We can now safely story inside of the sorted set.
Okay.
So that is one problem solved.
Now we're going to pause right here.
Come back in just a moment and will implement the user by username function.