On to the get user by username function.
We've spoken about this function quite a bit.
It's going to be called automatically during these sign in process.
We're really just using this function to take a username and give back a user.
Okay.
So inside of here, I'm going to write out a couple of comments just to guide us in what we need to
do.
The first thing we need to do is use the username arguments.
So this argument right here, do you look up the person's user ID with the user names?
Sorted, set.
Once we look up that idea, we will make sure we actually got an idea from the look.
So in other words, whenever we look into our sorted sets and we get back a value, we need to make
sure we actually got something from Redis.
So something that's not not.
After that, we will take the idea and convert it back to Hex.
So go back to basics.
Well then use the ID to look up the user's hash and then finally be serialized and return the hash.
Now just from the comments in here, because I know this stuff is pretty involved, so hopefully the
comments are going to guide us fairly well.
Let's get to it.
The step number one, you look up a score is that's what we really need to do here.
We have a member and we need to look at the associated score.
Inside of our sorted set, we can use the Z score function.
I'm going to do a await client dot z score.
I want to look up a member score here.
Inside of our usernames.
E sorted.
Set.
And I want to find the score associated with this username.
And then going to assign the result to that of that two decimal I.D.?
I was specifically calling it decimal ID.
Just make sure it's super clear this is a base ten ID and we need to convert it back into hexadecimal.
So then make sure that we actually got something back here.
Did we get nor did we actually ID.
We actually got an ID and we'll move on to the next step.
Otherwise we'll return an error saying, hey, we were not able to find an ID associated with the username
that was provided.
We'll say it.
There is no decimal idea.
And throw a new ear that says.
User does not exist.
Next, we're going to take the idea that we got converted back into base 16.
And to do that in JavaScript, we'll take a look at the number that we have and do a two string 16 like
so that's how we go from a number into hexadecimal.
Now that we have an actual ID here, a proper hexadecimal I.D., we can do a simple h, get all to find
this user's hash.
So an h get all just the same as we've done many times to find this person right here, find their hash
DC, realize that and return it.
They will say.
User is a weight.
Each get all.
User's key.
With that ID.
And then finally we can return these your allies.
And remember, the first argument you serialize is the idea of this person.
And then the second argument is their user hash that we just retrieved.
I'll put in the ID and then the user.
And that's it.
Okay.
Time for a quick test.
You test this out, I'm going to first make sure that I'm still running my server.
Yep.
Looks like I am.
We'll go back and watch the browser.
I'm going to sign up for a brand new account.
So again, air right here.
Totally fine.
The header did update, which means I was able to successfully sign up all then log out.
I'll go to sign in and I'll try to sign in with the username password combination that I just used.
And it worked.
All right.
That's perfect.
One more quick test.
You're going to try to sign in with a combination that definitely does not exist.
And if I do that, I still get the error of user does not exist.
All right.
Let's say that this looks pretty good.
I just want to repeat one more time that we used a sorted set where we could have used a hash instead.
We could have created a hash and had all the keys inside the hash, be the usernames and have all the
values, be the hexadecimal IDs.
So we would have not had to do any conversion there.
But again, I just wanted you to see a somewhat uncommon use of sorted sets.
Just you start to get into your head.
Yes, these things are super flexible.
We can use them in many locations.
And to help you see this conversion from a base 16 number into a decimal number, which allows us to
sometimes get around some restrictions of only being able to store numbers as scores.
Now we've got this kind of weird use of sorted sets out of the way.
All the future uses of sorted sets are going to be much more reasonable in nature.
We're going to only use them for some of the purposes I described in the last couple of videos.
So using them to use sort values and using them to set up relationships.
Lastly, I want to mention very quickly, we now have a username sorted set and the usernames unique
sets.
We no longer need usernames unique because we are recording all the different usernames inside this
sorted set so we can use the sorted set to track uniqueness of usernames instead of the plain set.
I'm going to leave our application as is.
I'm going to leave this kind of redundancy inside of here.
Just so I have an example in the future of a set and a sorted set.
All right.
On to our next implementation around sorted sets in just a moment.