We're going to start to implement these three different sections on our landing page.
So if you click on ARB at the very top, you see most expensive ending soonest and most views.
And I bet you can guess what we want to show in each one.
We want to show the items with the most we use as soon as most expensive.
Now implementing these is going to be pretty easy by using sorted sets.
It turns out that what we have to do here is just about identical to the example I showed you a little
bit ago.
Remember I showed you this diagram?
We have some hashes over here representing books, and then we can have a separate sorted set for each
sorting criteria.
The one to keep track of the books by reviews, one by ratings and one by purchases is sorted.
Sets make it really easy for us to answer these simple questions, such as which book has the most reviews
and so on.
We're going to first focus on the most abused section.
That's what we're taking care of first.
We're not going to worry about ending soonest or most expensive.
All right.
Most views.
Let's take a look at a diagram.
We're going to have a setup identical to what I showed you related to the book's example.
We've got the individual item hashes.
And remember, the item hashes already are storing a number of views.
We've already taken care of that behavior, the hashes themselves, record number of use.
We are then going to duplicate that information over to this separate sorted set as well.
We're going to have a sorted set where the key of something like items, colon views is going to record
the ID of every item and the score is going to be the number of use that that item has.
So again, it's going to make it very easy for us to answer the question which item has the most use?
Now once again, I just want to repeat that we are duplicating this Vieux information.
That might sound wasteful, but it's completely fine.
Remember, in general, with Redis, we want to optimize for lookup.
We want to make sure that queries are very, very fast.
And we usually don't want to have to try to piece together data from many different sources inside Redis.
In other words, if I ever want to show an item to a user on the screen, ideally I would be able to
fetch just one single hash and that hash will have all the data I need to show the item.
Ideally, I don't have to look around to ten different keys to a couple sorted sets and a set and the
hash analyst and all these different structures to assemble something I can use to show on the screen.
So duplicating this information will be fine.
All right.
Now, as we start to go back into some stuff we've already put together, such as items and add in this
new functionality, things are going to get really confusing really quick, not only on our application
but for your apps as well.
But as you start to add in more structures into readies, things just naturally get a little bit more
confusing whenever you start to add stuff in to touch code that you've already put together.
I really recommend you put together a diagram like this.
In this diagram, I've recorded a few different events.
So the first event is going to be what we need to do inside of Redis.
That's over here on the right hand side.
Whenever an item is created.
And then we also need to do some amount of stuff whenever someone views an item.
So whenever an item is created, we need to initialize the item.
Hashes, views, property to zero.
We're already doing that.
That's already taken care of.
The other thing we need to do, we need to take the items in and add it to our sorted set.
With an initial score of zero.
So in other words, whenever we create a brand new item, let's say I duplicate this down here.
This thing was just created for just now storing it inside of Redis.
So it's going to start off with, say, an idea of six and zero views.
We need to simultaneously add in a new record to our sorted set.
So it's going to have an idea six and a score of zero.
And technically it would be at the very top because it has the least number of views.
And then on item view.
Whenever someone views an item, we need to take a look at the item hashes of use property and increment
it by one.
We also need to take a look at the sorted set and add one to the score for this item to.
So again, things start to get a little bit confusing as you start to add in this more functionality.
We need to be aware of all these different data types inside of us, all the different properties that
need to be updated with any given events.
Now lastly, I want to remind you about is that ideally we're only going to record a review by a user
one time.
I don't want to record multiple different views for one single user.
We're going to add in that functionality later on.
We're not going to worry about that uniqueness check just yet.
We'll do that in just a little bit.
But not right now.
Okay.
So to get started, let's take a quick pause and then get to it in just a moment.