Let's get started on our implementation.
The first thing we'll take care of is to create a brand new key function that will generate the string
that's going to point to our sorted set.
We need to make a new key function that gives us that string right there.
Back inside my code editor.
Often the services you start to see file.
Now we're about to add in many different key functions related to items in addition to the one key related
to items that we already have.
Just to keep this file easy to read, I'm going to grouped together some of the different keys related
to the responsibility.
I'm going to add in a comment of items right here.
And in this little section, I'm going to add in all the different keys over time, not just yet, but
over time.
I'll add in all the different keys related to managing items in any way.
I've already got one key function related to items.
So I'm going to cut that and put it into this item section.
All then declare a new items by the use EA.
That's going to be a function as well.
And it's going to give me back a string of items Colin views again.
That's going to point to our sorted sets.
Okay.
I'm going to close that next up.
We're going to take a look at item creation whenever an item is created.
We need to make sure that we initialize the item.
Hashes, views, property to zero.
That's already been taken care of for you.
I already did that in another location inside of the app.
All we have to do is make sure that we take the item ID and that is being generated by us at some point
inside of our app.
We've already taken care of that.
We can take that item's ID and we're going to add it into our sorted set with an initial score of zero.
Inside of my editor, I'll find services, queries, items, folder and an item stocked.
Yes.
Inside.
If you're at the very top, I'll find the important four items key.
And I'm going to also import.
Items by use key.
That's the function we just created a moment ago.
Well, then go down to create item.
Here it is right here.
So this is where we generate the idea.
We serialize that attributes object and we create the items hash.
So in addition to all this, right after creating the items, hash will also take care of this step.
We'll make sure we add in the items ID to the sorted set.
With an initial score of zero.
So I will do and await.
Client Z ad.
Items by views key.
And then our arguments to Ziad are going to be a object with a value and a score.
The value is going to be the item ID.
So I'd be right there.
And the score is going to start off at zero because by default every item when it first gets created
has no views.
And forgot to call that.
There we go.
Okay.
So that should be it.
Now, before we move on, you might recall that we spoke about pipelines a little bit ago.
We can make use of pipelines to send across multiple different commands to Redis.
In one single request.
We could definitely make use of pipeline right here so we can make sure that we are not just waiting
for this command to be executed, get a response back and then execute this one.
We could just go ahead and run all these different commands at the same time.
Do that very small refactor on the line underneath.
I'll put in and await.
Promise.
Not all.
I'm going to add in an array.
And then we'll take just the client each set without the awaits.
And put it in there.
And notice I also did not take the semicolon.
And then the same thing right here.
After a wait.
All the way up to you.
But not including the semicolon.
And I'll put it right there.
Okay.
So again, making use of pipelines.
So we only send one single request over to Redis.
We could have done the same operation around user sign in just a little bit ago.
Remember, we had two separate requests going off at the same time, but just didn't get around to it
moving forward.
We'll definitely take care of Pipeline wherever possible.
Okay.
So that's step number one.
Now we need to go on to step number two.
Whenever someone views an item into increment, the item hashes, views property.
Now we need to increment the sorted set score as well.