Let's take care of incrementing this view's property whenever a user views an item.
Remember, we eventually want to make sure that all views are unique.
So one per user, per item.
That's going to prevent a user from just hitting refresh, refresh, refresh over and over again to
give themselves a ton of use on a single item.
But we're going to implement that later on using yet another data structure in Redis.
If right now, we'll just always add in a view no matter what.
So to get started.
Inside of my services directory.
Again, find queries and then inside of your views.
Yes.
So I have to find a function for us that's going to be called at some point in time whenever a user
views an item.
This function is going to be called the items ID and the user's ID as well will eventually use that
user ID to make sure that all these increments to views are always unique.
So one per user per item will take care of that later.
Right now we're only going to be making use of the item ID.
But inside that function I've to do is these two steps we're going to do an H incur by increment a number
stored inside of a hash and a z anchor by the increment.
A value stored inside of a sorted set.
To do all this, we have to import a couple of things at the top.
First I'm going to get my read his clients from services read us.
And then going to get my items key and items.
I.
Views.
He.
From Services.
He's.
And inside the function we need to do two separate commands.
So an anchor by and a z anchor by.
We can once again make use of pipeline and here to run both commands at the same time.
The we can do return promised at all with an array.
The first elements will be an H anchor by.
But this is where we are going to take a look at the item hash itself.
The item hash like this one right here.
We're going to take a look at its views property and incremented by one.
So whatever value it currently has, just add one to it.
To look up the particular item hash will make use of the items key function along with the item ID the
items key.
Item I.D..
We then want to increment specifically the VUSE property and we want to increment it by one.
So that's that.
Then we can move on to updating our sorted set as well.
Before that we could do a z inker by o client z inker, buy items, buy views key.
That's the key function we just put together a little bit ago.
And then remember very unexpectedly when we are doing it zinc-air by the order of the score and the
member is switched compared to h anchor by the word zinc-air by we're going to first put in one.
That's how much we're going to change the score by.
And then the member that we want to update is the items ID.
And that's it.
Okay.
So let's save this.
And now if we go back over to our browser.
I'm going to sign up.
Actually, I'll sign in because I now have a working user account.
I'm going to make a brand new item.
Use the default settings here.
And now whenever I refresh in theory, I'm incrementing that view counter by one, not only on the item
hash, but inside the sorted set as well.
At this point time, we are only updating the value.
We're not actually making use of that value anywhere.
I'm not showing any views on this page.
And what we've done so far is not going to make any views show up over here either.
We have to write out a separate query to actually make use of these view values now and actually get
them to be displayed on the screen.
And that's a separate little project, which we'll start in just a moment.
But what we have right now should be working in terms of at least maintaining this number of views.
Let's definitely go.