We just set up our assorted set to keep track of what items have the most views.
So now in theory, if you're building a normal application, we could start to figure out how to fetch
the appropriate items and display them in this list.
We're going to take a very short detour.
We're going to first set up a very similar sorted set to figure out which items are ending soonest.
As a quick reminder, we are building an e-commerce application that allows a user to auction off an
item.
Items are only going to be available for sale for some period of time.
So after, say, 10 minutes passes or a day or a week, other people can no longer bid on an item to
be purchased.
So we probably want to make sure it's really clear to everyone who is looking to purchase an item,
what item is ending soonest.
And that's why we're going to show that section right there.
So we can take a very short detour.
We're going to set up a sorted set, very similar to the one we just did.
That's going to organize items by their ending time.
Then after that, we're going to work on actually using these sorted sets to fetch the related items
and display them in that list.
The reason we are taking this detour is just because fetching data from using a sorted set, specifically
relational data.
There's more than one way to do it in Redis.
And so I want you to have two examples of two different ways of fetching relational data just immediately,
one after another, so we can point out some differences between the two approaches.
So that's why we're doing a very short detour.
Okay.
So with that in mind, we're going to take a look at ending soonest.
To implement this, we're going to set up a sorted set, very similar to the one we just put together
for views.
So we're going to make another sorted set tied to the key of items.
Call an ending at.
Then inside of here, we're going to once again have members of item IDs and the score is going to be
the ending time of this item's auction, recorded as a Unix timestamp in milliseconds.
Remember Unix time stamps?
That is the number of seconds or milliseconds elapsed from 1970 January 1st.
So that is going to be our score.
So our score is going to essentially cause all these items to be organized in order of when they end.
We can then use this sorted set to very easily figure out which items are ending soonest using a command
later on.
As far as the ending time.
The ending time itself is already being stored inside of all of our separate item hashes.
So once again, we're going to have a little bit of duplicate data inside of our app.
That's totally fine.
No issue with it whatsoever.
Okay.
So to create that sorted set, we're going to go through a very similar operation here as what we did
previously around views just a little bit ago.
So remember, we try to identify when we are creating an item or updating item, stuff like that and
what changes we need to make.
In the case of ending ATS, I think the only thing we have to really do here is say that whenever we
create a new item as usual, we're going to initialize the items ie ending at property to a UNIX timestamp
in milliseconds.
And again, that's already taken care of for us as already being done whenever an item is created.
In addition to that, what you and I have to add in right now, we have to make sure that we add that
items ID to that sorted set.
And the initial score is going to be at the UNIX time stamp expressed in milliseconds.
So pretty much exactly what we're showing in this diagram right here.
All right.
Time for implementation.
We're going to first begin by creating yet another key function.
And it's going to give us the key of items.
Colon ending at.
So back inside, my editor.
I will find.
Services he's got?
Yes.
Inside of here next to all my other item keys I will put in.
Items by ending at key.
There we go.
Then once again, inside of our services.
Queries.
Items.
Yes.
File.
So this is where we added in code just a little bit ago.
At the very top, let's import that key function we just created.
Items by ending at key.
Then we'll scroll down to item creation.
That is all inside of the function called create item right here.
Here's where we put together our pipeline just a little bit ago.
So we've got the hash creation right there and we've got the sorted set creation right there for organizing
items by views.
We're going to add in yet another sorted set commands.
So we'll do a client the add items by ending at key.
And then in this case, our value once again is going to be the ID, but the score is not going to be
zero.
The squirrel be that ending at time expressed in milliseconds.
If you got where that value is going to come from.
Remember, create item is called with an object called ATRs and that is a type create item ATRs.
If I do a command, click on that.
This will tell us what that object is going to look like and all the different properties it has.
So that object has an ending at property.
That is a date time object.
We can call the two milles method on this ending our property and that will give us the ending at time
expressed in milliseconds.
So in other words, back here at the Ziad we just put together, this score will be ATRs ending at 2
million, and that's it.
All right.
So once again, we can kind of test this out.
We're not going to see any content up here on the screen.
We'll still test it out just to make sure we didn't make any typos or big mistakes along the way.
We could test it out very easily by just trying to create a brand new item.
So back over at the app, I'm logged in right now.
I'm going to go to New.
I'm going to use the default inputs and click on Submit.
I was still able to carry an item.
I did not get any heirs along the way, so chances are everything is working, more or less as expected.
Okay.
So we've now got our set up complete.
We've got a sorted set for all of ending at we've got a sorted set for items by views and now it's time
to move on to the next step.
We need to make use of these sorted sets to actually figure out which items are truly most viewed and
which are ending soonest.
And we need to actually fetch some related item hashes so we can display them on the landing page.
Let's get to that loading up relational data part.
That's where the interesting stuff is going to be in just a moment.